<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>forgiveness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/forgiveness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in forgiveness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/forgiveness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Denial</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/denial/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/denial/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/denial/michael-held-g_Kde88IlvE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Denial" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the nature of Jesus&amp;rsquo; love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we journey this week towards Good Friday, towards the cross, let&amp;rsquo;s reflect on Jesus&amp;rsquo; journey towards that first Good Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus had just eaten his last supper with the disciples in the upper room and washed their feet, and then said something none of them expected or wanted to hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Simon, Simon, behold, Satan demanded to have you, that he might sift you like wheat, but I have prayed for you that your faith may not fail. And when you have turned again, strengthen your brothers.” Peter said to him, “Lord, I am ready to go with you both to prison and to death.” Jesus said, “I tell you, Peter, the rooster will not crow this day, until you deny three times that you know me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 22:31-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in such a familiar passage, here is something to notice afresh. Jesus refers to Peter by his pre-Christian name, Simon. Why is that? Remember that he had previously given him a new name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 16:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why does Jesus momentarily call him Simon here and then almost immediately Peter again? How interesting. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think about this. The crux is not that he initially calls him Simon, but that he then calls him Peter, and this is what Jesus wants to emphasize. Even as he is foretelling his betrayal, Jesus is affirming him as Peter, his chosen one, Cephas the rock. Even in his denial he is still Peter. He is still Jesus&amp;rsquo; chosen one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only shortly afterwards it happened just as Jesus had said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when they had kindled a fire in the middle of the courtyard and sat down together, Peter sat down among them. Then a servant girl, seeing him as he sat in the light and looking closely at him, said, “This man also was with him.” But he denied it, saying, “Woman, I do not know him.” And a little later someone else saw him and said, “You also are one of them.” But Peter said, “Man, I am not.” And after an interval of about an hour still another insisted, saying, “Certainly this man also was with him, for he too is a Galilean.” But Peter said, “Man, I do not know what you are talking about.” And immediately, while he was still speaking, the rooster crowed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 22:55-60&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the Lord turned and looked at Peter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v61a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would have been in that look from Jesus? Disappointment surely, and sadness⸺sadness beyond imagining⸺but also love, such love. Steadfast love. Irrefutable love. The love that would send Jesus to the cross, in obedience to his Father, love even unto death. Love for Peter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Peter remembered the saying of the Lord, how he had said to him, “Before the rooster crows today, you will deny me three times.” And he went out and wept bitterly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v61b-62&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter realised he had denied the Lord who loved him, who had affirmed him, and who loved him still. And in his shame and wretchedness and humiliation he wept bitterly. At the time of crisis, when Jesus was going to his death, he, Peter, had been found not to be worthy. He was nothing but a shameful failure. How he wept over that failure, his failure to love Jesus as he loved him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does this leave us, as we approach Good Friday? Where does it leave me? What of my own denial? Anxiety that denies Jesus as Saviour. Vestigial sin that seeks to deny him as Lord. Here&amp;rsquo;s where: Jesus turns and looks at me, and he loves me. In love he stretched out his arms on that cross and died for me, and for you, Amy. I know I am not worthy of this love, but it makes no difference to Jesus. His love is irrefutable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the nature of his great love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember his love for you, Amy, as we approach Good Friday, and praise him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Two kinds of sorrow</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/brahm-meyer-xwG9LGmc1Qk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two kinds of sorrow" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can sorrow ever be a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What of this, that Paul writes to the Corinthians?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even if I caused you sorrow by my letter, I do not regret it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Paul somehow pleased with himself because he stuck it to those wretched Corinthians in his first letter? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet now I am happy, not because you were made sorry, but because your sorrow led you to repentance. For you became sorrowful as God intended and so were not harmed in any way by us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their sorrow was as God intended and led to repentance. This is Godly sorrow, and the Lord uses it to expose sin in our lives to bring repentance and healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I weep over the shame and failure in my life and cry out to the Lord, this also is Godly sorrow, a gift of love from my Heavenly Father, received through the conviction that comes by the Holy Spirit. It drives me into the arms of my loving Heavenly Father, from shame to repentance and forgiveness and healing, and is, through the healing, eventually and ultimately, a cause for rejoicing in my wonderful Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we must beware. There is another sorrow which leads to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Godly sorrow brings repentance that leads to salvation and leaves no regret, but worldly sorrow brings death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldly sorrow is what I experience out of a sense of entitlement, a sense of “it&amp;rsquo;s not fair”, an inclination to blame God for all that&amp;rsquo;s wrong in my life. It is self-indulgent and self-pitying and full of regret. This drives me away from my loving Heavenly Father and brings death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two are so very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with your sorrow into the arms of your loving Heavenly Father, Amy, and receive healing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiving yourself</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/stephen-leonardi-TvzRUkSlCy4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving yourself" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is even harder than forgiving those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous? Here&amp;rsquo;s what: forgiving ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be said that part of growing up is having to learn to live with the consequences of one&amp;rsquo;s own mistakes, consequences which can be far-reaching indeed. But learning to live with and forgiving are quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistakes and wilful sins are also quite different. But when all the confessing and repenting is done, the endpoint may be the same: agonizing regret over the life that has been lost, what was and is no longer, or what was once hoped for but never came to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us remind ourselves why Jesus came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can those grieving over such a loss experience this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly we must repudiate any suggestion that the rescued life is in any sense second class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who will bring any charge against those whom God has chosen? It is God who justifies. Who then is the one who condemns?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me? Is it me that condemns? Is it me that contradicts the Lord of all creation over his declaration of my righteousness in Christ? What am I thinking? Who am I to think that my own judgment is the one that matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly there is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is what the LORD says &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Forget the former things; do not dwell on the past. See, I am doing a new thing! Now it springs up; do you not perceive it? I am making a way in the desert and streams in the wasteland.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:16, 18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wasteland which is my life, the Lord is doing a new thing, which is springing up, even now. Streams of living water. A way in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longing for what is past is incongruous. The lesson of history is that the Lord does not go back. What is lost is ultimately no loss. It has become a shrivelled, dead thing. There is a new thing springing up which is alive and exciting. Joseph experienced this. Job experienced it, finally⸺the goodness and kindness and overflowing generosity of the Lord, who does not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, this is how I can forgive myself and let go of the past. I surrender, Lord, not only to your plans and purposes for my life, but to your declaration that I am a new creation in Christ. The old is gone, the new is come, and I stand before you in Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget the former things, Amy, and see the new thing that the Lord is doing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiving others</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/madhu-shesharam-KQZZCVyEWVk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving others" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we forgive those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the how, let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge that we must. This is not optional, it is commanded by Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If your brother or sister sins, rebuke them; and if they repent, forgive them. Even if they sin against you seven times in a day and seven times come back to you saying &amp;lsquo;I repent&amp;rsquo;, you must forgive them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am facing a situation in which this is a real challenge. The response I received to my articulated desire for reconciliation and relationship and mutual forgiveness and healing was a crushing and callous brush-off. What now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first attempt to forgive was a false start. I tried to diminish the magnitude of the offence, to find a way to receive it as a simple misunderstanding, to excuse the other&amp;rsquo;s behaviour. This failed because there was no truth in it. The behaviour was in fact wretched and reprehensible. I cannot deny it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then had to grapple with “if they repent”. In my situation, there is no repentance. There is stubborn and Pharisaical judgment and rejection, and refusal to engage in authentic relationship. It is crushing. Heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some writers have tried to argue that the requirement to forgive is conditional on repentance, and in this passage it indeed appears so. Is that the whole story though? I think not. But let&amp;rsquo;s not resort to a human argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this from the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer, and what Jesus said next in the Sermon on the Mount:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you forgive others when they sin against you, your heavenly Father will also forgive you. But if you do not forgive others their sins, your Father will not forgive your sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:12, 14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here our forgiveness of others is linked to God&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness of us no less. How vital then is it to forgive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When they came to the place called the Skull, there they crucified him, along with the criminals⸺one on his right, the other on his left. Jesus said, “Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they are doing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 23:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was there repentance here? Of course not! How are we called to live? Like Christ! And how can we find the power to do this? Only in him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I must die to self, again. But as I do, I find I am being transformed into Christ&amp;rsquo;s likeness. There is no greater joy, even in the midst of all this pain. The joy in that transformation is empowering indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lengthy process, an ongoing journey, and I am not yet done. May the Lord have mercy on that individual as I forgive, and continue to forgive, dying to self and becoming like Christ. And if they come to the point of repentance, may we be restored in authentic relationship again, by Christ&amp;rsquo;s power and for his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like Christ, Amy, in him and by his power and for his glory, fuelled by the joy in your own transformation! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Casting off shame</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/allef-vinicius-oe_03B2Q5A4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Casting off shame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what we do about ourselves, how can we possibly hold our head high?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David had a similar problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was chosen by the Lord because he was a man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart (1 Samuel 13:14). He earnestly sought the Lord and wrote many of the psalms which have blessed the generations.  But let us not make the mistake of thinking that he was a righteous man. His later life was in fact a catalogue of failure and shame, culminating in his most shabby and shameful moral failure, committing adultery with Bathsheba and murdering her husband Uriah the Hittite (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, David wrote Psalm 3 when he was being pursued by his son Absalom, who was trying to kill him and seize control of the kingdom. What greater failure as a father could there be than that? How utterly shameful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet we read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, LORD, are a shield around me, my glory, the One who lifts my head high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was so aware that he had no glory of his own. He had only shame. But the Lord himself was his glory, and not only the reason that he could hold his head high, but the one who actually lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course, this in no way diminishes the Lord&amp;rsquo;s condemnation of sin in one&amp;rsquo;s life. David was severely rebuked by the Lord after his wretched doings with Bathsheba. Repentance was very necessary. Forgiveness followed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. The nearer we draw to God and the more we focus on personal holiness, the more aware we become of our own failure and shame, all those reasons Christ died on the cross. We own those reasons. And yet, the Lord is my glory, the lifter of my head. Yours too, Amy! He chose us in him to be holy and blameless in his sight, and he will achieve his purposes. In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins. Cast off the shame. He alone is my glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold your head high, Amy, and know that the Lord himself is your glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Radiant disciples</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/autumn-goodman-vTL_qy03D1I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Radiant disciples" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t look at the sun, it&amp;rsquo;s far too bright. Any attempt even to look nearby overloads our retina, so all else fades into nothing. And so it is with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the source of the radiance. Ours is merely a reflection, unlikely to cause blindness, but bright and shining nonetheless, and enormously attractive to those who don&amp;rsquo;t have it. How does this work, then? We must consider how to be those who &lt;em&gt;look to him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with forgiveness⸺&lt;em&gt;their faces are never covered with shame&lt;/em&gt;. All is forgiven, all debt is cancelled and all shame is gone. This is the glorious truth that underpins everything we are as children of God. Rejoice in that forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues with hope. As we look to the Lord, we look with the hope that notwithstanding all that we have already received, his work in us is not yet complete. There&amp;rsquo;s more to come, and what is to come is so certain and so very good, and so much more than we could possibly ask or imagine. This is our source of joy, our source of radiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we love the Lord, with a grateful heart that magnifies that love, and irrepressible hope that fuels it with tremendous power. When someone is in love, absolutely captivated, they have a glow about them, evidenced in shining eyes and wonder. This is powerful and joyous, and others desire it. May we know this as we look to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him, Amy, bask in his glory which shines like the sun in all its brilliance, and be radiant! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiveness and purification</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 06:44:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/nega-YdyhHbWZ1V0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiveness and purification" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a well loved verse from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter, that we may be in danger of reading too quickly and missing the most important word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some important words here. Confess. Sins. And some wonderful, lifting words. Faithful. Forgive. Purify. But what am I referring to? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. &lt;em&gt;Just&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem to be a little out of place, yet it is the crucial word. Consider why. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours, in full. If we confess our sins, and cry out to God for mercy, it is his &lt;em&gt;justice&lt;/em&gt; that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment. Rejoice, that he is faithful &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; just.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
