<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>forgiveness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/forgiveness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in forgiveness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 06:24:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/forgiveness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Forgiving others</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/madhu-shesharam-KQZZCVyEWVk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving others" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we forgive those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the how, let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge that we must. This is not optional, it is commanded by Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If your brother or sister sins, rebuke them; and if they repent, forgive them. Even if they sin against you seven times in a day and seven times come back to you saying &amp;lsquo;I repent&amp;rsquo;, you must forgive them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am facing a situation in which this is a real challenge. The response I received to my articulated desire for reconciliation and relationship and mutual forgiveness and healing was a crushing and callous brush-off. What now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first attempt to forgive was a false start. I tried to diminish the magnitude of the offence, to find a way to receive it as a simple misunderstanding, to excuse the other&amp;rsquo;s behaviour. This failed because there was no truth in it. The behaviour was in fact wretched and reprehensible. I cannot deny it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then had to grapple with “if they repent”. In my situation, there is no repentance. There is stubborn and Pharisaical judgment and rejection, and refusal to engage in authentic relationship. It is crushing. Heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some writers have tried to argue that the requirement to forgive is conditional on repentance, and in this passage it indeed appears so. Is that the whole story though? I think not. But let&amp;rsquo;s not resort to a human argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this from the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer, and what Jesus said next in the Sermon on the Mount:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you forgive others when they sin against you, your heavenly Father will also forgive you. But if you do not forgive others their sins, your Father will not forgive your sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:12, 14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here our forgiveness of others is linked to God&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness of us no less. How vital then is it to forgive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When they came to the place called the Skull, there they crucified him, along with the criminals—one on his right, the other on his left. Jesus said, “Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they are doing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 23:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was there repentance here? Of course not! How are we called to live? Like Christ! And how can we find the power to do this? Only in him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I must die to self, again. But as I do, I find I am being transformed into Christ&amp;rsquo;s likeness. There is no greater joy, even in the midst of all this pain. The joy in that transformation is empowering indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lengthy process, an ongoing journey, and I am not yet done. May the Lord have mercy on that individual as I forgive, and continue to forgive, dying to self and becoming like Christ. And if they come to the point of repentance, may we be restored in authentic relationship again, by Christ&amp;rsquo;s power and for his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like Christ, Amy, in him and by his power and for his glory, fuelled by the joy in your own transformation! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Casting off shame</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/allef-vinicius-oe_03B2Q5A4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Casting off shame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what we do about ourselves, how can we possibly hold our head high?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David had a similar problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was chosen by the Lord because he was a man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart (1 Samuel 13:14). He earnestly sought the Lord and wrote many of the psalms which have blessed the generations.  But let us not make the mistake of thinking that he was a righteous man. His later life was in fact a catalogue of failure and shame, culminating in his most shabby and shameful moral failure, committing adultery with Bathsheba and murdering her husband Uriah the Hittite (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, David wrote Psalm 3 when he was being pursued by his son Absalom, who was trying to kill him and seize control of the kingdom. What greater failure as a father could there be than that? How utterly shameful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet we read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, LORD, are a shield around me, my glory, the One who lifts my head high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was so aware that he had no glory of his own. He had only shame. But the Lord himself was his glory, and not only the reason that he could hold his head high, but the one who actually lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course, this in no way diminishes the Lord&amp;rsquo;s condemnation of sin in one&amp;rsquo;s life. David was severely rebuked by the Lord after his wretched doings with Bathsheba. Repentance was very necessary. Forgiveness followed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. The nearer we draw to God and the more we focus on personal holiness, the more aware we become of our own failure and shame, all those reasons Christ died on the cross. We own those reasons. And yet, the Lord is my glory, the lifter of my head. Yours too, Amy! He chose us in him to be holy and blameless in his sight, and he will achieve his purposes. In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins. Cast off the shame. He alone is my glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold your head high, Amy, and know that the Lord himself is your glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Radiant disciples</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/autumn-goodman-vTL_qy03D1I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Radiant disciples" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t look at the sun, it&amp;rsquo;s far too bright. Any attempt even to look nearby overloads our retina, so all else fades into nothing. And so it is with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the source of the radiance. Ours is merely a reflection, unlikely to cause blindness, but bright and shining nonetheless, and enormously attractive to those who don&amp;rsquo;t have it. How does this work, then? We must consider how to be those who &lt;em&gt;look to him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with forgiveness — &lt;em&gt;their faces are never covered with shame&lt;/em&gt;. All is forgiven, all debt is cancelled and all shame is gone. This is the glorious truth that underpins everything we are as children of God. Rejoice in that forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues with hope. As we look to the Lord, we look with the hope that notwithstanding all that we have already received, his work in us is not yet complete. There&amp;rsquo;s more to come, and what is to come is so certain and so very good, and so much more than we could possibly ask or imagine. This is our source of joy, our source of radiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we love the Lord, with a grateful heart that magnifies that love, and irrepressible hope that fuels it with tremendous power. When someone is in love, absolutely captivated, they have a glow about them, evidenced in shining eyes and wonder. This is powerful and joyous, and others desire it. May we know this as we look to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him, Amy, bask in his glory which shines like the sun in all its brilliance, and be radiant! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiveness and purification</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 06:44:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/nega-YdyhHbWZ1V0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiveness and purification" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a well loved verse from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter, that we may be in danger of reading too quickly and missing the most important word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some important words here. Confess. Sins. And some wonderful, lifting words. Faithful. Forgive. Purify. But what am I referring to? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. &lt;em&gt;Just&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem to be a little out of place, yet it is the crucial word. Consider why. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours, in full. If we confess our sins, and cry out to God for mercy, it is his &lt;em&gt;justice&lt;/em&gt; that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment. Rejoice, that he is faithful &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; just.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
