<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>integrity on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/integrity/</link>
        <description>Recent content in integrity on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/integrity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>In pursuit of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/jonathan-chng-3R4vPrSB1c4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post In pursuit of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this wisdom in the secret heart is so precious in the sight of the Lord then surely it is worth pursuing with zeal and determination. How exactly can we do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man [or woman] keep his [or her] way pure? By guarding it according to your word.&lt;br&gt;
With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments!&lt;br&gt;
I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed are you, O LORD; teach me your statutes!&lt;br&gt;
With my lips I declare all the rules of your mouth.&lt;br&gt;
In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches.&lt;br&gt;
I will meditate on your precepts and fix my eyes on your ways.&lt;br&gt;
I will delight in your statutes; I will not forget your word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 takes us into the depths, the depths of longing for the Lord, of desiring to be right with him, for an alignment of our secret heart with his will, and for his plans and purposes to be unfolded in our lives. Truly it challenges Ephesians Chapter One in my heart for which I would take to that desert island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see how to pursue wisdom in the secret heart. These are the headlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With my whole heart&lt;/em&gt; — no compromise! Ruthless consistency is required. Nothing can remain that is displeasing to the Lord, and in this we should expect to be tested. Will we take the Lord seriously or not? He is not deceived and nor should we be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have stored up your word in my heart &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — more than just knowing, this is loving⸺loving to spend time with the Lord in his word. His word in our hearts must be that which fuels our very lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; that I might not sin against you&lt;/em&gt; — our ongoing sanctification, our growing in holiness, is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessed are you, O Lord&lt;/em&gt; — we must meditate on the goodness of God, over and over, dwelling in it, reminding ourselves of his mercy. All his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness! To displace those idols which compete for our affection we must grow such a love for our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches&lt;/em&gt; — our Heavenly Father reveals himself to us through his written word. May we delight to read it, and to read it more, and to surrender our will to it, joyfully, ever growing in relationship with the one who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will meditate on your precepts &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — with a surrendered heart, taking all the time required for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s holy word to permeate our hearts and lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; and fix my eyes on your ways&lt;/em&gt; — every cyclist knows that you end up in the place where you fix your eyes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is required in pursuit of these things and we are not left alone in this. It is the heart-work of the Holy Spirit, his utmost desire for us, but we must not overlook how much discipline is required on our part, as Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that in a race all the runners run, but only one receives the prize? So run that you may obtain it. Every athlete exercises self-control in all things. They do it to receive a perishable wreath, but we an imperishable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 9:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lest we forget what is at stake,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all vigilance, Amy, pursue wisdom in the secret heart, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Wisdom in the secret heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/wisdom-in-the-secret-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/wisdom-in-the-secret-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/wisdom-in-the-secret-heart/mike-lewis-headsmart-media-waAAaeC9hns-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Wisdom in the secret heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is wisdom in the secret heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phrase is used by David in his psalm of repentance, following his crisis of being confronted by the prophet Nathan about his adultery with Bathsheba and his murder of her husband, Uriah the Hittite⸺confronted with the wickedness and wretchedness of his sinful heart, desperate to be restored into relationship with the Lord, desperate to be clean, desperate to have again a right spirit within him. And at this time of crisis suddenly he is given real insight, which comes as a shaft of light in the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, you delight in truth in the inward being, and you teach me wisdom in the secret heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 51:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not something he has known in recent times, and he longs for it. But what is it exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This word wisdom is what appears throughout the book of Proverbs, and in particular,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom, and the knowledge of the Holy One is insight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 9:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We simply must start there, with reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done⸺this is wisdom&amp;rsquo;s beginning. Everything we do and all that we are must be oriented to acknowledge and honour the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wisdom continues with our behaviour. What we do, look at, read, watch, listen to, and where and with whom we go, these all shape us, and require ruthless consistency if we are to live with wisdom. We see its absence so clearly in that hapless, foolish youth of Proverbs 7 walking in the way of temptation, thinking it was his lucky day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; as a bird rushes into a snare; he does not know that it will cost him his life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 7:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavioural wisdom can save us from such an outcome⸺but that is nothing more than Wisdom 101. Wisdom in the secret heart goes beyond that, far beyond. As far as this, in fact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must consider then what it means to keep my heart with all vigilance. This is about what I set my affection upon, what I long for, the narrative I pursue with myself when I grapple with life&amp;rsquo;s ups and downs, the truths I cling to, the battles I fight, the Lord I honour, or not. All of this is in the secret heart. It is this that determines the whole course of my life, and it is this that the Lord desires to teach me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it look like, this wisdom in the secret heart? Nothing visible externally, at least, nothing directly visible. For surely it results in a groundedness, an authenticity which is truly compelling, when there is truth in the inward being, when the secret heart is aligned with all that pleases and glorifies the Lord. And then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, you delight in truth in the inward being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 51:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrity is found in the secret heart. Truth is found in the secret heart. Wisdom is found in the secret heart. And the Lord delights in these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all vigilance, Amy, pursue wisdom in the secret heart, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ruthless consistency</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/nick-fewings-4x9cfxaiBYQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Ruthless consistency" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else follows from ruthless consistency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already saw that ruthless consistency is the enabler for engaging our whole mind in faith, but there&amp;rsquo;s more to be found along this path, much more. By bringing our intellect into alignment with the eternal truths of the Lord, our mind is renewed, so much so, as if it were previously firing on only a few of the available cylinders. Paul writes about this to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not conform to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind. Then you will be able to test and approve what God’s will is⸺his good, pleasing and perfect will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewed minds transform our very lives. Otherwise how blindly we may find ourselves following along in the ways of the world: judging others, taking offence, living for self, and being so pleased with ourselves, smug and self-righteous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewing of the mind and the life-transformation that follows is an ongoing process, fuelled by a ruthless consistency in seeking to honour the Lord⸺that ruthless consistency which compels us to root out and expel every sin, every misplaced thought. To replace love of self with love for the Lord and for one another, and to do this with zeal and great joy. To dwell in love and faithfulness, gentleness and kindness and patience, and to live with humility and absolute integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then? Then we will be able to test and approve what God’s will is. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider for a moment what that means, as it&amp;rsquo;s not immediately apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test here means to be able to recognise as genuine after examination. For example being able to see the Lord&amp;rsquo;s handiwork in situations which might otherwise be difficult to endure. In all things God works for our good, and some of these things are painful indeed, and can be prolonged. With a renewed mind we are able to perceive his grace in these very situations as he works on our hearts, preparing us for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And our approval simply means saying, yes Lord! Accepting, and making a joyful surrender⸺even in the difficulty and the pain⸺to the power and grace and healing from the Lord which is making us like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with ruthless consistency, Amy, and be transformed by the renewing of your mind! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Integrity and uprightness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/chris-brignola-X2CxUXFqKcM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Integrity and uprightness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can goodness protect us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; goodness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greek word is &lt;em&gt;agathōsunē&lt;/em&gt;, which can be translated &lt;em&gt;uprightness of heart and life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look briefly again into Psalm 25 (what a jewel of a psalm that is!), where David writes with such humility, so aware of his own shortcomings and his desire to live a life of integrity, honouring the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect me, because my hope is in you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see protection there, but how does that work? Before we get to that, read the whole psalm and notice that there is not a shred of smug self-satisfaction as David seeks with all his heart to honour the Lord and live a right life. Paul also writes of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must seek with our whole heart to live as slaves to righteousness, purging every wrong thought and deed, pouring ourselves out in humility and gratitude to the Lord. The Holy Spirit enables us to do this. It is a miracle of grace that sinners such as we are, even forgiven sinners, can live with such integrity and uprightness, evidence in our own lives of the victory Jesus won on the cross. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we live with humility as slaves to righteousness, continuing to be sanctified by the Holy Spirit, integrity and uprightness keep us on the narrow path that leads to life, and it is this that protects us. The process is ongoing, and so is the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect you, Amy, as you live as a slave to righteousness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hard teaching</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 06:39:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/maranda-vandergriff-9mqdPNk2Xwc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hard teaching" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain passages or verses in the Bible are really hard to understand. How should we approach them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intention this week was to write about telling a mountain to throw itself into the sea, not doubting. But when I looked into the context, I found that Jesus said it after cursing the fig tree on approaching Jerusalem for the last week of his life. How do we understand that? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about that first, and I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to the mountain another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day as they were leaving Bethany, Jesus was hungry. Seeing in the distance a fig tree in leaf, he went to find out if it had any fruit. When he reached it, he found nothing but leaves, because it was not the season for figs. Then he said to the tree, “May no one ever eat fruit from you again.” And his disciples heard him say it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning, as they went along, they saw the fig tree withered from the roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:12-14, 20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this reasonable? It was not the season for figs! This seems so harsh. It is certainly hard to understand. What should we do with passages like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we ought not to anthropomorphize the tree. It was just a tree. It served a purpose, to illustrate a teaching point of Jesus. Nobody suffered in the making of this point. But still!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst comment I read about this explained that first fruits appear early, and Jesus would have expected there to be figs for that reason. But Mark would have known that, and would have said, there were no first fruits. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t the reason given! Let us not second guess the gospel writers. The Lord is responsible for his own reputation, and has no need of our defence, no need of our pitiful attempts to make him look good. Let us not brush aside these difficulties with bogus explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was about to suffer and die, for the sins of all humanity. This was God&amp;rsquo;s plan, and it required rejection and brutal treatment of the Son of God by those who should have been fruitful for the Kingdom, but were not. Was the fig tree a symbol of the Jews who rejected Jesus? It was not their season to be fruitful, and they were severely judged. Is this harsh? It is a hard teaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cannot claim perfect understanding of the mysteries of God. But as we grapple, let us do so with intellectual integrity, being faithful to Scripture, and honouring the Lord. And may we continue to love and trust him when the limits of our understanding are exceeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love and trust, Amy, and don&amp;rsquo;t stop grappling! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>On being vulnerable</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/on-being-vulnerable/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/on-being-vulnerable/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/on-being-vulnerable/vitaliy-zalishchyker-3Ank_q_qVtE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post On being vulnerable" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it so important to be vulnerable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our every instinct is to protect and defend, to justify ourselves, and yet we must not do it!  Why is this?  Paul wrote to the Corinthians about his vision and the thorn in his flesh, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Lord said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly about my weaknesses, so that Christ’s power may rest on me &amp;hellip; I delight in weaknesses &amp;hellip; for when I am weak, then I am strong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 12:9, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am judged, even when the judgment is as ignorant as it is harsh, I choose not to defend myself. How easy is it to do this? It is the hardest thing! It is dying to self. (But, my integrity is not defined by what others think of me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reputation is the idol of our age, both within and without the church, maybe the greatest barrier to the gospel, to the transforming power of the Holy Spirit, and to us honouring the Lord with our whole lives. Here are the four most oppressive words, that empty us of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and make us utterly useless for him: &lt;em&gt;what will they think?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will they think of me? I choose not to care! And here is the reason to be vulnerable, to not care about this. Suddenly I can share the gospel with great power, and absolute confidence. I am invincible, because what defines me is unassailable! (2 Cor 5:17, Col 3:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Let me reach down from my pedestal of perfection and set you on the right path, O hapless misguided sinner.” No! No! No! A hundred times no! That is the way of the Pharisee, and the Lord is not in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather, “Let me tell you of the one who rescued me”, risking the contemptuous, sneering reply, “What? Did you need to be rescued?” Yes, I did. I was rescued, am being rescued, will be rescued. It is ongoing, and I am unashamed. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be vulnerable and unashamed, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
