<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>gratitude on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/gratitude/</link>
        <description>Recent content in gratitude on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/gratitude/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Answered prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/answered-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/answered-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/answered-prayer/alexander-krivitskiy-3HcR4bxfogM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Answered prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is it to mind our P&amp;rsquo;s and Q&amp;rsquo;s in prayer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s think for a moment about answered prayer, and what Paul has to say about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 4:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important to be watchful in prayer? Why, so we can thank the Lord for his gracious response of course! Before we can thank him we first have to notice the answer. How joyous it is to notice answer to prayer, and how it fuels our ongoing praying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During your recent journey to and stopover in Port Moresby for your police check there were two specific things I was praying for you, Amy. Firstly for travelling mercies and safety, especially in that city which is described in the New Zealand government advice for travellers as particularly dangerous. I thank the Lord for his safekeeping of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing I was praying most earnestly was for a ridiculously swift processing of your police check. I imagine that Papua New Guinea is a place where such things can take four months or twelve months or forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that others were praying the very same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what happened? It was all processed within two days! How utterly ridiculous! And what an answer to prayer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my follow-up prayer after “Please Lord” is “Thank you, thank you, thank you!” Thank you Lord, for your protection and provision and grace and kindness to Amy, your faithful servant. Thank you Lord! Thank you, thank you, thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t he wonderful? Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s notice what Paul wrote about a particularly low point in his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we do not want you to be unaware, brothers, of the affliction we experienced in Asia. For we were so utterly burdened beyond our strength that we despaired of life itself. Indeed, we felt that we had received the sentence of death. But that was to make us rely not on ourselves but on God who raises the dead. He delivered us from such a deadly peril, and he will deliver us. On him we have set our hope that he will deliver us again. You also must help us by prayer, so that many will give thanks on our behalf for the blessing granted us through the prayers of many.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 1:8-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us not overlook quite how much we can help by prayer. We must do this! And let many give thanks for the blessing granted through these prayers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prayer is such a mystery, isn&amp;rsquo;t it, and unanswered prayer especially so? But from time to time, like your visit to Port Moresby, we get an insight into the love and care and provision and immediacy of the Lord like a shaft of light beaming down from heaven. It is both overwhelmingly joyous and thoroughly humbling. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give thanks, Amy, for answered prayer, and may it fuel your ongoing praying, for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own glory and the blessing of the saints! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Thankfulness that glorifies</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/thankfulness-that-glorifies/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/thankfulness-that-glorifies/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/thankfulness-that-glorifies/joshua-clay-VNjNtdu0yCw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Thankfulness that glorifies" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can our thankfulness glorify the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will praise God’s name in song and glorify him with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 69:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an aspect to thankfulness that I want to explore this week, which is this: receiving kindness from those around us as from the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone treats me with particular kindness, who am I likely to thank? Too often we think in purely human terms, but there&amp;rsquo;s another dimension here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s one side of the coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For it is God who works in you to will and to act in order to fulfil his good purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we are God’s handiwork, created in Christ Jesus to do good works, which God prepared in advance for us to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has plans and purposes, and he works in and through each one of us to fulfil them. He works even in the lives of those who neither honour nor acknowledge him. We know this. Now consider the other side of that coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that the Lord delights in exercising kindness (Jeremiah 9:24)⸺this is one of his good purposes! So when we receive kindness from others, why would we not make that connection and ascribe it to him? To do so makes my soul sing in gratitude to my Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I experienced exactly this, twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one occasion I was in church, after the morning service. Church can be the loneliest place, and I was facing the bleak prospect of a Sunday afternoon by myself, at a time when I was particularly downcast. Just outside church and completely out of the blue, a friend invited me mountain biking that afternoon, in a way that seemed so random and so kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other was on my birthday, and I was at home in a melancholic mood. Suddenly there was a knock on my back door. It was my neighbour, with a slice of apple shortcake she had just made, and a little tub of cream to go with it. How lovely. She had no idea it was my birthday, nor did I tell her. How random again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have learned that these random acts of kindness are not remotely random. I ascribe them to my Heavenly Father, and thank him. And through these he makes known his own character, his overflowing kindness, and he is glorified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise God’s name in song, Amy, and glorify him with thanksgiving! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
