<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>wisdom on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/wisdom/</link>
        <description>Recent content in wisdom on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/wisdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>In pursuit of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/jonathan-chng-3R4vPrSB1c4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post In pursuit of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this wisdom in the secret heart is so precious in the sight of the Lord then surely it is worth pursuing with zeal and determination. How exactly can we do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man [or woman] keep his [or her] way pure? By guarding it according to your word.&lt;br&gt;
With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments!&lt;br&gt;
I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed are you, O LORD; teach me your statutes!&lt;br&gt;
With my lips I declare all the rules of your mouth.&lt;br&gt;
In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches.&lt;br&gt;
I will meditate on your precepts and fix my eyes on your ways.&lt;br&gt;
I will delight in your statutes; I will not forget your word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 takes us into the depths, the depths of longing for the Lord, of desiring to be right with him, for an alignment of our secret heart with his will, and for his plans and purposes to be unfolded in our lives. Truly it challenges Ephesians Chapter One in my heart for which I would take to that desert island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see how to pursue wisdom in the secret heart. These are the headlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With my whole heart&lt;/em&gt; — no compromise! Ruthless consistency is required. Nothing can remain that is displeasing to the Lord, and in this we should expect to be tested. Will we take the Lord seriously or not? He is not deceived and nor should we be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have stored up your word in my heart &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — more than just knowing, this is loving⸺loving to spend time with the Lord in his word. His word in our hearts must be that which fuels our very lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; that I might not sin against you&lt;/em&gt; — our ongoing sanctification, our growing in holiness, is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessed are you, O Lord&lt;/em&gt; — we must meditate on the goodness of God, over and over, dwelling in it, reminding ourselves of his mercy. All his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness! To displace those idols which compete for our affection we must grow such a love for our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches&lt;/em&gt; — our Heavenly Father reveals himself to us through his written word. May we delight to read it, and to read it more, and to surrender our will to it, joyfully, ever growing in relationship with the one who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will meditate on your precepts &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — with a surrendered heart, taking all the time required for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s holy word to permeate our hearts and lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; and fix my eyes on your ways&lt;/em&gt; — every cyclist knows that you end up in the place where you fix your eyes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is required in pursuit of these things and we are not left alone in this. It is the heart-work of the Holy Spirit, his utmost desire for us, but we must not overlook how much effort and discipline is required on our part, as Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that in a race all the runners run, but only one receives the prize? So run that you may obtain it. Every athlete exercises self-control in all things. They do it to receive a perishable wreath, but we an imperishable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 9:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lest we forget what is at stake,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all vigilance, Amy, pursue wisdom in the secret heart, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Wisdom in the secret heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/wisdom-in-the-secret-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/wisdom-in-the-secret-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/wisdom-in-the-secret-heart/mike-lewis-headsmart-media-waAAaeC9hns-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Wisdom in the secret heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is wisdom in the secret heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phrase is used by David in his psalm of repentance, following his crisis of being confronted by the prophet Nathan about his adultery with Bathsheba and his murder of her husband, Uriah the Hittite⸺confronted with the wickedness and wretchedness of his sinful heart, desperate to be restored into relationship with the Lord, desperate to be clean, desperate to have again a right spirit within him. And at this time of crisis suddenly he is given real insight, which comes as a shaft of light in the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, you delight in truth in the inward being, and you teach me wisdom in the secret heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 51:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not something he has known in recent times, and he longs for it. But what is it exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This word wisdom is what appears throughout the book of Proverbs, and in particular,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom, and the knowledge of the Holy One is insight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 9:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We simply must start there, with reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done⸺this is wisdom&amp;rsquo;s beginning. Everything we do and all that we are must be oriented to acknowledge and honour the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wisdom continues with our behaviour. What we do, look at, read, watch, listen to, and where and with whom we go, these all shape us, and require ruthless consistency if we are to live with wisdom. We see its absence so clearly in that hapless, foolish youth of Proverbs 7 walking in the way of temptation, thinking it was his lucky day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; as a bird rushes into a snare; he does not know that it will cost him his life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 7:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavioural wisdom can save us from such an outcome⸺but that is nothing more than Wisdom 101. Wisdom in the secret heart goes beyond that, far beyond. As far as this, in fact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must consider then what it means to keep my heart with all vigilance. This is about what I set my affection upon, what I long for, the narrative I pursue with myself when I grapple with life&amp;rsquo;s ups and downs, the truths I cling to, the battles I fight, the Lord I honour, or not. All of this is in the secret heart. It is this that determines the whole course of my life, and it is this that the Lord desires to teach me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it look like, this wisdom in the secret heart? Nothing visible externally, at least, nothing directly visible. For surely it results in a groundedness, an authenticity which is truly compelling, when there is truth in the inward being, when the secret heart is aligned with all that pleases and glorifies the Lord. And then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, you delight in truth in the inward being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 51:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrity is found in the secret heart. Truth is found in the secret heart. Wisdom is found in the secret heart. And the Lord delights in these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all vigilance, Amy, pursue wisdom in the secret heart, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to get what you want</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/jen-theodore-ualbj7tyJH0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to get what you want" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I told you there was a way to get exactly what you want? That the Spirit would work towards this end, and the Lord himself would make it so? Absolutely guaranteed. Are you interested in that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of promise is this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem too good to be true? Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to delight yourself in the Lord? It is no small thing. Let me paraphrase. &lt;em&gt;Make the Lord the desire of your heart, and he will give you &amp;hellip; the desire of your heart.&lt;/em&gt; Dwell in that for a while. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re not disappointed, because truth be told, it&amp;rsquo;s a phenomenal promise. Jeremiah says the same, just after that verse that everyone quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You will seek me and find me when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this look like? To seek the Lord with all your heart? To make him your heart&amp;rsquo;s desire? It is surely time-consuming. In fact, it is all-consuming. It is worth waking up early for. It is worth pursuing through the day, and resting in through the night. We cannot afford to be half-hearted in this. David said as much to his own son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you, my son Solomon, acknowledge the God of your father, and serve him with wholehearted devotion and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches every heart and understands every motive behind the thoughts. If you seek him, he will be found by you;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There can be no pretending here. He &lt;em&gt;understands every motive behind the thoughts&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s confronting! So we must be absolutely ruthless, rooting out and expelling every misplaced thought and motive. This takes real work, earnest heart-work. But it is Spirit work. It is what he does. It is the work he knows so well. In him, and only in him, we can do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the Lord, Amy, and he will give you the desires of your heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The master craftsman</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/jonny-gios-KGL7Rw_-YPY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The master craftsman" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be completely confident in surrendering to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we retain some level of control? What might he do in our lives, by the Holy Spirit unleashed with power and authority? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it just all too scary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me ask a different question which may provide some insight. If I invite the Spirit into my situation, into my life, how can I be sure he will do what I am hoping for? What I want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many leave this question unstated, and yet it remains in their subconscious, in the background, undermining confidence in the Lord and trust in him. But it must be articulated, because only then can we repudiate it. Of course he won&amp;rsquo;t do what I want! The very idea is preposterous! He will do his own work, the work that he knows so well, at which he is the master. So the better question to ask is, what is that work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already considered this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To him who is able to keep you from falling and to present you before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy⸺to the only God our Saviour be glory, majesty, power and authority, through Jesus Christ our Lord, before all ages, now and for evermore! Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work is to keep us from falling and to present us before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy.  It is a heart work, where he transforms us from wretches, having the smallest, meanest, most selfish lives and motives, into sons and daughters, having abundance of life and joy in the Lord, living as slaves to righteousness, with hearts bursting with love for our Saviour and for our brothers and sisters in Christ. And he will do whatever it takes to achieve this purpose, no matter the cost, to him or to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who did not spare his own Son, but gave him up for us all⸺how will he not also, along with him, graciously give us all things?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not make the mistake as some have done, of thinking this means he will give us whatever we want. By no means! But he will give us whatever &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; wants, in pursuit of his goal for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrender joyfully, Amy, and trust the master craftsman who knows his work, who along with his own Son, will graciously give you all things! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 06:43:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know the will of the Lord? Let&amp;rsquo;s look again into the treasure trove which is Psalm 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, then, are those who fear the LORD? He will instruct them in the ways he chooses (v12).  The LORD confides in those who fear him; he makes his covenant known to them (v14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Keller defines the fear of the Lord as this, in a sermon from Proverbs on the fear of the Lord being the beginning of wisdom. &amp;ldquo;The fear of the Lord is a reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My prayer for you is that you learn to live this more each day.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
