<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>witness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/witness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in witness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/witness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>From glory to glory</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/joshua-j-cotten-dMn92oICKFY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post From glory to glory" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can those made in the image of God be transformed into his image? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that a bit, well, circular?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we all, with unveiled face, reflecting the glory of the Lord, are being transformed into the same image from one degree of glory to another. For this comes from the Lord who is the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chapter Paul is contrasting the old and new covenants, characterising the old covenant as “the ministry of death” (v7) and “the ministry of condemnation” (v9), oh my! What do we need to know to understand what he writes here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hope in the new covenant is in the ministry of the Spirit and the ministry of righteousness⸺our righteousness in Christ, purchased at such great cost⸺a permanent glory (v8-11). In contrast, when Moses came down from Mount Sinai, while his face initially shone with the reflected glory of the Lord, he covered himself with a veil so that the Israelites would not see how quickly it faded (Exodus 34:29-35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s follow Paul&amp;rsquo;s reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since we have such a hope, we are very bold, not like Moses, who would put a veil over his face so that the Israelites might not gaze at the outcome of what was being brought to an end. But their minds were hardened. For to this day, when they read the old covenant, that same veil remains unlifted, because only through Christ is it taken away. Yes, to this day whenever Moses is read a veil lies over their hearts. But when one turns to the Lord, the veil is removed. Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:12-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who live under the old covenant live with a veil over their hearts to cover the shame of failing to live up to what is required, for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God (Romans 3:23).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why then are we so bold? Because we stand in Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness, not our own. Hallelujah! Our faces are unveiled because there is no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus (Romans 8:1). Only through Christ is the veil taken away. No condemnation. No fear. No shame. Freedom is ours! Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we, the rescued ones, beloved of God, are being transformed from one degree of glory into another. What we were created to be has not yet been seen in our lives. Assuredly we were made in the image of God, but that became so tarnished by sin, by that rebellion against God passed down through the ages from the first man and the first woman. There is, however, such a joyous anticipation in the ongoing process of sanctification, of being made holy, through which we will be made into that which we were always meant to be. And get this: &lt;em&gt;we ourselves are fully a part of that process&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For in his great wisdom, in the mystery of his marvellous ways, the Lord chooses to involve us in that transformation. It comes when we surrender our will to the Holy Spirit, and when we do, how it comes! Look at the lovely way that Paul describes those who are being transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you show that you are a letter from Christ delivered by us, written not with ink but with the Spirit of the living God, not on tablets of stone but on tablets of human hearts.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are a letter from Christ, Amy, written on the tablet of your own heart, a witness before the nations to his great love and mercy and grace and his power to transform into his own likeness! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A great cloud of witnesses</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/sandeep-damre-14IPTP-6mTc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A great cloud of witnesses" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently we are surrounded by a great cloud of witnesses, and this is a reason to run the race with perseverance. What&amp;rsquo;s all that about?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important that we understand this, because doesn&amp;rsquo;t it sound just a little bit creepy? Are all these witnesses sitting in heaven watching us, and so had we better not embarrass ourselves for that reason? By no means! (as Paul would say). That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what this is not saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these witnesses are listed in Chapter 11, with this introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now faith is being sure of what we hope for and certain of what we do not see. This is what the ancients were commended for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer then goes on to list the incredible demonstrations of faith by these witnesses, and they are incredible. But what is it that they are witnessing? Is it us? No, it&amp;rsquo;s not us. Here&amp;rsquo;s what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By their faith they are &lt;em&gt;witnesses to the Lord&lt;/em&gt;, to his goodness and kindness and faithfulness. When we live lives of radical faith it points to the one who enables us to do that, to the one for whom we live. And they were commended for it and highly honoured because this is glorious, to live in such a way that our very lives bear testimony to the Lord. This is a powerful witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is why &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; run the race with perseverance. It is a powerful witness. The only ones watching are our contemporaries (oh, and the Lord, obviously — Ps 139, Rev 20:12). But if we run this race well, the Lord may choose to use &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; witness to save some of &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with perseverance, Amy, and join the great cloud of witnesses in testifying to the goodness, kindness and faithfulness of the Lord! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
