<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>sanctification on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/sanctification/</link>
        <description>Recent content in sanctification on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/sanctification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The journey</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-journey/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-journey/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-journey/finding-dan-dan-grinwis-O35rT6OytRo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The journey" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this life for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been stated with exceeding clarity by those who went before us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the chief end of man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man’s chief end is to glorify God, and to enjoy him forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Westminster Shorter Catechism, 1647&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can refocus and reframe our whole lives, especially that word &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt;. But let me for a moment observe that our glorification of the Lord and our enjoyment of him will be so much the greater in our post resurrection life, so let me ask, what is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; life for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a related question. Is this life more about the journey or the destination?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly I long for the destination, to arrive in the presence of my Lord and Saviour, to finally stand face to face. John describes the meeting as it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a new heaven and a new earth, for the first heaven and the first earth had passed away, and the sea was no more. And I saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the bride of Christ, his beloved church of which you and I are members, Amy, and in the words of that beautiful song,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;She will be who he adores, this is what he made her for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Casting Crowns, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyTuh0v4jnY&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Wedding Day&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is this preparation of which John speaks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preparation is this life. It is the journey. The destination that I must therefore focus on is that of &lt;em&gt;the state of my heart&lt;/em&gt;. I desire to arrive well, welcomed into heaven with smiles and joy, not as one escaping through the flames (1 Corinthians 3:15). In advance of that, there is heart-work to be done, so that on that day I will not be ashamed at the smallness of my own heart and its miserly love for my Saviour and for my fellow travellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so this realisation informs every choice I make on the journey. The Holy Spirit continues to do his work of sanctifying grace in my life and I surrender to it joyfully and my heart is transformed. Slowly. Surely. Through each painful moment, I continue to die to self and live for him, all the while longing for that day, and all the while growing in love for my wonderful Saviour and his beloved church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journey well, Amy!  🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Personal holiness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/jeffery-erhunse-4XK2oKKvzVU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Personal holiness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you think of another aspect of worship which has nothing to do with singing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, I urge you, brothers and sisters, in view of God’s mercy, to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God⸺this is your spiritual act of worship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the act of worship which is personal holiness, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the most important word here: &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; links what follows to the entirety of the previous eleven chapters, which is Paul&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the wretched state of humankind without Christ, and of the magnitude and sufficiency of our rescue in Christ, God&amp;rsquo;s free and costly gift of grace to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now a righteousness from God, apart from law, has been made known, to which the Law and the Prophets testify. This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where, then, is boasting? It is excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:21-22, 27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My response then to this gift of grace and righteousness must be to live a life of personal holiness. As I live my life, each day facing temptation, and each day surrendering my will to the sanctifying work of the Spirit, I articulate each small victory as an act of worship to my Heavenly Father who loves me and has rescued me from such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; offer yourselves to God, as those who have been brought from death to life; and offer the parts of your body to him as instruments of righteousness. For sin shall not be your master, because you are not under law, but under grace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should note that God&amp;rsquo;s call to personal holiness is not to the righteous but to sinners, and we would do well to remember his call to Abraham out of the absolute mess and shame that he found himself in thirteen long years after his shabby act with Hagar. Hear the grace and love in this, right alongside the uncompromising call to holiness. Our Heavenly Father has so much love and such a high expectation for his sons and daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old, the LORD appeared to him and said, “I am God Almighty; walk before me and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only in Christ can we live like this, but in him, we can! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer your body as a living sacrifice, Amy, holy and pleasing to God, and worship him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The breastplate of righteousness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 07:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/Lorica_segmentata.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The breastplate of righteousness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the breastplate of righteousness, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand firm then &amp;hellip; with the breastplate of righteousness in place &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the function of the breastplate is to protect the torso, the heart and lungs, those vital organs without which we cannot live. But what is the nature of this righteousness without which we cannot live before the Lord? It is interesting to see how writers disagree about this, because there are two possible answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the gospel a righteousness from God is revealed, a righteousness that is by faith from first to last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first view is that the breastplate is Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to us, a free gift of grace received entirely through &lt;em&gt;faith&lt;/em&gt;. We can stand firm irrespective of our own wretchedness and sin and failure because of this righteousness from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is profound truth in this. But there is another view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But thanks be to God that, though you used to be slaves to sin, you wholeheartedly obeyed the form of teaching to which you were entrusted. You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:17-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Very truly I tell you, whoever keeps my word will never see death.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:51&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being slaves to righteousness and living in total surrender and complete obedience to God is about our sanctification, and ultimately our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;, as we are transformed into the likeness of Christ and live lives that reflect that. Faith or works? Are these contradictory? Jim Packer has a helpful explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final judgment, as we saw, will be according to our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;⸺that is, our &lt;em&gt;doings&lt;/em&gt;, our whole course of life. The relevance of our &amp;lsquo;doings&amp;rsquo; is not that they ever merit an award from the court⸺they are too far short of perfection to do that⸺but that they provide an index of what is in the heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that one way of acting was meritorious while the other was not, but that from these actions one can tell whether there was love to Christ, the love that springs from faith, in the
heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J.I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Knowing God, Chapter 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James takes up this very idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Show me your faith without deeds, and I will show you my faith by my deeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 2:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we can see it clearly. The righteousness is Christ&amp;rsquo;s alone, freely given and received through faith by us who believe, and initiating in us an ongoing transformation into slaves to righteousness. Through this we live ever more radically changed lives, and through this we have assurance of salvation. The merit is all Christ&amp;rsquo;s and so is the glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand firm in the battle, Amy, wholly depending on Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to you, and have assurance of that by the evidence of your own transformed life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
