<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>pain on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/pain/</link>
        <description>Recent content in pain on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Two kinds of sorrow</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/brahm-meyer-xwG9LGmc1Qk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two kinds of sorrow" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can sorrow ever be a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What of this, that Paul writes to the Corinthians?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even if I caused you sorrow by my letter, I do not regret it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Paul somehow pleased with himself because he stuck it to those wretched Corinthians in his first letter? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet now I am happy, not because you were made sorry, but because your sorrow led you to repentance. For you became sorrowful as God intended and so were not harmed in any way by us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their sorrow was as God intended and led to repentance. This is Godly sorrow, and the Lord uses it to expose sin in our lives to bring repentance and healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I weep over the shame and failure in my life and cry out to the Lord, this also is Godly sorrow, a gift of love from my Heavenly Father, received through the conviction that comes by the Holy Spirit. It drives me into the arms of my loving Heavenly Father, from shame to repentance and forgiveness and healing, and is, through the healing, eventually and ultimately, a cause for rejoicing in my wonderful Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we must beware. There is another sorrow which leads to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Godly sorrow brings repentance that leads to salvation and leaves no regret, but worldly sorrow brings death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldly sorrow is what I experience out of a sense of entitlement, a sense of “it&amp;rsquo;s not fair”, an inclination to blame God for all that&amp;rsquo;s wrong in my life. It is self-indulgent and self-pitying and full of regret. This drives me away from my loving Heavenly Father and brings death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two are so very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with your sorrow into the arms of your loving Heavenly Father, Amy, and receive healing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The God of all comfort</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/helena-lopes-ikOKjyLZRno-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The God of all comfort" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the nature of the comfort we can receive from God, and how can we receive it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life can be so hard. We need this comfort. So we need to understand just what it is, and how it works. Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise be to the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of compassion and the God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our troubles, so that we can comfort those in any trouble with the comfort we ourselves have received from God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gained some insight into this recently, quite indirectly and unexpectedly. Just as I was arriving back home from a run, I bumped into a friend, a professor of theology with whom I have had some interesting and uplifting conversations over the years. I remarked that I had been struck by the incredible grace and kindness of the Lord. He then asked an interesting question: “Did something particularly good just happen?” to which the answer was no, not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I reflected on this later, it made me a little sad. So often, the grace of God is understood as being received through our circumstances, equated with something good and pleasant happening to us. How impoverished can be our understanding of grace! The grace of God is a powerful, tangible thing, which can be received and experienced in its own right, independently of any change in circumstance. And invisible to others, save perhaps for some glow about us as we receive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with comfort. If we read around those verses we see the context of the comfort is severe hardship, hardly pleasant circumstances. In particular, note this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For just as the sufferings of Christ flow over into our lives, so also through Christ our comfort overflows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering and comfort here are hand-in-hand. This comfort from God is not received through observable, physical happenings. It is received directly. It is wonderful, powerful, and oh so tangible, a gift from the Father of compassion himself. A heavenly hug, so to speak, from the one who loves us beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever is happening, Amy, receive comfort directly from the God of all comfort, the Father of compassion, the one who loves you beyond imagining! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/sasha-freemind-nXo2ZsKHTHg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unanswered prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7, 11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unanswered prayer is a real thing. How can we deal with it? Many have grappled with this, and much has been written. Some have said, the Lord always answers prayer: sometimes yes; sometimes no; sometimes not yet. I find this glib and unhelpful. Because sometimes there is silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a husband and father, let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mark, a faithful servant of the Lord, suffering with severe health issues for so many years, for whom we have been faithfully, earnestly praying, confident that the Lord hears and is powerful to heal. Except he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, and this man dies, leaving his grieving wife, Grace, and their eight-year-old son, Callum. And from the Lord, only silence. What kind of answer to prayer is that? How is that a reasonable response to desperate prayers offered from a broken heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another way to see this. Unanswered prayer is an &lt;em&gt;invitation into relationship&lt;/em&gt;. An invitation into intimacy. How does this work? Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Why did Mark have to die? Don&amp;rsquo;t you care?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you have done something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “He loved you, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? Did you love him? You did love him, didn&amp;rsquo;t you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Yes, Amy, I loved him. I love him still.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “What about Grace and little Callum? This is breaking my heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;long pause, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Mine too, Amy. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit together for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;intimate, healing silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father grieves over his broken world, and the suffering his people bear. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with him, and grieve also, in the intimacy of his healing presence. And in the meantime,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us. For the creation waits in eager expectation for the children of God to be revealed. For the creation was subjected to frustration, not by its own choice, but by the will of the one who subjected it, in hope that the creation itself will be liberated from its bondage to decay and brought into the freedom and glory of the children of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:18-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit with the Lord in the silence of the unanswered prayer, Amy, in the intimacy of his healing presence 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why is life so hard?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/hugo-jehanne-LOHVrTsdvzY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Why is life so hard?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is life so hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider: the young person, to whom life seems so bleak they turn to self harm to try to anchor to reality; the older person who lives alone, who may go days without speaking with another, having long forgotten what it&amp;rsquo;s like to give and receive a hug; the faithful believer waiting on the Lord for the fulfillment of a promise, praising him in the heart-breaking years of waiting, or the one crying out for healing and enduring debilitating pain in the waiting and the praising; the grief in the death of a child. Why is life quite so very hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this may be a consequence of trying to live apart from the Lord, or simply failing to love one another, but some is not. What of that, then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul writes about this in Romans 8:18-27, in a passage sandwiched between two rather better known and loved celebrations of victory. If you possibly can, read it in The Message. Here&amp;rsquo;s an extract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The difficult times of pain throughout the world are simply birth pangs. But it’s not only around us; it’s within us. &amp;hellip; These sterile and barren bodies of ours are yearning for full deliverance. That is why waiting does not diminish us, any more than waiting diminishes a pregnant mother. We are enlarged in the waiting. &amp;hellip; the longer we wait, the larger we become, and the more joyful our expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s much in this world that is anaesthetic. Beware! It may dull the pain, but it will also dull the joyful expectancy. Perhaps only when we bear some pain ourselves can we be of any real use in the Kingdom. It need not be our own, but then it&amp;rsquo;s not too hard to find someone else&amp;rsquo;s, and wait with them in that. These are the places where God&amp;rsquo;s grace is most evident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait with joyful expectancy, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
