<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pain on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/pain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pain on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The God of all comfort</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is the nature of the comfort we can receive from God, and how can we receive it?
Life can be so hard. We need this comfort. So we need to understand just what it is, and how it works. Paul tells us.
 Praise be to the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of compassion and the God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our troubles, so that we can comfort those in any trouble with the comfort we ourselves have received from God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?
 [Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you &amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”
― Matthew 7:7, 11  “You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”
― John 14:14 But unanswered prayer is a real thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is life so hard?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Why is life so hard?
Consider: the young person, to whom life seems so bleak they turn to self harm to try to anchor to reality; the older person who lives alone, who may go days without speaking with another, having long forgotten what it&amp;rsquo;s like to give and receive a hug; the faithful believer waiting on the Lord for the fulfillment of a promise, praising him in the heart-breaking years of waiting, or the one crying out for healing and enduring debilitating pain in the waiting and the praising; the grief in the death of a child.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
