<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rescue on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/rescue/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rescue on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 06:28:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/rescue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The rescued life</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 06:28:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What difference does it make to have been rescued?
Cycling back from Karitane on Sunday afternoon, I saw my neighbours walking up the hill and stopped to say hello. They asked about the awful thing that happened to me in Rarotonga. Word evidently gets around! Instead I told them about the wonderful, impossible thing which happened, which resulted in me being alive and not dead.
Then I found myself saying, “every day feels like a bonus now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescue</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/rescue/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How many times will the Lord rescue? Isn&amp;rsquo;t once enough?
 “Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”
― Psalm 91:14 To be honest, my Bible actually says this:
 “Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”
 But gender is of no consequence here. What matters is this: the pronoun is singular.
Some think the only rescue is the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saves us from our sin and brings us into relationship with our Heavenly Father, but that&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On being vulnerable</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/on-being-vulnerable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/on-being-vulnerable/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Why is it so important to be vulnerable?
Our every instinct is to protect and defend, to justify ourselves, and yet we must not do it! Why is this? Paul wrote to the Corinthians about his vision and the thorn in his flesh, concluding:
 The Lord said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly about my weaknesses, so that Christ’s power may rest on me &amp;hellip; I delight in weaknesses &amp;hellip; for when I am weak, then I am strong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
