<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>knowing God on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/knowing-god/</link>
        <description>Recent content in knowing God on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/knowing-god/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>In pursuit of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/jonathan-chng-3R4vPrSB1c4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post In pursuit of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this wisdom in the secret heart is so precious in the sight of the Lord then surely it is worth pursuing with zeal and determination. How exactly can we do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man [or woman] keep his [or her] way pure? By guarding it according to your word.
With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments!
I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.
Blessed are you, O LORD; teach me your statutes!
With my lips I declare all the rules of your mouth.
In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches.
I will meditate on your precepts and fix my eyes on your ways.
I will delight in your statutes; I will not forget your word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 takes us into the depths, the depths of longing for the Lord, of desiring to be right with him, for an alignment of our secret heart with his will, and for his plans and purposes to be unfolded in our lives. Truly it challenges Ephesians Chapter One in my heart for which I would take to that desert island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see how to pursue wisdom in the secret heart. These are the headlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With my whole heart&lt;/em&gt; — no compromise! Ruthless consistency is required. Nothing can remain that is displeasing to the Lord, and in this we should expect to be tested. Will we take the Lord seriously or not? He is not deceived and nor should we be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have stored up your word in my heart &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — more than just knowing, this is loving⸺loving to spend time with the Lord in his word. His word in our hearts must be that which fuels our very lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; that I might not sin against you&lt;/em&gt; — our ongoing sanctification, our growing in holiness, is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessed are you, O Lord&lt;/em&gt; — we must meditate on the goodness of God, over and over, dwelling in it, reminding ourselves of his mercy. All his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness! To displace those idols which compete for our affection we must grow such a love for our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches&lt;/em&gt; — our Heavenly Father reveals himself to us through his written word. May we delight to read it, and to read it more, and to surrender our will to it, joyfully, ever growing in relationship with the one who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will meditate on your precepts &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — with a surrendered heart, taking all the time required for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s holy word to permeate our hearts and lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; and fix my eyes on your ways&lt;/em&gt; — every cyclist knows that you end up in the place where you fix your eyes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is required in pursuit of these things and we are not left alone in this. It is the heart-work of the Holy Spirit, his utmost desire for us, but we must not overlook how much discipline is required on our part, as Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that in a race all the runners run, but only one receives the prize? So run that you may obtain it. Every athlete exercises self-control in all things. They do it to receive a perishable wreath, but we an imperishable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 9:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lest we forget what is at stake,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all vigilance, Amy, pursue wisdom in the secret heart, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fully known</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/miguel-bruna-ex1CRGFAftA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fully known" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else does God know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather a lot in fact⸺this is the omniscient Creator God of the universe we are talking about! But in particular, to understand what it means for each one of us to be known by God, let&amp;rsquo;s meditate on Psalm 139.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;O LORD, you have searched me and known me! You know when I sit down and when I rise up; you discern my thoughts from afar. You search out my path and my lying down and are acquainted with all my ways. Even before a word is on my tongue, behold, O LORD, you know it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you formed my inward parts; you knitted me together in my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb. I praise you, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My frame was not hidden from you, when I was being made in secret, intricately woven in the depths of the earth. Your eyes saw my unformed substance; in your book were written, every one of them, the days that were formed for me, when as yet there was none of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 139:1-4, 13-14a, 15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That I am known by my loving Heavenly Father quite so comprehensively and quite so intimately is truly wonderful. For one thing it completely dispels fear. All is fully known. The Lord is acquainted with all my ways. There is nothing hidden that could suddenly be revealed and remove his love for me, or for you. God already knows it all. He knows the very worst and he loves. He already knew and still he chose to love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one thing left to say. Consider the most well known passage on love in the Bible, the passage that is read at weddings and which makes our souls sing: 1 Corinthians 13. Have you noticed Paul&amp;rsquo;s penultimate point there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I have been fully known.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 13:12b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing and loving go together and they grow together. The extent to which we know another limits our love for them. Now I know the Lord only in part, which limits my love for him. Then I shall know fully and so will I love. But right here right now I am fully known by the Lord and fully loved by him. Fully loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, Amy: you are fully known by the Lord, and fully loved! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The eyes of your heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:31:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/javardh-FC59Au36moM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The eyes of your heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the eyes of our heart for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still stuck on this desert island, reading Ephesians 1. It is not a bad place to be! Consider what Paul writes about the eyes of our heart. (The heart is the seat of life and strength, the centre of one&amp;rsquo;s will. That is mind, soul, spirit, one&amp;rsquo;s entire emotional nature and understanding.)  Paul writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I pray also that the eyes of your heart may be enlightened in order that you may know the hope to which he has called you, the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and his incomparably great power for us who believe. That power is like the working of his mighty strength, which he exerted in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a prayer. Paul asks for enlightening of the eyes of our heart. We must ask for this thing that otherwise we may miss. Notice that what the enlightened eyes of our heart do is to &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;. Merely seeing is curiosity. Knowing is life-changing. What is there to know? Three things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope. My dictionary defines hope as grounds for believing that something good may happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not wishful thinking, there are actual grounds for believing this. In our context, “something good” is understated, to say the least! May the enlightened eyes of our heart know the best thing that could possibly happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our glorious inheritance in the saints. What is this? In v3 Paul writes that the Lord “has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ”. Note the tense. Something has already happened! But what of the rest? The prophetic past tense is used throughout scripture where a future event is so certain it is written as if it had already occurred. The fulfilment of our future blessing in the heavenly realms is that certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His incomparably great power for us. This is the same power that raised Christ from the dead. It is not a small thing, and it is at work in us who believe! When we feel overwhelmed or empty, and so aware of our need for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and grace, perhaps his mighty strength which raised Christ from the dead will be enough. We must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the eyes of your heart be enlightened, Amy, in order that you may know, really know, these life changing things. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Desert island</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 06:43:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/pablo-garcia-saldana-K1YRblz-rD0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Desert island" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could take only one chapter of the Bible with you to a desert island, which would you choose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, my pick would be Ephesians Chapter One. I cannot possibly do the whole chapter justice in this short letter, so for now let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one verse. (I may have to return to the wider chapter another time. Perhaps several times!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I keep asking that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the glorious Father, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and revelation, so that you &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you complete that prayer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; may be able to make good choices in your life? &amp;hellip; may be able to discern his will for you? &amp;hellip; may be able to better understand what is happening around you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, none of these! Paul asks this of the Lord so that you “&amp;hellip; may know him better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That you may know the Lord better! This is what the Spirit of wisdom and revelation is for. That I may know him better. To know and be known, this is the ultimate in relationship. But how can we possibly know the infinite, everlasting, majestic God, creator of the ends of the earth, of the universe? It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to know such a one, surely, with our finite minds, with our sinful hearts. And yet, the Spirit of wisdom and revelation makes the impossible, possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we marvel at this, let us notice that this is not a small thing Paul asks for. He &lt;em&gt;keeps asking&lt;/em&gt;, persisting in prayer for the stuff that really matters. Keep asking, Amy, for the stuff that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one he keeps asking is God, the glorious Father. He is glorious, and it is glorious that he is our father. He is the source of all that is good, and he is kind and generous beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the glorious Father, give you the Spirit of wisdom and revelation, Amy, so that you may know him better! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
