<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>transformation on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/transformation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in transformation on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/transformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Ruthless consistency</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/nick-fewings-4x9cfxaiBYQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Ruthless consistency" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else follows from ruthless consistency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already saw that ruthless consistency is the enabler for engaging our whole mind in faith, but there&amp;rsquo;s more to be found along this path, much more. By bringing our intellect into alignment with the eternal truths of the Lord, our mind is renewed, so much so, as if it were previously firing on only a few of the available cylinders. Paul writes about this to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do not conform to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind. Then you will be able to test and approve what God’s will is — his good, pleasing and perfect will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Renewed minds transform our very lives. Otherwise how blindly we may find ourselves following along in the ways of the world: judging others, taking offence, living for self, and being so pleased with ourselves, smug and self-righteous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewing of the mind and the life-transformation that follows is an ongoing process, fuelled by a ruthless consistency in seeking to honour the Lord — that ruthless consistency which compels us to root out and expel every sin, every misplaced thought. To replace love of self with love for the Lord and for one another, and to do this with zeal and great joy. To dwell in love and faithfulness, gentleness and kindness and patience, and to live with humility and absolute integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then? Then we will be able to test and approve what God’s will is. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider for a moment what that means, as it&amp;rsquo;s not immediately apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test here means to be able to recognise as genuine after examination. For example being able to see the Lord&amp;rsquo;s handiwork in situations which might otherwise be difficult to endure. In all things God works for our good, and some of these things are painful indeed, and can be prolonged. With a renewed mind we are able to perceive his grace in these very situations as he works on our hearts, preparing us for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And our approval simply means saying, yes Lord! Accepting, and making a joyful surrender—even in the difficulty and the pain—to the power and grace and healing from the Lord which is making us like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with ruthless consistency, Amy, and be transformed by the renewing of your mind! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Patience in waiting</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/pavlenko-8BNO4HUQYRw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Patience in waiting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we grow in patience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; patience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dictionary defines patience like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/&lt;br&gt;
▸ noun [mass noun]&lt;br&gt;
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Oxford Dictionary of English&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on delay for now. So, how can we grow in patience in the face of delay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m asking an easy question! We grow in this patience by having to wait, and by learning to wait well. But actually waiting well is anything but easy. It is the hardest thing. And it&amp;rsquo;s harder still when we can&amp;rsquo;t understand why. Why the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to consider those who waited before us. Like Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a miraculous escape from being drowned at birth, Moses had a privileged upbringing, growing up in the royal palace of Egypt, learning leadership and what it meant to rule.  As a gifted and highly capable forty year old, he thought he was ready to lead his people out of slavery. The Lord had other plans! Moses spent the next forty years tending sheep in the wilderness. We can wonder how long it took him to come to terms with that! I&amp;rsquo;m sure he spent quite some time raging against the apparent pointlessness of his life. But what was the result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now Moses was a very humble man, more humble than anyone else on the face of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 12:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During those forty years the Lord wrought some fundamental changes in Moses&#39; heart. Where else did that humility come from? In that waiting time, Moses had been completely transformed, and was finally ready to be used by the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting may feel like death, but in fact it can be a path to abundant life, to the mother lode of spiritual blessing and joy. It is a powerful agency of the Lord to change our heart and grow each one of us into someone who can be of some use in the Kingdom. If we can notice this happening in ourselves as it unfolds, that may help us to wait with patience, and to wait well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to wait well, Amy, and grow in patience! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
