<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>transformation on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/transformation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in transformation on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/transformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>From glory to glory</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/joshua-j-cotten-dMn92oICKFY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post From glory to glory" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can those made in the image of God be transformed into his image? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that a bit, well, circular?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we all, with unveiled face, reflecting the glory of the Lord, are being transformed into the same image from one degree of glory to another. For this comes from the Lord who is the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chapter Paul is contrasting the old and new covenants, characterising the old covenant as “the ministry of death” (v7) and “the ministry of condemnation” (v9), oh my! What do we need to know to understand what he writes here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hope in the new covenant is in the ministry of the Spirit and the ministry of righteousness⸺our righteousness in Christ, purchased at such great cost⸺a permanent glory (v8-11). In contrast, when Moses came down from Mount Sinai, while his face initially shone with the reflected glory of the Lord, he covered himself with a veil so that the Israelites would not see how quickly it faded (Exodus 34:29-35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s follow Paul&amp;rsquo;s reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since we have such a hope, we are very bold, not like Moses, who would put a veil over his face so that the Israelites might not gaze at the outcome of what was being brought to an end. But their minds were hardened. For to this day, when they read the old covenant, that same veil remains unlifted, because only through Christ is it taken away. Yes, to this day whenever Moses is read a veil lies over their hearts. But when one turns to the Lord, the veil is removed. Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:12-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who live under the old covenant live with a veil over their hearts to cover the shame of failing to live up to what is required, for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God (Romans 3:23).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why then are we so bold? Because we stand in Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness, not our own. Hallelujah! Our faces are unveiled because there is no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus (Romans 8:1). Only through Christ is the veil taken away. No condemnation. No fear. No shame. Freedom is ours! Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we, the rescued ones, beloved of God, are being transformed from one degree of glory into another. What we were created to be has not yet been seen in our lives. Assuredly we were made in the image of God, but that became so tarnished by sin, by that rebellion against God passed down through the ages from the first man and the first woman. There is, however, such a joyous anticipation in the ongoing process of sanctification, of being made holy, through which we will be made into that which we were always meant to be. And get this: &lt;em&gt;we ourselves are fully a part of that process&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For in his great wisdom, in the mystery of his marvellous ways, the Lord chooses to involve us in that transformation. It comes when we surrender our will to the Holy Spirit, and when we do, how it comes! Look at the lovely way that Paul describes those who are being transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you show that you are a letter from Christ delivered by us, written not with ink but with the Spirit of the living God, not on tablets of stone but on tablets of human hearts.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are a letter from Christ, Amy, written on the tablet of your heart, a witness before the nations to his great love and mercy and grace and his power to transform into his own likeness! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ruthless consistency</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/nick-fewings-4x9cfxaiBYQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Ruthless consistency" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else follows from ruthless consistency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already saw that ruthless consistency is the enabler for engaging our whole mind in faith, but there&amp;rsquo;s more to be found along this path, much more. By bringing our intellect into alignment with the eternal truths of the Lord, our mind is renewed, so much so, as if it were previously firing on only a few of the available cylinders. Paul writes about this to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not conform to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind. Then you will be able to test and approve what God’s will is⸺his good, pleasing and perfect will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewed minds transform our very lives. Otherwise how blindly we may find ourselves following along in the ways of the world: judging others, taking offence, living for self, and being so pleased with ourselves, smug and self-righteous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewing of the mind and the life-transformation that follows is an ongoing process, fuelled by a ruthless consistency in seeking to honour the Lord⸺that ruthless consistency which compels us to root out and expel every sin, every misplaced thought. To replace love of self with love for the Lord and for one another, and to do this with zeal and great joy. To dwell in love and faithfulness, gentleness and kindness and patience, and to live with humility and absolute integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then? Then we will be able to test and approve what God’s will is. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider for a moment what that means, as it&amp;rsquo;s not immediately apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test here means to be able to recognise as genuine after examination. For example being able to see the Lord&amp;rsquo;s handiwork in situations which might otherwise be difficult to endure. In all things God works for our good, and some of these things are painful indeed, and can be prolonged. With a renewed mind we are able to perceive his grace in these very situations as he works on our hearts, preparing us for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And our approval simply means saying, yes Lord! Accepting, and making a joyful surrender⸺even in the difficulty and the pain⸺to the power and grace and healing from the Lord which is making us like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with ruthless consistency, Amy, and be transformed by the renewing of your mind! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Patience in waiting</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/pavlenko-8BNO4HUQYRw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Patience in waiting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we grow in patience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; patience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dictionary defines patience like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/&lt;br&gt;
▸ noun [mass noun]&lt;br&gt;
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Oxford Dictionary of English&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on delay for now. So, how can we grow in patience in the face of delay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m asking an easy question! We grow in this patience by having to wait, and by learning to wait well. But actually waiting well is anything but easy. It is the hardest thing. And it&amp;rsquo;s harder still when we can&amp;rsquo;t understand why. Why the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to consider those who waited before us. Like Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a miraculous escape from being drowned at birth, Moses had a privileged upbringing, growing up in the royal palace of Egypt, learning leadership and what it meant to rule.  As a gifted and highly capable forty year old, he thought he was ready to lead his people out of slavery. The Lord had other plans! Moses spent the next forty years tending sheep in the wilderness. We can wonder how long it took him to come to terms with that! I&amp;rsquo;m sure he spent quite some time raging against the apparent pointlessness of his life. But what was the result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Moses was a very humble man, more humble than anyone else on the face of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 12:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those forty years the Lord wrought some fundamental changes in Moses&amp;rsquo; heart. Where else did that humility come from? In that waiting time, Moses had been completely transformed, and was finally ready to be used by the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting may feel like death, but in fact it can be a path to abundant life, to the mother lode of spiritual blessing and joy. It is a powerful agency of the Lord to change our heart and grow each one of us into someone who can be of some use in the Kingdom. If we can notice this happening in ourselves as it unfolds, that may help us to wait with patience, and to wait well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to wait well, Amy, and grow in patience! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
