<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>regret on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/regret/</link>
        <description>Recent content in regret on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/regret/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Forgiving yourself</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/stephen-leonardi-TvzRUkSlCy4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving yourself" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is even harder than forgiving those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous? Here&amp;rsquo;s what: forgiving ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be said that part of growing up is having to learn to live with the consequences of one&amp;rsquo;s own mistakes, consequences which can be far-reaching indeed. But learning to live with and forgiving are quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistakes and wilful sins are also quite different. But when all the confessing and repenting is done, the endpoint may be the same: agonizing regret over the life that has been lost, what was and is no longer, or what was once hoped for but never came to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us remind ourselves why Jesus came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can those grieving over such a loss experience this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly we must repudiate any suggestion that the rescued life is in any sense second class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who will bring any charge against those whom God has chosen? It is God who justifies. Who then is the one who condemns?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me? Is it me that condemns? Is it me that contradicts the Lord of all creation over his declaration of my righteousness in Christ? What am I thinking? Who am I to think that my own judgment is the one that matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly there is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is what the LORD says &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Forget the former things; do not dwell on the past. See, I am doing a new thing! Now it springs up; do you not perceive it? I am making a way in the desert and streams in the wasteland.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:16, 18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wasteland which is my life, the Lord is doing a new thing, which is springing up, even now. Streams of living water. A way in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longing for what is past is incongruous. The lesson of history is that the Lord does not go back. What is lost is ultimately no loss. It has become a shrivelled, dead thing. There is a new thing springing up which is alive and exciting. Joseph experienced this. Job experienced it, finally — the goodness and kindness and overflowing generosity of the Lord, who does not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, this is how I can forgive myself and let go of the past. I surrender, Lord, not only to your plans and purposes for my life, but to your declaration that I am a new creation in Christ. The old is gone, the new is come, and I stand before you in Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget the former things, Amy, and see the new thing that the Lord is doing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
