<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>surrender on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/surrender/</link>
        <description>Recent content in surrender on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 08:30:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/surrender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>My soul magnifies the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/my-soul-magnifies-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 08:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/my-soul-magnifies-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/my-soul-magnifies-the-lord/benjamin-davies-FiZTaNTj2Ak-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My soul magnifies the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does true worship look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the so-called worship songs we sing in church fall far short, often because there is a bit too much me in them. There are however some that emphatically do not, for example “Worthy is the Lamb” and “Here I Bow” and “He Who is Mighty”. I want to dwell in the latter today, because its bridge in particular is the epitome of true worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now my soul magnifies the Lord&lt;br&gt;
I rejoice in the God Who saves&lt;br&gt;
I will trust His unfailing love&lt;br&gt;
I will sing His praises all my days&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sovereign Grace Music, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HxPvMJB--R4&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;He Who Is Mighty&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically there are three “I”s and two “my”s here, and yet this is in fact completely focused on the Lord. Singing this lifts me directly into his presence in joyous worship, losing myself in praise and awe and wonder⸺this is the real thing! And the heart of it is “my soul magnifies the Lord”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is taken from Mary&amp;rsquo;s song of praise, the Magnificat, her response to her cousin Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s “Blessed is she who has believed that what the Lord has said to her will be accomplished!” after Mary&amp;rsquo;s humble acceptance of and joyful surrender to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s revelation to her (Luke 1:26-56).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just consider what Mary had gone through. The archangel had appeared to her and told her she was going to be the unmarried mother of the Son of God. On a human level, consider the shame she would face⸺indeed, Joseph had in mind to break the marriage pledge quietly (Matthew 1:19). What was Mary&amp;rsquo;s response to the angel? That humble acceptance and joyful surrender:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Mary said, “Behold, I am the servant of the Lord; let it be to me according to your word.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No wonder the angel had said to her, “Do not be afraid, Mary, for you have found favour with God.“ (Luke 1:30).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greek word translated magnify is &lt;em&gt;megalunō&lt;/em&gt;, and is the same word translated shown in the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now the time came for Elizabeth to give birth, and she bore a son. And her neighbours and relatives heard that the Lord had shown great mercy to her, and they rejoiced with her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:57-58&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magnifying here is that of the Lord himself making known his great mercy⸺the character and person of God being revealed and made known⸺and the only right response is one of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does it mean, “my soul magnifies the Lord”?  Simply that all that is within me, the very core of my being, reveals and makes known and honours the character and person of God, and is aligned in love and praise and worship and affirmation that the Lord is great and so worthy of praise. This is what we were created for by our Heavenly Father who knows us and loves us beyond understanding, and it is incomparably joyous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May your soul magnify the Lord, Amy, and may you rejoice in the God who saves! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The master craftsman</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/jonny-gios-KGL7Rw_-YPY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The master craftsman" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be completely confident in surrendering to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we retain some level of control? What might he do in our lives, by the Holy Spirit unleashed with power and authority? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it just all too scary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me ask a different question which may provide some insight. If I invite the Spirit into my situation, into my life, how can I be sure he will do what I am hoping for? What I want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many leave this question unstated, and yet it remains in their subconscious, in the background, undermining confidence in the Lord and trust in him. But it must be articulated, because only then can we repudiate it. Of course he won&amp;rsquo;t do what I want! The very idea is preposterous! He will do his own work, the work that he knows so well, at which he is the master. So the better question to ask is, what is that work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already considered this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To him who is able to keep you from falling and to present you before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy—to the only God our Saviour be glory, majesty, power and authority, through Jesus Christ our Lord, before all ages, now and for evermore! Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work is to keep us from falling and to present us before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy.  It is a heart work, where he transforms us from wretches, having the smallest, meanest, most selfish lives and motives, into sons and daughters, having abundance of life and joy in the Lord, living as slaves to righteousness, with hearts bursting with love for our Saviour and for our brothers and sisters in Christ. And he will do whatever it takes to achieve this purpose, no matter the cost, to him or to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who did not spare his own Son, but gave him up for us all—how will he not also, along with him, graciously give us all things?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not make the mistake as some have done, of thinking this means he will give us whatever we want. By no means! But he will give us whatever &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; wants, in pursuit of his goal for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrender joyfully, Amy, and trust the master craftsman who knows his work, who along with his own Son, will graciously give you all things! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The rescued life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 06:28:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/kyle-cottrell-QGSD-bfJHIw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The rescued life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference does it make to have been rescued?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycling back from Karitane on Sunday afternoon, I saw my neighbours walking up the hill and stopped to say hello. They asked about the awful thing that happened to me in Rarotonga. Word evidently gets around! Instead I told them about the wonderful, impossible thing which happened, which resulted in me being alive and not dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found myself saying, “every day feels like a bonus now.” And so it is. But this principle applies equally to the original rescue, the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saved each one of us from our sin and brought us into relationship with our Heavenly Father in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live as those rescued? We need to understand what has changed, and so experience each waking moment as a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You are not your own; you were bought at a price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 6:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rescue changes everything! Recognizing that we now belong to the one who rescued us and our lives are no longer our own, may we surrender joyfully to the Holy Spirit, live as slaves to righteousness, and know the complete life-transformation that brings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness and self-control. Against such things there is no law. Those who belong to Christ Jesus have crucified the sinful nature with its passions and desires. Since we live by the Spirit, let us keep in step with the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This crucifying of the sinful nature sounds like a one-time thing, but is in fact a lifelong journey. May we travel it with grateful hearts, never forgetting the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in step with the Spirit, Amy, and continue to live as one rescued! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
