<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>judgment on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/judgment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in judgment on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/judgment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Flood</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/flood/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/flood/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/flood/kelly-sikkema-_whs7FPfkwQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Flood" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference can be made by one holy and blameless life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of things just came together: the flooding in your village and the recent floods here in Auckland and the surrounding areas. We have been praying about both, and this got me thinking about The Flood, that is, Noah&amp;rsquo;s flood, the introduction to which is simply terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. How he must have wept over that, heartbrokenly. And in more recent times? As we look around at what is going on in this broken world, perhaps we can gain some small insight into how that must have felt. This was not as he had created it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God saw everything that he had made, and behold, it was very good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something had gone terribly wrong, and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s first instinct in wrath and holiness was to eliminate the evil completely and comprehensively⸺simply terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But Noah found favour in the eyes of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could this be? Simply as we are told.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noah was a righteous man, and this was enough for the Lord to find another way to deal with the evil of humankind. And so what was the consequence of Noah&amp;rsquo;s holy and blameless life? God did indeed wipe out from the earth all of humankind, birds, animals, creeping things, &lt;em&gt;except for Noah and his family and the species-representatives which were saved in the ark&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is the difference that was made by Noah&amp;rsquo;s holy and blameless life. Life on earth was not blotted out, and we ourselves are here today, only because Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think on that for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s staggeringly, outrageously, mind-bogglingly extraordinary, isn&amp;rsquo;t it, the difference that was made by one holy and blameless life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Lord said to Abraham, so he says to each one of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we start to see from Noah&amp;rsquo;s story quite how important this is? Quite how much it matters? The Creator God of the Universe, the Lord of all creation, God Almighty calls us to it, and he is deadly serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the Lord speaking this today, Amy, and never overlook the difference that can be made by one holy and blameless life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>But this I call to mind and therefore I have hope</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 08:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/veit-hammer-YSnZqsF4DLQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post But this I call to mind and therefore I have hope" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ought to occupy our thinking at the beginning of a new year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several possible answers to that question. Here&amp;rsquo;s mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this I call to mind, and therefore I have hope:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The LORD is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD is good to those who wait for him, to the soul who seeks him. It is good that one should wait quietly for the salvation of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These few verses are a shaft of light in the book of Lamentations which otherwise makes for a sobering read. The backdrop is the destruction of Jerusalem after an eighteen month siege by Nebuchadnezzar, and the exile of Judah to Babylon. It was the grimmest of times. The city was plundered and its inhabitants taken into captivity. Women were raped; priests, prophets and officials executed. There was famine so severe that mothers were eating their own children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worst of all, this was the Lord&amp;rsquo;s judgment on his own people, his chosen ones, for their ongoing waywardness and apostasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judah has gone into exile because of affliction
and hard servitude; &amp;hellip; because the LORD has afflicted her for the multitude of her transgressions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerusalem sinned grievously; therefore she became filthy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look and see if there is any sorrow like my sorrow, which was brought upon me, which the LORD inflicted on the day of his fierce anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 1:3, 5, 8, 12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the just and holy judgment of our God whose name is Jealous, a consuming fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should tremble as we read, and then repent and expel every last sin from our own lives and purge every wrong thought and every crooked motive from our own hearts and minds. The Lord takes seriously our sanctification, our holiness, and so must we.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But marvel that it is in the midst of this tribulation that the writer expresses hope in the steadfast love and faithfulness of the Lord. Even in the judgment there is mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the Lord will not cast off forever, but, though he cause grief, he will have compassion according to the abundance of his steadfast love; for he does not afflict from his heart or grieve the children of men.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:31-33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I the LORD do not change; therefore you, O children of Jacob, are not consumed. From the days of your fathers you have turned aside from my statutes and have not kept them. Return to me, and I will return to you, says the LORD of hosts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the Lord never ceases and his mercies never come to an end. Put all your hope in him for this new year, Amy, for great is his faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The breastplate of righteousness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 07:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/Lorica_segmentata.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The breastplate of righteousness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the breastplate of righteousness, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand firm then &amp;hellip; with the breastplate of righteousness in place &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the function of the breastplate is to protect the torso, the heart and lungs, those vital organs without which we cannot live. But what is the nature of this righteousness without which we cannot live before the Lord? It is interesting to see how writers disagree about this, because there are two possible answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the gospel a righteousness from God is revealed, a righteousness that is by faith from first to last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first view is that the breastplate is Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to us, a free gift of grace received entirely through &lt;em&gt;faith&lt;/em&gt;. We can stand firm irrespective of our own wretchedness and sin and failure because of this righteousness from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is profound truth in this. But there is another view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But thanks be to God that, though you used to be slaves to sin, you wholeheartedly obeyed the form of teaching to which you were entrusted. You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:17-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Very truly I tell you, whoever keeps my word will never see death.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:51&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being slaves to righteousness and living in total surrender and complete obedience to God is about our sanctification, and ultimately our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;, as we are transformed into the likeness of Christ and live lives that reflect that. Faith or works? Are these contradictory? Jim Packer has a helpful explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final judgment, as we saw, will be according to our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;⸺that is, our &lt;em&gt;doings&lt;/em&gt;, our whole course of life. The relevance of our &amp;lsquo;doings&amp;rsquo; is not that they ever merit an award from the court⸺they are too far short of perfection to do that⸺but that they provide an index of what is in the heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that one way of acting was meritorious while the other was not, but that from these actions one can tell whether there was love to Christ, the love that springs from faith, in the
heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Knowing God, Chapter 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James takes up this very idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Show me your faith without deeds, and I will show you my faith by my deeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 2:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we can see it clearly. The righteousness is Christ&amp;rsquo;s alone, freely given and received through faith by us who believe, and initiating in us an ongoing transformation into slaves to righteousness. Through this we live ever more radically changed lives, and through this we have assurance of salvation. The merit is all Christ&amp;rsquo;s and so is the glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand firm in the battle, Amy, wholly depending on Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to you, and have assurance of that by the evidence of your own transformed life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
