<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>justice on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/justice/</link>
        <description>Recent content in justice on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Act justly</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/act-justly/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/act-justly/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/act-justly/tony-rojas-lk5MYKmGyFE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Act justly" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s not to like about justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has told you, O man, what is good; and what does the LORD require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/micah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Micah 6:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But justice can be harsh, and justice as enforced by the privileged and powerful sometimes especially so. Perhaps the very worst aspect of justice is some entitled one insisting on asserting their own rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s heart in this justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The opening of the prison to those who are bound could also be translated &lt;em&gt;the opening of the eyes to those who are blind&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a justice which rescues and protects and defends and cares for the most vulnerable. It is a justice overflowing with compassion. Are you beginning to see why “do justice” is a better translation than “act justly”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how it continues. The outcast and the alien are welcomed and invited in and integrated. They receive blessing and protection from the Lord as ministered by his people. And his people in return are richly blessed as these vulnerable ones who are raised up and made whole become themselves the source of blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Strangers shall stand and tend your flocks; foreigners shall be your plowmen and vinedressers; but you shall be called the priests of the LORD; they shall speak of you as the ministers of our God; you shall eat the wealth of the nations, and in their glory you shall boast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s own people shall boast in the glory of these broken and vulnerable ones raised up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why does the Lord set his love upon these who were not his people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; that they may be called oaks of righteousness, the planting of the LORD, that he may be glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such justice born from compassion brings glory to the Lord, that he may display his beauty. May the name of the Lord be praised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I the LORD love justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the justice of which Micah speaks⸺justice as an outworking of compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is the source of the compassion that enables us to do such justice? It is found in the justice that the Lord has done for us⸺the justice that surprises and rescues and will not be thwarted by our own sin and wretchedness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have considered this before. Christ died for our sins, paying the debt in full. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s justice demands that we be forgiven. He will not take a second payment. We cannot keep such compassion to ourselves! It rises up and overflows and stokes the justice that we do⸺the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own justice. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the Lord&amp;rsquo;s justice with compassion, Amy, and bring glory to his name! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Uneven blessing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/atul-pandey-0f3bZHXZSz8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Uneven blessing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that some seem to receive more bounteous blessing from the Lord than others? How is that fair? And how is it congruent with a God of justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with fair, and let&amp;rsquo;s be frank. What would be fair would be for each one of us to be cast into the fiery pit. And collectively, we must take responsibility through our wretched ancestors for much of the suffering of humankind, for we share the same rebellious spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Because you have &amp;hellip; eaten of the tree of which I commanded you, ‘You shall not eat of it,’ cursed is the ground because of you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, and this is a wonderful, unmerited, joyous but,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a rescue! What a Saviour! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with grateful, praising hearts, in fear and trembling, let us dare to ask again, how is it that God&amp;rsquo;s blessing is quite so unevenly distributed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul grappled with such a question in relation to the election of the Gentiles and God&amp;rsquo;s apparent rejection of the nation of Israel (Romans 9-11). That he takes three chapters over this shows us that such questions are no small matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take some of his arguments and apply them to the more general question of uneven blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What shall we say then? Is there injustice on God&amp;rsquo;s part? By no means! For he says to Moses, “I will have mercy on whom I have mercy, and I will have compassion on whom I have compassion.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is all mercy, and it is all undeserved. And let us not forget that the giver is the Creator God of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Has the potter no right over the clay, to make out of the same lump one vessel for honourable use and another for dishonourable use? What if God, desiring to show his wrath and to make known his power, has endured with much patience vessels of wrath prepared for destruction, in order to make known the riches of his glory for vessels of mercy, which he has prepared beforehand for glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow in the unevenness of the blessing, God is making known the riches of his glory. Paul also shows us how to respond in the face of the apparent injustice of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Brothers, my heart&amp;rsquo;s desire and prayer to God for them is that they may be saved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 10:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And observe the extent of his love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have great sorrow and unceasing anguish in my heart. For I could wish that I myself were accursed and cut off from Christ for the sake of my brothers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this then the key to understanding? Even as we cry out to God over the unevenness of the blessing, is this our opportunity to learn how to truly love, and in so doing to glorify God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I was hungry and you gave me food, I was thirsty and you gave me drink, I was a stranger and you welcomed me, I was naked and you clothed me, I was sick and you visited me, I was in prison and you came to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Truly, I say to you, as you did it to one of the least of these my brothers, you did it to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:35-36, 40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the Lord enlarge our hearts for this broken world as we look around and see places where his blessing seems to be absent. And let us cry out to him for mercy, to the Lord, our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you think we have arrived at a place of only partial understanding, let us observe that Paul himself, the great apostle and teacher, is in just that place after three chapters of his own wrestling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, the depth of the riches and wisdom and knowledge of God! How unsearchable are his judgments and how inscrutable his ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 11:33, 36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cry out, Amy, to the one who is wise beyond understanding, and in places of meagre blessing love with his own love, from him and through him and to him, for his glory forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiveness and purification</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 06:44:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiveness-and-purification/nega-YdyhHbWZ1V0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiveness and purification" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a well loved verse from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter, that we may be in danger of reading too quickly and missing the most important word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some important words here. Confess. Sins. And some wonderful, lifting words. Faithful. Forgive. Purify. But what am I referring to? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. &lt;em&gt;Just&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem to be a little out of place, yet it is the crucial word. Consider why. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours, in full. If we confess our sins, and cry out to God for mercy, it is his &lt;em&gt;justice&lt;/em&gt; that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment. Rejoice, that he is faithful &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; just.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
