<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>present on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/present/</link>
        <description>Recent content in present on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/present/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>This is the day that the Lord has made</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/this-is-the-day-that-the-lord-has-made/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/this-is-the-day-that-the-lord-has-made/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/this-is-the-day-that-the-lord-has-made/artem-sapegin-8c6eS43iq1o-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post This is the day that the Lord has made" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What reason is there to rejoice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the fact that Jesus is alive and reigning and ruling over the nations with power and authority and compassion and kindness, we find some more reasons in Psalm 118.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh give thanks to the LORD, for he is good; for his steadfast love endures forever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD is on my side; I will not fear. What can man do to me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD is my strength and my song; he has become my salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD has disciplined me severely, but he has not given me over to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD is God, and he has made his light to shine upon us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:1, 6, 14, 18, 27a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s something in particular I want to focus on. Something that enables us to rejoice even though our earthly future is uncertain in regard to &amp;hellip; so many things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the day that the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only by living in &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; day, really living in it, enjoying the goodness and kindness and steadfast love and faithfulness of the Lord in &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; day, only by this may we really grasp what Jesus meant when he said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only by living in this day, fully living in it, are we able to grasp hold of what it is the Lord is doing in us and through us, for his glory and for the advancement of his Kingdom, and to surrender to it and to become a part of it, and then to rejoice! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. There&amp;rsquo;s a whole other dimension to this day. Let&amp;rsquo;s read that stanza in its entirety⸺remember context!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open to me the gates of righteousness, that I may enter through them and give thanks to the LORD. This is the gate of the LORD; the righteous shall enter through it. I thank you that you have answered me and have become my salvation. The stone that the builders rejected has become the cornerstone. This is the LORD&amp;rsquo;s doing; it is marvelous in our eyes. This is the day that the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:19-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus quoted this (Luke 20:17) and he himself is the cornerstone. So there is another “this day”, and it is the day of salvation. This is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s doing, and it is marvelous in our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the day that the Lord has made, Amy. Rejoice and be glad in it! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Present tense</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/present-tense/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/present-tense/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/present-tense/GSFC_20171208_Archive_e001661_orig.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Present tense" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference is made by the tense of a verb?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading again John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the throne room in heaven. Just as a preliminary, let me note one thing there that always makes me smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At once I was in the Spirit, and behold, a throne stood in heaven, with one seated on the throne.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Creator God of the universe is enthroned, high and exalted, and John is describing what he saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he who sat there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jasper and carnelian? Really? Come on, John, is that all you&amp;rsquo;ve got for us? Is that the best you can do? That tells us nothing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is, from which we may infer just how indescribable is the Lord. Beautiful beyond description. Holy beyond description. Good and wise and kind beyond description. Praise his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and around the throne was a rainbow that had the appearance of an emerald. Around the throne were twenty-four thrones, and seated on the thrones were twenty-four elders, clothed in white garments, with golden crowns on their heads. From the throne came flashes of lightning, and rumblings and peals of thunder, and before the throne were burning seven torches of fire, which are the seven spirits of God, and before the throne there was as it were a sea of glass, like crystal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:3b-6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the inadequacy of the description, doesn&amp;rsquo;t this quicken the pulse and thrill our hearts?⸺the awesome majesty of our great God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s what comes next that caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And around the throne, on each side of the throne, are four living creatures, full of eyes in front and behind: the first living creature like a lion, the second living creature like an ox, the third living creature with the face of a man, and the fourth living creature like an eagle in flight. And the four living creatures, each of them with six wings, are full of eyes all around and within, and day and night they never cease to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Holy, holy, holy, is the Lord God Almighty, who was and is and is to come!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:6b-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you notice that John switched to the present tense? What he describes is happening right now! The worship in heaven is ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join with them, Amy, and worship the holy, holy, holy Lord God Almighty, who was and is and is to come! 🙏🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiving yourself</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-yourself/stephen-leonardi-TvzRUkSlCy4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving yourself" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is even harder than forgiving those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous? Here&amp;rsquo;s what: forgiving ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be said that part of growing up is having to learn to live with the consequences of one&amp;rsquo;s own mistakes, consequences which can be far-reaching indeed. But learning to live with and forgiving are quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistakes and wilful sins are also quite different. But when all the confessing and repenting is done, the endpoint may be the same: agonizing regret over the life that has been lost, what was and is no longer, or what was once hoped for but never came to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us remind ourselves why Jesus came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can those grieving over such a loss experience this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly we must repudiate any suggestion that the rescued life is in any sense second class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who will bring any charge against those whom God has chosen? It is God who justifies. Who then is the one who condemns?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me? Is it me that condemns? Is it me that contradicts the Lord of all creation over his declaration of my righteousness in Christ? What am I thinking? Who am I to think that my own judgment is the one that matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly there is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is what the LORD says &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Forget the former things; do not dwell on the past. See, I am doing a new thing! Now it springs up; do you not perceive it? I am making a way in the desert and streams in the wasteland.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:16, 18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wasteland which is my life, the Lord is doing a new thing, which is springing up, even now. Streams of living water. A way in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longing for what is past is incongruous. The lesson of history is that the Lord does not go back. What is lost is ultimately no loss. It has become a shrivelled, dead thing. There is a new thing springing up which is alive and exciting. Joseph experienced this. Job experienced it, finally⸺the goodness and kindness and overflowing generosity of the Lord, who does not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, this is how I can forgive myself and let go of the past. I surrender, Lord, not only to your plans and purposes for my life, but to your declaration that I am a new creation in Christ. The old is gone, the new is come, and I stand before you in Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget the former things, Amy, and see the new thing that the Lord is doing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
