<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>perseverance on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/perseverance/</link>
        <description>Recent content in perseverance on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/perseverance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Discouragement</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/discouragement/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/discouragement/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/discouragement/from-marwool-X-Z9gHq6iow-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Discouragement" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does discouragement come from and what can we do about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, discouragement can sneak in at any time and begin its insidious work of erosion of faith and joy. Perhaps all we notice is being a little flat, a little down. Why does this happen, and why does it sometimes happen so suddenly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many and varied reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the reasons are obvious: prolonged waiting, for healing, for deliverance, for the fulfillment of a promise; or fatigue, especially post-mission fatigue, when a work has been completed⸺perhaps when a young and enthusiastic team leaves after a significant and high energy visit and all the energy seems to leave with them. And sometimes the reasons are less obvious and there is simply an absence of waypoints upon which to pin hope, or merely a nagging sense that we have dropped off other people&amp;rsquo;s radar and there is no-one to notice whether we are flourishing or fading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, what to do? Paul knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I want you to know how great a struggle I have for you and for those at Laodicea and for all who have not seen me face to face, that their hearts may be encouraged, being knit together in love, to reach all the riches of full assurance of understanding and the knowledge of God&amp;rsquo;s mystery, which is Christ, in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, we all need encouragement from our brothers and sisters in Christ. The journey of faith is not a solitary one. Our hearts are encouraged as we are knit together in love, one with another, but more than this. What could be more encouraging than to be reminded of the treasures of wisdom and knowledge which are in Jesus and which are Jesus? To hear “cheer up” is of such limited comfort. But to hear “Jesus is interceding for you at the right hand of the Father, even now” lifts me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you look ahead to your last few months in the village, Amy, know that the work you have been doing and the work that you will complete before you leave is of eternal significance. Not only is Jesus himself interceding for you, but together with the Father he is so pleased to see you completing your faithful service, persevering even when it is hard and there is no-one to say well done. So pleased with you. And so I say it now: well done, Amy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one last insight for you, for sometimes when we need to hear such words of encouragement there is no-one speaking them to us. What then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider how Paul regarded the Thessalonians, who were so dear to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For what is our hope or joy or crown of boasting before our Lord Jesus at his coming? Is it not you? For you are our glory and joy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 2:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we long for a word of encouragement, and it does not come. So then we must speak it to another, affirm and encourage them in the Lord, and find in that, as Paul did, glory and joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With much love and encouragement to you, Amy, as you continue on in your faithful work for the Lord! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A great cloud of witnesses</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/sandeep-damre-14IPTP-6mTc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A great cloud of witnesses" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently we are surrounded by a great cloud of witnesses, and this is a reason to run the race with perseverance. What&amp;rsquo;s all that about?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important that we understand this, because doesn&amp;rsquo;t it sound just a little bit creepy? Are all these witnesses sitting in heaven watching us, and so had we better not embarrass ourselves for that reason? By no means! (as Paul would say). That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what this is not saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these witnesses are listed in Chapter 11, with this introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now faith is being sure of what we hope for and certain of what we do not see. This is what the ancients were commended for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer then goes on to list the incredible demonstrations of faith by these witnesses, and they are incredible. But what is it that they are witnessing? Is it us? No, it&amp;rsquo;s not us. Here&amp;rsquo;s what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By their faith they are &lt;em&gt;witnesses to the Lord&lt;/em&gt;, to his goodness and kindness and faithfulness. When we live lives of radical faith it points to the one who enables us to do that, to the one for whom we live. And they were commended for it and highly honoured because this is glorious, to live in such a way that our very lives bear testimony to the Lord. This is a powerful witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is why &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; run the race with perseverance. It is a powerful witness. The only ones watching are our contemporaries (oh, and the Lord, obviously — Ps 139, Rev 20:12). But if we run this race well, the Lord may choose to use &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; witness to save some of &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with perseverance, Amy, and join the great cloud of witnesses in testifying to the goodness, kindness and faithfulness of the Lord! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Running with perseverance</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/cameron-venti-I1EWTM5mFEM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Running with perseverance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a long race to run. How will we not grow weary and lose heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews tells us exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us. Let us fix our eyes on Jesus, the author and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy set before him endured the cross, scorning its shame, and sat down at the right hand of the throne of God. Consider him who endured such opposition from sinful men, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? By fixing our eyes on Jesus and considering him. Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack that a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running is hard and I get tired, but by fixing my eyes on Jesus one thing is sure. I will be running towards him, always. He is the author of my story, the author of my faith, the reason that I live and the reason that I live in him. He is also the perfecter (that is completer) of my faith, sustaining me so that I can finish the race. I will not fall because &amp;hellip; Jesus. Because of all that he is and all that he has done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did he do all this? He endured such opposition from sinful men⸺those he had come to save no less! He endured the pain and humiliation of the cross, and the real agony of it all: separation from the Father. But why? Why did he do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are told why he did it and how he endured: &lt;em&gt;for the joy set before him&lt;/em&gt;. And what was that joy? That joy was the knowledge that he was saving you and me, Amy. That was what gave him the strength to endure the unendurable. That was his joy. His love for you and his love for me, and saving you and saving me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that! Consider him! How loved we are! How comprehensive Jesus&amp;rsquo; victory! How wonderful his love!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider him, Amy, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
