<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>disappointment on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/disappointment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in disappointment on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/disappointment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What if?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/what-if/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/what-if/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/what-if/edwin-andrade-5CpS8deLsDY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What if?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does anxiety come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anxiety is so perniciously faith-destroying. If we are not careful we can find ourselves dwelling in imagined futures of dissatisfaction and disappointment, dragged down into doubting the goodness and faithfulness of God, into that awful place of asking in consternation: does he even care about me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this happen and where does it come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this let&amp;rsquo;s consider that question which is so often asked out of uncertainty: “What if?”⸺the question from which anxiety is crystallised. It may start with something specific, but quickly leads to more general fears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if all that I hope for comes to nothing, leaving only disappointment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if my future is only shattered dreams and heartbreak?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if failure and shame prevail over the rest of my life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we vanquish such spiritually disembowelling questions? We must, for Jesus commanded it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are I think three things that we can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly we have to own the question. Let&amp;rsquo;s ask a different “what if?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if Jesus is faithful and true? (Revelation 19:11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if all the Lord&amp;rsquo;s ways are steadfast love and faithfulness? (Psalm 25:10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he always keeps his promises? (Joshua 23:14, Hebrews 10:23, Numbers 23:19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if there&amp;rsquo;s nothing he won&amp;rsquo;t do for his beloved sons and daughters? (Romans 8:32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight? (Ephesians 1:4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he is transforming each one of us into the likeness of Christ? (2 Corinthians 3:18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he will surely see this work through to completion? (Philippians 1:6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? We can own this question in the Lord! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we must notice the context in which Jesus gave that commandment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore I tell you, do not be anxious about your life, what you will eat or what you will drink, nor about your body, what you will put on. Is not life more than food, and the body more than clothing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore! Why therefore? Because Jesus has just been talking about treasure in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our treasure must be in heaven. Oh what protection from anxiety we experience when we keep our treasure in that unassailable place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thirdly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While our treasure may be in heaven, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s blessing is not withheld until then. How he dotes on his sons and daughters, on us, and how he lavishes his love upon us, right here and right now. We must rest in that love, thanking him, acknowledging him as the source of all that his good in our lives, bringing to him all those things that are on our minds, and receiving from him his most blessed and wonderful peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, Amy! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Expectant and not disappointed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/patrick-fore-T2S4CatGdfQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Expectant and not disappointed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be expectant and not disappointed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living with high expectations of oneself and others is surely right, but can lead to ongoing disappointment, as we and those around us fall short of what we aspired to do and to be. How can the same not be true of the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should we expect of the Lord anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 27:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is anyone among you sick? &amp;hellip; the prayer offered in faith will make the sick person well; the Lord will raise them up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 5:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 91:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You know with all your heart and soul that not one of all the good promises the LORD your God gave you has failed. Every promise has been fulfilled; not one has failed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am the LORD, the God of all mankind. Is anything too hard for me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 32:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are we not just setting ourselves up for disappointment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However we deal with this, we must never lower our expectation of the Lord. He is the Creator, Almighty, Sovereign Lord, infinite in power and wisdom. He loves us his children absolutely, and he blesses us richly and without bounds. May we never doubt that!  And may we never limit our praying to what seems reasonable. If someone is sick, shame on me if I pray merely for their comfort rather than for miraculous healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To live with such expectation makes me so vulnerable, though. Vulnerable to disappointment. Vulnerable to the scorn of the sceptics. Vulnerable and defenceless. How can my faith survive this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that Abraham was strengthened in his faith (Rom 4:20). It is a work of the Lord. I commit completely, in faith, trusting. The Lord defends me.  It is miraculous grace.  The heartache may remain as I wait, in that amalgam of joy and pain which characterises the Christian life as we engage with the Lord&amp;rsquo;s work in this broken world. But disappointment does not crush me, does not crush my faith. How does this work? It is a mystery, a wondrous gift of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my, I seem to have written another tome. Good job I do this only once a week, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lean on him, trust him for his impossible promises, and praise him for his miraculous grace, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Experiencing grace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 06:32:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/denise-jans-IJy2ZUex0-Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Experiencing grace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we better perceive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s grace in all we experience, and what would that mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is full of frustrations and disappointments. Even for the Christian seeking the Lord with all of our heart, living a surrendered life, putting him first in everything, things may not turn out as we would have wished. And that&amp;rsquo;s not just small things. The whole course of one&amp;rsquo;s life could turn out to be so different from what was desired. Where is our loving Heavenly Father in this? Does he not want to bless his children? Absolutely he does! So what is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote to the Romans this oft-quoted verse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that in all things God works for the good of those who love him, who have been called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider that in the context of Solomon&amp;rsquo;s wisdom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In his heart a man plans his course, but the LORD determines his steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 16:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has hopes and desires for their own life. Some may be sufficiently well organised to have a plan! But the Lord determines their steps. It is his plans and purposes that prevail. Let us not delude ourselves that we can control our own destiny, and somehow plan our way there. That is for the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to dispel a misconception. Paul is not saying that everything that happens is good and is caused by God. That is observably false⸺terrible things do happen. Rather he is saying that whatever happens, God works in it and through it “for the good of those who love him”. Let us be those!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us learn to see the world through the lens of Romans 8:28 as it actually is then. May we consciously receive God&amp;rsquo;s grace in all that happens. “In all things” let us submit to his superior wisdom, knowing that there is no better eternal outcome than the one he has for us. When apparent disappointments come, let us receive them with a grateful heart. The Lord has seen things that we have not. His love is unfailing. He may very well be rescuing us from something we thought was better, but is in fact not.  He is the one who determines our steps, and it is very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive his grace with a grateful heart in all things, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
