<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>faithfulness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/faithfulness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in faithfulness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 06:24:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/faithfulness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A labour of love for the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/loren-joseph-11eY-tkB9VU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A labour of love for the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you return to the village for another year of serving the Lord, know that he sees all that you do and all that you are with such approval, smiling down on you like the proud father that he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul evidently had a particular fondness for and bond with the Thessalonians. You can see it in his writing, in the phrases he uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, then, brothers and sisters, we ask and urge you in the Lord Jesus, that as you received from us how you ought to walk and to please God, just as you are doing, that you do so more and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 4:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He urges them to continue to live their lives in a way which pleases God, &lt;em&gt;just as they were doing&lt;/em&gt;. Just as &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are doing, Amy, and to do this more and more. And what do we know of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to God always for all of you, constantly mentioning you in our prayers, remembering before our God and Father your work of faith and labour of love and steadfastness of hope in our Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; for you received the word in much affliction, with the joy of the Holy Spirit, so that you became an example to all the believers in Macedonia and in Achaia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 1:2-3, 6b-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul had noticed their work of faith and labour of love and steadfastness of hope in Jesus, and so had the Lord, and it pleased him. And neither of them had failed to notice the affliction they endured, quite how hard it was for them to live like this, and that they did it with the joy of the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has surely not failed to notice how hard it has been for you, Amy, and how you have lived with the joy of the Holy Spirit, honouring him, an example to all the believers in Dunedin City Baptist Church and beyond. Well done indeed! We give thanks to God for you, constantly remembering you in &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look up and see with the eyes of your heart our loving Heavenly Father taking so much joy and delight in you, Amy, gently nudging Jesus in the ribs and saying, “Look at our daughter, how she lives!” 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>But this I call to mind and therefore I have hope</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 08:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/veit-hammer-YSnZqsF4DLQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post But this I call to mind and therefore I have hope" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ought to occupy our thinking at the beginning of a new year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several possible answers to that question. Here&amp;rsquo;s mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this I call to mind, and therefore I have hope:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The LORD is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD is good to those who wait for him, to the soul who seeks him. It is good that one should wait quietly for the salvation of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These few verses are a shaft of light in the book of Lamentations which otherwise makes for a sobering read. The backdrop is the destruction of Jerusalem after an eighteen month siege by Nebuchadnezzar, and the exile of Judah to Babylon. It was the grimmest of times. The city was plundered and its inhabitants taken into captivity. Women were raped; priests, prophets and officials executed. There was famine so severe that mothers were eating their own children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worst of all, this was the Lord&amp;rsquo;s judgment on his own people, his chosen ones, for their ongoing waywardness and apostasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judah has gone into exile because of affliction
and hard servitude; &amp;hellip; because the LORD has afflicted her for the multitude of her transgressions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerusalem sinned grievously; therefore she became filthy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look and see if there is any sorrow like my sorrow, which was brought upon me, which the LORD inflicted on the day of his fierce anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 1:3, 5, 8, 12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the just and holy judgment of our God whose name is Jealous, a consuming fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should tremble as we read, and then repent and expel every last sin from our own lives and purge every wrong thought and every crooked motive from our own hearts and minds. The Lord takes seriously our sanctification, our holiness, and so must we.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But marvel that it is in the midst of this tribulation that the writer expresses hope in the steadfast love and faithfulness of the Lord. Even in the judgment there is mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the Lord will not cast off forever, but, though he cause grief, he will have compassion according to the abundance of his steadfast love; for he does not afflict from his heart or grieve the children of men.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:31-33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I the LORD do not change; therefore you, O children of Jacob, are not consumed. From the days of your fathers you have turned aside from my statutes and have not kept them. Return to me, and I will return to you, says the LORD of hosts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the Lord never ceases and his mercies never come to an end. Put all your hope in him for this new year, Amy, for great is his faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The shield of faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/Cap-s_Shield.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shield of faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have so many Christians thrown away the shield of faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In addition to all this, take up the shield of faith, with which you can extinguish all the flaming arrows of the evil one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, understand the nature of these flaming arrows. They are lies. Lies about us and lies about the Lord and what he has done. Jesus says of the devil,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“When he lies, he speaks his native language, for he is a liar and the father of lies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:44b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lies can be insidious. They must be stamped out before they take hold, like flames licking around. What do these lies do? They create doubt. And how do we combat doubt? By exercising and building faith! But how do we do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is faith anyway? Those who think it is an intellectual acceptance of some revealed truth are so far away from real understanding. Faith is a &lt;em&gt;life lived&lt;/em&gt; upon the foundation of this truth from the Lord, upon Christ himself, fully committed, trusting and even depending on him to keep his promises. (And he will.) So, how to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is again the key. I have to ask myself with brutal honesty, does my life reflect that I will one day stand before the Lord and give an account? Does my life reflect that I have understood Jesus teaching and am living by it in full obedience to him, joyously surrendered? Many seem not to understand this and then wonder why their faith is so small and why doubt is creeping in. Half-hearted belief is no belief at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider even this one thing that Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But many who are first will be last, and many who are last will be first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context of this is the rich young ruler, earnestly seeking but tragically unable to give up this life&amp;rsquo;s riches and pleasures for the Kingdom, just like so many today. Why is it that even within the church so many are trying to be first? Do we really not believe Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may need some help with this. So let us ask our heavenly Father, who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open my eyes that I may see wonderful things in your law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May this be our most earnest prayer as we learn to wield the shield of faith and extinguish those flaming arrows. And let us observe the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in our lives as we live this life of faith, recognising that his faithfulness is in fact the ultimate faith builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take up your shield of faith, Amy, and know that he who promised is faithful! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Self-control</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/peter-herrmann-9_FK2Tp-kLA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Self-control" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we travel in time, and how could that help our self-control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; self-control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact it&amp;rsquo;s easy to travel in time, in our imagination. There are two vital destinations that can help us grow in self-control, especially in the face of temptation. But first, take note of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God is faithful; he will not let you be tempted beyond what you can bear. But when you are tempted, he will also provide a way out so that you can stand up under it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should expect to be tempted. How else will we grow in self-control other than by exercising it? So we should expect also to have to work at this. It won&amp;rsquo;t be easy, obviously, since nothing worthwhile was ever gained like that. Just let us never overlook God&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in enabling us to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first destination in time is just a few minutes into the future. Let us imagine looking back, observing our own behaviour through the lens of hindsight. Do we see someone behaving honourably? Someone displaying strength of character? Someone we are pleased to be? May the Lord&amp;rsquo;s sustaining grace enable us to be that! We must be mindful that our character is defined by the accumulation of every choice that we make, no matter how small or apparently insignificant. The new viewpoint helps enormously with this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second destination is a little further, at the end of our lives. Let us imagine being welcomed into heaven by our Lord. What is it that I want to hear on that day? I will live my life to hear him say this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Well done, good and faithful servant!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do some time-travelling in your mind, Amy, and live your life to hear him say, “Well done, my good and faithful servant!” 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faithfulness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/sean-benesh-VnmbcgAfL3Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faithfulness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fuels faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; faithfulness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness is such an honourable character trait, perhaps the noblest of them all. To be loyal, steadfast, trustworthy and true⸺surely these words make our hearts soar. They speak to the very heart of noble character, of character that honours the Lord. So where does faithfulness come from? There are two answers to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness, evident throughout Scripture, from where he first introduces himself to Moses, right up to John&amp;rsquo;s vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, the rider on the white horse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [the LORD] passed in front of Moses, proclaiming, “The LORD, the LORD, the compassionate and gracious God, slow to anger, abounding in love and faithfulness, maintaining love to thousands, and forgiving wickedness, rebellion and sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the ways of the LORD are loving and faithful for those who keep the demands of his covenant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the word of the LORD is right and true; he is faithful in all he does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 33:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your love, O LORD, reaches to the heavens, your faithfulness to the skies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 36:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet this I call to mind and therefore I have hope: Because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great love we are not consumed, for his compassions never fail. They are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who calls you is faithful and he will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I saw heaven standing open and there before me was a white horse, whose rider is called Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness to us makes our hearts burn with fire, fuelling our own faithfulness, our noblest thoughts and deeds, through and for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, consider the word itself, &lt;em&gt;pistis&lt;/em&gt; in the original Greek. Mostly that word is not in fact translated as faithfulness, but rather faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pistis — persuasion that is credence; moral conviction (of religious truth or the truthfulness of God or a religious teacher) especially reliance upon Christ for salvation; abstractly constancy in such profession; by extension the system of religious (Gospel) truth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Strong&amp;#39;s Greek Lexicon&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness then is fueled by being full of faith. Genuine, all-in, life-changing faith in the one who is faithful to all he has said, and indeed all he is, gives us the power to live lives that are worthy of our calling, manifesting in the noblest of hearts, and lasting faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him Amy, whose name is Faithful and True, be full of faith, and let that fuel your own faithfulness, to him and for him, forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
