<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>faithfulness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/faithfulness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in faithfulness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/faithfulness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What now?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/what-now/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 08:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/what-now/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/what-now/nathan-trampe-oOmwruKXv5U-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What now?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After three years your time in the village has finally come to an end! You have served the Lord so faithfully, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not wrong in saying that you have put a smile on the face of your Heavenly Father (Psalm 147:11). Well done! Well done indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some may see your return to New Zealand as a home-coming, perhaps for you it seems to be the opposite, as you are leaving the village and the friends who have been home to you for these three long years, with whom you have journeyed sharing joys and sorrows, trials and triumphs. And as you return you&amp;rsquo;ll surely feel like a stranger in a strange land, for isn&amp;rsquo;t that what New Zealand has become?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly how it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider how the writer to the Hebrews describes the faith of Abel and Enoch and Noah and Abraham and Sarah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These all died in faith, not having received the things promised, but having seen them and greeted them from afar, and having acknowledged that they were strangers and exiles on the earth. For people who speak thus make it clear that they are seeking a homeland. If they had been thinking of that land from which they had gone out, they would have had opportunity to return. But as it is, they desire a better country, that is, a heavenly one. Therefore God is not ashamed to be called their God, for he has prepared for them a city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:13-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People living in western affluence can become so self-satisfied and complacent, distracted by comfort and privilege. Expect to find this thoroughly jarring on your return. But know that this is not your home. It is not my home. It is not any of ours. We long for a better country, a heavenly one. And in this longing of ours, astonishingly, God is not ashamed to be called our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be my last letter to you, Amy. It has been such a privilege to be able to offer you these small encouragements from afar, and I have certainly encouraged my own heart as I have sought the Lord over what to offer to you. I have one last offering for you now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my question. How can I live a life of humility and contentment, honouring the Lord in the midst of all this self-satisfaction and complacency and privilege, when all around me people with agendas are chasing after the limelight and my own life seems rather small and disregarded?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David has the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vindicate me, O LORD, for I have walked in my integrity, and I have trusted in the LORD without wavering. Prove me, O LORD, and try me; test my heart and my mind. For your steadfast love is before my eyes, and I walk in your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 26:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I am called to live, and it is joyous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; love is before my eyes because I think about it all the time. In fact it is the lens through which I see the world. It rescues me and enables me even to live my life. And the overflow of that love spills into every relationship and every conversation. It is life-changing love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise him for his wonderful &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; love and faithfulness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk in your integrity, Amy, and in his faithfulness! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What if?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/what-if/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/what-if/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/what-if/edwin-andrade-5CpS8deLsDY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What if?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does anxiety come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anxiety is so perniciously faith-destroying. If we are not careful we can find ourselves dwelling in imagined futures of dissatisfaction and disappointment, dragged down into doubting the goodness and faithfulness of God, into that awful place of asking in consternation: does he even care about me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this happen and where does it come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this let&amp;rsquo;s consider that question which is so often asked out of uncertainty: “What if?”⸺the question from which anxiety is crystallised. It may start with something specific, but quickly leads to more general fears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if all that I hope for comes to nothing, leaving only disappointment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if my future is only shattered dreams and heartbreak?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if failure and shame prevail over the rest of my life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we vanquish such spiritually disembowelling questions? We must, for Jesus commanded it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are I think three things that we can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly we have to own the question. Let&amp;rsquo;s ask a different “what if?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if Jesus is faithful and true? (Revelation 19:11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if all the Lord&amp;rsquo;s ways are steadfast love and faithfulness? (Psalm 25:10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he always keeps his promises? (Joshua 23:14, Hebrews 10:23, Numbers 23:19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if there&amp;rsquo;s nothing he won&amp;rsquo;t do for his beloved sons and daughters? (Romans 8:32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight? (Ephesians 1:4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he is transforming each one of us into the likeness of Christ? (2 Corinthians 3:18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if he will surely see this work through to completion? (Philippians 1:6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? We can own this question in the Lord! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we must notice the context in which Jesus gave that commandment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore I tell you, do not be anxious about your life, what you will eat or what you will drink, nor about your body, what you will put on. Is not life more than food, and the body more than clothing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore! Why therefore? Because Jesus has just been talking about treasure in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our treasure must be in heaven. Oh what protection from anxiety we experience when we keep our treasure in that unassailable place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thirdly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While our treasure may be in heaven, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s blessing is not withheld until then. How he dotes on his sons and daughters, on us, and how he lavishes his love upon us, right here and right now. We must rest in that love, thanking him, acknowledging him as the source of all that his good in our lives, bringing to him all those things that are on our minds, and receiving from him his most blessed and wonderful peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, Amy! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Soaring on wings like an eagle</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/soaring-on-wings-like-an-eagle/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/soaring-on-wings-like-an-eagle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/soaring-on-wings-like-an-eagle/marcus-woodbridge-0s81Kf6lWzY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Soaring on wings like an eagle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often do you soar like an eagle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But they who wait for the LORD shall renew their strength; they shall mount up with wings like eagles; they shall run and not be weary; they shall walk and not faint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you journey through each day faithfully serving the Lord, is this your experience? My utmost desire for you is that it is! But as I observe those around me here also faithfully serving the Lord, I don&amp;rsquo;t see much soaring. Instead I see the opposite⸺weariness and exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that? Why is it so hard to experience this? And why was it also not the experience of those to whom these words were originally spoken? For it was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two reasons. For the first we must consider these words in their original context. They are such familiar words but perhaps the context gets overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These words were spoken to the Israelites in their exile in Babylon⸺that exile which was the judgment of a holy God upon an unholy people, a people chosen by the Lord but characterised by stubbornly ongoing waywardness and apostasy. It was a just and righteous judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these words were delivered with a sharp rebuke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why do you say, O Jacob, and speak, O Israel, “My way is hidden from the LORD, and my right is disregarded by my God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the first reason for absence of soaring: believing that the Lord is ignorant of or indifferent to one&amp;rsquo;s situation. That is, thinking he either does not know or does not care. We could observe that perhaps the Israelites in their Babylonian exile more than anyone else were justified in thinking this. But no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the rebuke:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have you not known? Have you not heard? The LORD is the everlasting God, the Creator of the ends of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not one who is ignorant of anything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of that insidious presumption of indifference? For this there&amp;rsquo;s another rebuke. Isaiah has another rebuke for anyone who even flirts with the idea that the Lord is indifferent to their cause. It is a rebuke bound up in his prophecy of the Messiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Out of the anguish of his soul he shall see and be satisfied; by his knowledge shall the righteous one, my servant, make many to be accounted righteous, and he shall bear their iniquities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 53:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contemplate the anguish of his soul that Jesus would endure, out of which he would make many to be accounted righteous, bearing their iniquities. He was and is so invested in his rescued ones! We can be sure of that because of the enormous price that he would pay, the cost that he would bear. How could anyone possibly behold that and surmise indifference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only the first of the two reasons that prevent one soaring like an eagle. It must be thoroughly repudiated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:31-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father both knows each one of us intimately and cares so tenderly and he will not hold back rescue and blessing beyond imagining. This is the first and foremost enabler for soaring, that we rest confidently in that glorious truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest confidently in the unfailing love and faithfulness and boundless generosity and kindness of our most wonderful God, Amy, so you may be ready to soar on wings like an eagle! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Love mercy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/love-mercy/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/love-mercy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/love-mercy/jon-tyson-nI8YlkExQoI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Love mercy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why love mercy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has told you, O man, what is good; and what does the LORD require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/micah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Micah 6:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the ESV does have slightly unfamiliar wording here. All my Christian life I have known it as act justly, love mercy, and walk humbly. But the unfamiliar prompted me to look further into what this word mercy actually means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And why love and not show? Why not “show mercy”? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that go better with those other doing words, act justly and walk humbly? Isn&amp;rsquo;t this purely about our behaviour? Not remotely! It is so much richer and deeper than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word translated mercy or kindness is &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt;. Over the last couple of weeks or so I have been on a journey into &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt;, mainly thanks to Jim McClure. It has been rich and deep. As we come to understand &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; we come to understand something of the heart of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hebrew &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; has been translated by a variety of words including mercy, kindness, goodness, favour, pity and loving-kindness. Sometimes it has been translated as faithfulness, grace, leal-love, steadfast love and troth. The fact that so many words have been employed to translate &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; reveals that it is extremely difficult to find an equivalent English word and every attempt is ultimately inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; is love that is covenantal and it is about relationship. God&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; is wonderful, ever present, always surrounding, universal, superlative, quick to pardon, immense in its essence, immense in its duration, immense in its quantity, and, remarkably, can be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Adapted from Jim McClure, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://connectingwithyou.net/2016/12/12/words-of-life-5-loyal-love-chesed/&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Words of Life #5, Loyal Love — Chêsêd&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where else does this word appear? Everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I the LORD your God am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children to the third and the fourth generation of those who hate me, but showing &lt;em&gt;steadfast love&lt;/em&gt; to the thousandth generation of those who love me and keep my commandments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 20:5b-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the paths of the LORD are &lt;em&gt;steadfast love&lt;/em&gt; and faithfulness, for those who keep his covenant and his testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But this I call to mind, and therefore I have hope: The &lt;em&gt;steadfast love&lt;/em&gt; of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By loving &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; we are loving an essential and fundamental attribute of God&amp;rsquo;s character, and ultimately we are loving God himself. By immersing ourselves in this mercy and kindness, joyously and with grateful hearts, we fall more deeply in love with our Lord and Saviour, and that changes us. How we need this mercy! The overwhelmingly good news is that it flows freely⸺as and because Jesus&amp;rsquo; blood flowed freely on the cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as we receive this it becomes a part of us and starts to define our own character, such that we become people of mercy, &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; people. Jesus talked about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the merciful, for they shall receive mercy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, let&amp;rsquo;s observe what it looks like to love mercy, to live for it and because of it. Can you hear the longing here, such deep longing, for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let your &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; come to me, O LORD, your salvation according to your promise; then shall I have an answer for him who taunts me, for I trust in your word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:41-42&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when we live with such deep longing for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt;? The answer is, we put a smile on the face of our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD takes pleasure in those who fear him, in those who hope in his &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love mercy, Amy, and put a smile on the face of your Heavenly Father! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>O Lord, remember!</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/o-lord-remember/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/o-lord-remember/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/o-lord-remember/jayden-yoon-zk-OGWTZqz3wiI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post O Lord, remember!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does God forget, such that he needs to be reminded? A strange question to be sure, but what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember your word to your servant, in which you have made me hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:49&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such prayers appear throughout the Bible. Over and over we observe the Lord&amp;rsquo;s most faithful servants crying out to him, O Lord, remember! Must he be reminded of things he has overlooked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw something similar when the Israelites were crying out for rescue from slavery in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During those many days the king of Egypt died, and the people of Israel groaned because of their slavery and cried out for help. Their cry for rescue from slavery came up to God. And God heard their groaning, and God remembered his covenant with Abraham, with Isaac, and with Jacob. God saw the people of Israel⸺and God knew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 2:23-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we imagine a heavenly face palm here, as God suddenly realises what he has overlooked? Of course not! How utterly ridiculous! What is this remembering then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gain understanding by looking at what came next. What came next is that God spoke to Moses out of the burning bush, unleashed ten plagues upon the Pharaoh who imagined he himself held all the power, delivered his people from slavery, and led them, eventually, into the promised land, fulfilling the covenant that he had made with Abraham so many years previously. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s remembering, then, is about him acting with great power on behalf of his beloved ones to fulfil his promises to them. Nothing is ever forgotten and nothing is ever overlooked. All his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with this understanding we can return to our verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember your word to your servant, in which you have made me hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:49&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the heart-cry of one holding a promise from the Lord⸺an incredible, joyous, life-giving promise. It is a cry to the Faithful One for him to deliver on this as yet unfulfilled promise. It is a cry of faith, believing not doubting. It is a cry of longing and of waiting and of pain in the waiting. It is a cry for the Lord to act with great power, and that the time to act is now, please Lord may it be so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is more. This is the promise &lt;em&gt;in which you have made me hope&lt;/em&gt;. The psalmist&amp;rsquo;s faith journey of receiving the promise, hoping in it and resting on it, is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s work. It is a work of grace, and it is a gift of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O Lord, remember!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very next verse reveals the psalmist&amp;rsquo;s heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is my comfort in my affliction, that your promise gives me life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:50&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The promise is not yet realised. The fulfilment is to come and yet the comfort in the promise is now. It is present tense comfort which comes from resting confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love and faithfulness. The promise is life-giving ahead of time, and the cry is, O Lord, remember!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cry out, Amy, to the Faithful One: O Lord, remember! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dwelling in the land</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/dwelling-in-the-land/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/dwelling-in-the-land/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/dwelling-in-the-land/leonard-cotte-c1Jp-fo53U8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dwelling in the land" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever marvel at how the Bible is quite so dense with blessing and encouragement, and that even the most familiar passages can suddenly reveal to us new insight and bestow upon us new grace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example, just half a verse, a mere seven words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dwell in the land and befriend faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the face of it this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be saying very much at all. What does “dwell in the land” even mean? Is it simply saying, live your life? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand this we must understand the Old Testament significance of the land from the very beginning, from the call of Abraham, even before God gave him his new name which means “father of a multitude”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the LORD said to Abram, “Go from your country and your kindred and your father&amp;rsquo;s house to the land that I will show you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To your offspring I will give this land.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 12:1, 7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Be mindful that this promise was spoken to a childless 75 year old man who was married to a barren woman.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More was revealed when God spoke to Moses out of the burning bush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, and I have come down to deliver them out of the hand of the Egyptians and to bring them up out of that land to a good and broad land, a land flowing with milk and honey, to the place of the Canaanites, the Hittites, the Amorites, the Perizzites, the Hivites, and the Jebusites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was “the land” and it was hugely symbolic of the covenant promise of the Lord to Abraham and to his chosen people, the Israelites. To dwell in the land then is to live in the promises of God⸺the promises of the most faithful God to his woefully unfaithful people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And “befriend faithfulness”? The Lord himself is faithfulness personified. We befriend faithfulness by honouring him with our own faithfulness, trusting not doubting his promises to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these promises? Some are common to us all⸺Scripture is full of them! One of the most astonishing is in the very next verse, and we already considered this extravagant promise, seemingly too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD, and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek the Lord with all of your heart, desiring him alone, and he will give himself to you in the richest of relationship. This extraordinary promise is that we can have as much of the Lord in our lives as we desire. Praise his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some promises are uniquely given. Promises that I have received are for me, and different from yours, Amy. We honour him alike by resting in these promises, living in them expectantly, believing not doubting, just as David goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is not uninvolved as we live in his promises. Trust in him and he will act, whatever has been promised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dwell in the land, Amy, and befriend faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The provision of God</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-provision-of-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-provision-of-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-provision-of-god/dan-dennis-GM6CJ2h8GHE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The provision of God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of provision can we expect to receive from the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an interesting passage in Philippians 4:10-20 which addresses this, with the most interesting part in my mind being the reciprocity. But even before we get to provision we have to consider contentment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; for I have learned in whatever situation I am to be content. I know how to be brought low, and I know how to abound. In any and every circumstance, I have learned the secret of facing plenty and hunger, abundance and need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:11b-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul faced so much hardship in his ministry⸺see 2 Corinthians 11:24-28 for the details, it&amp;rsquo;s quite a list! In the midst of this, notice two things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, Paul had learned to be content whatever the situation through his joy and trust in the Lord. This contentment freed him from the tyranny of circumstance. He was secure in the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly, he was so aware of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s strength, and the sufficiency of that strength for all he was facing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I can do all things through him who strengthens me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was a faithful servant of the Lord pouring himself out, and because of this receiving the Lord&amp;rsquo;s provision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more, and here&amp;rsquo;s where we gain some insight into the provision of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you Philippians yourselves know that in the beginning of the gospel, when I left Macedonia, no church entered into partnership with me in giving and receiving, except you only. Even in Thessalonica you sent me help for my needs once and again. Not that I seek the gift, but I seek the fruit that increases to your credit. I have received full payment, and more. I am well supplied, having received from Epaphroditus the gifts you sent, a fragrant offering, a sacrifice acceptable and pleasing to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Philippians were supporting Paul in his ministry⸺the Lord&amp;rsquo;s provision for Paul⸺not out of what they could spare, but out of what they could not (“a sacrifice acceptable and pleasing to God”). Notice that this was fruit that increased to their credit, and that this left them in need themselves, which is precisely why Paul continued:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord provides in response to the needs of his most faithful servants, those who pour themselves out for his Kingdom, and his provision is always enough. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do all things, Amy, through him who strengthens you, and my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A labour of love for the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/loren-joseph-11eY-tkB9VU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A labour of love for the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you return to the village for another year of serving the Lord, know that he sees all that you do and all that you are with such approval, smiling down on you like the proud father that he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul evidently had a particular fondness for and bond with the Thessalonians. You can see it in his writing, in the phrases he uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, then, brothers and sisters, we ask and urge you in the Lord Jesus, that as you received from us how you ought to walk and to please God, just as you are doing, that you do so more and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 4:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He urges them to continue to live their lives in a way which pleases God, &lt;em&gt;just as they were doing&lt;/em&gt;. Just as &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are doing, Amy, and to do this more and more. And what do we know of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to God always for all of you, constantly mentioning you in our prayers, remembering before our God and Father your work of faith and labour of love and steadfastness of hope in our Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; for you received the word in much affliction, with the joy of the Holy Spirit, so that you became an example to all the believers in Macedonia and in Achaia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 1:2-3, 6b-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul had noticed their work of faith and labour of love and steadfastness of hope in Jesus, and so had the Lord, and it pleased him. And neither of them had failed to notice the affliction they endured, quite how hard it was for them to live like this, and that they did it with the joy of the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has surely not failed to notice how hard it has been for you, Amy, in your own work of faith and labour of love and steadfastness of hope in Jesus, and how you have lived with the joy of the Holy Spirit, honouring him, an example to all the believers in Dunedin City Baptist Church and beyond. Well done indeed! We give thanks to God for you, constantly remembering you in &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look up and see with the eyes of your heart our loving Heavenly Father taking so much joy and delight in you, Amy, gently nudging Jesus in the ribs and saying, “Look at our daughter, how she lives!” 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>But this I call to mind and therefore I have hope</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 08:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/veit-hammer-YSnZqsF4DLQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post But this I call to mind and therefore I have hope" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ought to occupy our thinking at the beginning of a new year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several possible answers to that question. Here&amp;rsquo;s mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this I call to mind, and therefore I have hope:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The LORD is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD is good to those who wait for him, to the soul who seeks him. It is good that one should wait quietly for the salvation of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These few verses are a shaft of light in the book of Lamentations which otherwise makes for a sobering read. The backdrop is the destruction of Jerusalem after an eighteen month siege by Nebuchadnezzar, and the exile of Judah to Babylon. It was the grimmest of times. The city was plundered and its inhabitants taken into captivity. Women were raped; priests, prophets and officials executed. There was famine so severe that mothers were eating their own children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worst of all, this was the Lord&amp;rsquo;s judgment on his own people, his chosen ones, for their ongoing waywardness and apostasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judah has gone into exile because of affliction
and hard servitude; &amp;hellip; because the LORD has afflicted her for the multitude of her transgressions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerusalem sinned grievously; therefore she became filthy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look and see if there is any sorrow like my sorrow, which was brought upon me, which the LORD inflicted on the day of his fierce anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 1:3, 5, 8, 12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the just and holy judgment of our God whose name is Jealous, a consuming fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should tremble as we read, and then repent and expel every last sin from our own lives and purge every wrong thought and every crooked motive from our own hearts and minds. The Lord takes seriously our sanctification, our holiness, and so must we.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But marvel that it is in the midst of this tribulation that the writer expresses hope in the steadfast love and faithfulness of the Lord. Even in the judgment there is mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the Lord will not cast off forever, but, though he cause grief, he will have compassion according to the abundance of his steadfast love; for he does not afflict from his heart or grieve the children of men.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:31-33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I the LORD do not change; therefore you, O children of Jacob, are not consumed. From the days of your fathers you have turned aside from my statutes and have not kept them. Return to me, and I will return to you, says the LORD of hosts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/malachi&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the Lord never ceases and his mercies never come to an end. Put all your hope in him for this new year, Amy, for great is his faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The shield of faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/Cap-s_Shield.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shield of faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have so many Christians thrown away the shield of faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In addition to all this, take up the shield of faith, with which you can extinguish all the flaming arrows of the evil one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, understand the nature of these flaming arrows. They are lies. Lies about us and lies about the Lord and what he has done. Jesus says of the devil,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“When he lies, he speaks his native language, for he is a liar and the father of lies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:44b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lies can be insidious. They must be stamped out before they take hold, like flames licking around. What do these lies do? They create doubt. And how do we combat doubt? By exercising and building faith! But how do we do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is faith anyway? Those who think it is an intellectual acceptance of some revealed truth are so far away from real understanding. Faith is a &lt;em&gt;life lived&lt;/em&gt; upon the foundation of this truth from the Lord, upon Christ himself, fully committed, trusting and even depending on him to keep his promises. (And he will.) So, how to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is again the key. I have to ask myself with brutal honesty, does my life reflect that I will one day stand before the Lord and give an account? Does my life reflect that I have understood Jesus teaching and am living by it in full obedience to him, joyously surrendered? Many seem not to understand this and then wonder why their faith is so small and why doubt is creeping in. Half-hearted belief is no belief at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider even this one thing that Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But many who are first will be last, and many who are last will be first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context of this is the rich young ruler, earnestly seeking but tragically unable to give up this life&amp;rsquo;s riches and pleasures for the Kingdom, just like so many today. Why is it that even within the church so many are trying to be first? Do we really not believe Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may need some help with this. So let us ask our Heavenly Father, who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open my eyes that I may see wonderful things in your law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May this be our most earnest prayer as we learn to wield the shield of faith and extinguish those flaming arrows. And let us observe the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in our lives as we live this life of faith, recognising that his faithfulness is in fact the ultimate faith builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take up your shield of faith, Amy, and know that he who promised is faithful! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Self-control</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/peter-herrmann-9_FK2Tp-kLA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Self-control" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we travel in time, and how could that help our self-control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; self-control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact it&amp;rsquo;s easy to travel in time, in our imagination. There are two vital destinations that can help us grow in self-control, especially in the face of temptation. But first, take note of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God is faithful; he will not let you be tempted beyond what you can bear. But when you are tempted, he will also provide a way out so that you can stand up under it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should expect to be tempted. How else will we grow in self-control other than by exercising it? So we should expect also to have to work at this. It won&amp;rsquo;t be easy, obviously, since nothing worthwhile was ever gained like that. Just let us never overlook God&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in enabling us to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first destination in time is just a few minutes into the future. Let us imagine looking back, observing our own behaviour through the lens of hindsight. Do we see someone behaving honourably? Someone displaying strength of character? Someone we are pleased to be? May the Lord&amp;rsquo;s sustaining grace enable us to be that! We must be mindful that our character is defined by the accumulation of every choice that we make, no matter how small or apparently insignificant. The new viewpoint helps enormously with this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second destination is a little further, at the end of our lives. Let us imagine being welcomed into heaven by our Lord. What is it that I want to hear on that day? I will live my life to hear him say this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Well done, good and faithful servant!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do some time-travelling in your mind, Amy, and live your life to hear him say, “Well done, my good and faithful servant!” 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faithfulness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/sean-benesh-VnmbcgAfL3Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faithfulness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fuels faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; faithfulness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness is such an honourable character trait, perhaps the noblest of them all. To be loyal, steadfast, trustworthy and true⸺surely these words make our hearts soar. They speak to the very heart of noble character, of character that honours the Lord. So where does faithfulness come from? There are two answers to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness, evident throughout Scripture, from where he first introduces himself to Moses, right up to John&amp;rsquo;s vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, the rider on the white horse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [the LORD] passed in front of Moses, proclaiming, “The LORD, the LORD, the compassionate and gracious God, slow to anger, abounding in love and faithfulness, maintaining love to thousands, and forgiving wickedness, rebellion and sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the ways of the LORD are loving and faithful for those who keep the demands of his covenant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the word of the LORD is right and true; he is faithful in all he does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 33:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your love, O LORD, reaches to the heavens, your faithfulness to the skies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 36:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet this I call to mind and therefore I have hope: Because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great love we are not consumed, for his compassions never fail. They are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who calls you is faithful and he will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I saw heaven standing open and there before me was a white horse, whose rider is called Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness to us makes our hearts burn with fire, fuelling our own faithfulness, our noblest thoughts and deeds, through and for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, consider the word itself, &lt;em&gt;pistis&lt;/em&gt; in the original Greek. Mostly that word is not in fact translated as faithfulness, but rather faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pistis — persuasion that is credence; moral conviction (of religious truth or the truthfulness of God or a religious teacher) especially reliance upon Christ for salvation; abstractly constancy in such profession; by extension the system of religious (Gospel) truth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Strong&amp;#39;s Greek Lexicon&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness then is fueled by being full of faith. Genuine, all-in, life-changing faith in the one who is faithful to all he has said, and indeed all he is, gives us the power to live lives that are worthy of our calling, manifesting in the noblest of hearts, and lasting faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him Amy, whose name is Faithful and True, be full of faith, and let that fuel your own faithfulness, to him and for him, forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
