<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>consistency on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/consistency/</link>
        <description>Recent content in consistency on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/consistency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The way to holiness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-way-to-holiness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-way-to-holiness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-way-to-holiness/alexander-schimmeck-Aohf8gqa7Zc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The way to holiness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you holy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I dare to ask such a confronting question? In fact it&amp;rsquo;s not my own. The question belongs to J.C. Ryle, and was first asked in 1887.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For one thing, let me ask everyone who may read these pages, Are you holy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not ask whether you attend church regularly, whether you have been baptized and receive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper, or whether you call yourself a Christian; I ask something more than this: Are you holy, or are you not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not ask &amp;hellip; whether you want to be holy and hope you will be holy some day. I ask something more than this: Are you yourself holy this very day, or are you not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I ask so directly and so strongly? I do it because the Bible says that without holiness, no one will see the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J.C. Ryle, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Holiness, Chapter 3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an uncomfortable question to be sure but a vital one, and one which I ask myself from time to time. There is enormous value in asking this question. Why is that? Not only because our personal holiness is so important, but because the question itself &lt;em&gt;shows us the way to holiness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can such a question show the way? Simply because when I ask this of myself, certain things may suddenly and vividly spring into the forefront of my mind⸺things in my life that seek to deny that I am holy. What a revelation! These are precisely the things that need to be purged from my life, biffed out, put to death. Or things not in my life that need to be. Those must come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, am I holy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a remarkably simple and straightforward and practical way to know how to live a holy life, don&amp;rsquo;t you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryle is quoting here from the letter to the Hebrews, just after the cloud of witnesses and running with perseverance and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s discipline of his sons and daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore lift your drooping hands and strengthen your weak knees, and make straight paths for your feet, so that what is lame may not be put out of joint but rather be healed. Strive for peace with everyone, and for the holiness without which no one will see the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware the pernicious lie that lurks in our subconscious which we must deal with⸺that living with such holiness is entirely beyond us, and it is unrealistic to aspire to such a thing. Repudiate the lie! It is Satan&amp;rsquo;s utmost desire that we swallow it. Jesus warns us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He was a murderer from the beginning, and does not stand in the truth, because there is no truth in him. When he lies, he speaks out of his own character, for he is a liar and the father of lies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:44&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then is the truth? Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each one of us was chosen by our Heavenly Father before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. He is ambitious to achieve his plans and purposes for and in each one of us! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursue that holiness, Amy, with steadfast faithfulness and determination, so you may answer that question with a joyous and resounding yes! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>In pursuit of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/jonathan-chng-3R4vPrSB1c4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post In pursuit of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this wisdom in the secret heart is so precious in the sight of the Lord then surely it is worth pursuing with zeal and determination. How exactly can we do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man [or woman] keep his [or her] way pure? By guarding it according to your word.&lt;br&gt;
With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments!&lt;br&gt;
I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed are you, O LORD; teach me your statutes!&lt;br&gt;
With my lips I declare all the rules of your mouth.&lt;br&gt;
In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches.&lt;br&gt;
I will meditate on your precepts and fix my eyes on your ways.&lt;br&gt;
I will delight in your statutes; I will not forget your word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 takes us into the depths, the depths of longing for the Lord, of desiring to be right with him, for an alignment of our secret heart with his will, and for his plans and purposes to be unfolded in our lives. Truly it challenges Ephesians Chapter One in my heart for which I would take to that desert island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see how to pursue wisdom in the secret heart. These are the headlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With my whole heart&lt;/em&gt; — no compromise! Ruthless consistency is required. Nothing can remain that is displeasing to the Lord, and in this we should expect to be tested. Will we take the Lord seriously or not? He is not deceived and nor should we be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have stored up your word in my heart &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — more than just knowing, this is loving⸺loving to spend time with the Lord in his word. His word in our hearts must be that which fuels our very lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; that I might not sin against you&lt;/em&gt; — our ongoing sanctification, our growing in holiness, is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessed are you, O Lord&lt;/em&gt; — we must meditate on the goodness of God, over and over, dwelling in it, reminding ourselves of his mercy. All his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness! To displace those idols which compete for our affection we must grow such a love for our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches&lt;/em&gt; — our Heavenly Father reveals himself to us through his written word. May we delight to read it, and to read it more, and to surrender our will to it, joyfully, ever growing in relationship with the one who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will meditate on your precepts &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — with a surrendered heart, taking all the time required for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s holy word to permeate our hearts and lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; and fix my eyes on your ways&lt;/em&gt; — every cyclist knows that you end up in the place where you fix your eyes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is required in pursuit of these things and we are not left alone in this. It is the heart-work of the Holy Spirit, his utmost desire for us, but we must not overlook how much discipline is required on our part, as Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that in a race all the runners run, but only one receives the prize? So run that you may obtain it. Every athlete exercises self-control in all things. They do it to receive a perishable wreath, but we an imperishable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 9:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lest we forget what is at stake,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all vigilance, Amy, pursue wisdom in the secret heart, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The shield of faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/Cap-s_Shield.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shield of faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have so many Christians thrown away the shield of faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In addition to all this, take up the shield of faith, with which you can extinguish all the flaming arrows of the evil one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, understand the nature of these flaming arrows. They are lies. Lies about us and lies about the Lord and what he has done. Jesus says of the devil,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“When he lies, he speaks his native language, for he is a liar and the father of lies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:44b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lies can be insidious. They must be stamped out before they take hold, like flames licking around. What do these lies do? They create doubt. And how do we combat doubt? By exercising and building faith! But how do we do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is faith anyway? Those who think it is an intellectual acceptance of some revealed truth are so far away from real understanding. Faith is a &lt;em&gt;life lived&lt;/em&gt; upon the foundation of this truth from the Lord, upon Christ himself, fully committed, trusting and even depending on him to keep his promises. (And he will.) So, how to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is again the key. I have to ask myself with brutal honesty, does my life reflect that I will one day stand before the Lord and give an account? Does my life reflect that I have understood Jesus teaching and am living by it in full obedience to him, joyously surrendered? Many seem not to understand this and then wonder why their faith is so small and why doubt is creeping in. Half-hearted belief is no belief at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider even this one thing that Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But many who are first will be last, and many who are last will be first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context of this is the rich young ruler, earnestly seeking but tragically unable to give up this life&amp;rsquo;s riches and pleasures for the Kingdom, just like so many today. Why is it that even within the church so many are trying to be first? Do we really not believe Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may need some help with this. So let us ask our Heavenly Father, who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open my eyes that I may see wonderful things in your law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May this be our most earnest prayer as we learn to wield the shield of faith and extinguish those flaming arrows. And let us observe the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in our lives as we live this life of faith, recognising that his faithfulness is in fact the ultimate faith builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take up your shield of faith, Amy, and know that he who promised is faithful! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ruthless consistency</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/ruthless-consistency/nick-fewings-4x9cfxaiBYQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Ruthless consistency" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else follows from ruthless consistency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already saw that ruthless consistency is the enabler for engaging our whole mind in faith, but there&amp;rsquo;s more to be found along this path, much more. By bringing our intellect into alignment with the eternal truths of the Lord, our mind is renewed, so much so, as if it were previously firing on only a few of the available cylinders. Paul writes about this to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not conform to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind. Then you will be able to test and approve what God’s will is⸺his good, pleasing and perfect will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewed minds transform our very lives. Otherwise how blindly we may find ourselves following along in the ways of the world: judging others, taking offence, living for self, and being so pleased with ourselves, smug and self-righteous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewing of the mind and the life-transformation that follows is an ongoing process, fuelled by a ruthless consistency in seeking to honour the Lord⸺that ruthless consistency which compels us to root out and expel every sin, every misplaced thought. To replace love of self with love for the Lord and for one another, and to do this with zeal and great joy. To dwell in love and faithfulness, gentleness and kindness and patience, and to live with humility and absolute integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then? Then we will be able to test and approve what God’s will is. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider for a moment what that means, as it&amp;rsquo;s not immediately apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test here means to be able to recognise as genuine after examination. For example being able to see the Lord&amp;rsquo;s handiwork in situations which might otherwise be difficult to endure. In all things God works for our good, and some of these things are painful indeed, and can be prolonged. With a renewed mind we are able to perceive his grace in these very situations as he works on our hearts, preparing us for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And our approval simply means saying, yes Lord! Accepting, and making a joyful surrender⸺even in the difficulty and the pain⸺to the power and grace and healing from the Lord which is making us like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with ruthless consistency, Amy, and be transformed by the renewing of your mind! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faith vs reason</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/dan-cristian-padure-h3kuhYUCE9A-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faith vs reason" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does radical faith require us to switch off our intellect?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dear friend of mine has been having what I would call a faith crisis. In the context of my ongoing waiting on an impossible promise from the Lord, he cannot relate to someone who he would say is living in the hope of something that contradicts the observed and obvious reality. He asks, how could I have abandoned reason and switched off the rational part of my brain in quite such a naive way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I argue that in fact the opposite is true, and that I have brought all my intellect and understanding to bear in my faith situation. How so? And what does the Bible have to say about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom, and knowledge of the Holy One is understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 9:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One aspect of wisdom is &lt;em&gt;applied intellect&lt;/em&gt;, that is intellect used to align a life with knowledge of the Holy One in a practical way, in order to live that life on the right path.  And wisdom begins with the fear of the Lord. Recall Tim Keller&amp;rsquo;s definition: “The fear of the Lord is a reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Lord of all creation loves me to the extent that he gave up his only Son to an excruciating death in order to rescue me, and has promised abundant life and ongoing rescue in him, the only rational response is to completely cast myself upon his love, trusting him, absolutely. Anything less betrays a lack of understanding of the eternal reality. (Sadly it seems to me that few indeed are able to rationalize to this extent.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this rational response look like then? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. Diving headfirst into the wellspring of life. Living confidently on the firm foundation of such a promise from the Lord.  Ruthless consistency is the key which unlocks the understanding to be able to live like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so radical faith in the one who is faithful and true is in fact the only way to live with intellectual integrity. Having tested it, we must lean into it as the foundation of our life. Nothing else makes any sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with radical faith, Amy, employing all of your intellect to live a life increasingly aligned with your growing knowledge of the Holy One! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
