<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>waiting on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/waiting/</link>
        <description>Recent content in waiting on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/waiting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Gordian problems</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/gordian-problems/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/gordian-problems/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/gordian-problems/gordian-knot-coin.webp" alt="Featured image of post Gordian problems" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you untangle a Gordian knot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you know the legend of the knot so complex and tangled, for which the one who released it would be bestowed with glory and honour? Alexander the Great famously drew his sword and sliced it apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the problems we face in life, or the problems faced by those we know⸺problems so complex and tangled that they are utterly beyond us, intractable problems, Gordian problems⸺shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we expect the Lord simply to slice them apart triumphantly as did Alexander? Why does he not do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we find instead? That the Lord&amp;rsquo;s response to our prayers, his mighty work of great power, is so painfully slow that we can barely see headway. How can our faith withstand this? How can we endure the waiting, the ongoing nature of such a problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could there be another way to see this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter tells us straightforwardly what we should expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But do not overlook this one fact, beloved, that with the Lord one day is as a thousand years, and a thousand years as one day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Peter 3:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh dear. In the light of this verse I remember chuckling self-deprecatingly to myself that all my problems would be sorted out in a couple of days. God time is slow, slow, slow time. Isn&amp;rsquo;t the waiting simply infuriating?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three observations that enable us to endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s notice that Peter addresses his readers as beloved. That&amp;rsquo;s us! We are beloved of the Lord, and whatever the situation and no matter how long the waiting, we must not forget that. Notice the tenderness and understanding here, as Peter articulates that the wait may be prolonged. The Lord is not oblivious of nor indifferent to our pain in the waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, let&amp;rsquo;s notice that Alexander the Great was in fact a brutal warlord who left in his wake death and destruction. Slicing through the knot in the way that he did reflects who he was. The Lord is so completely not like this. Consider the very next verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Lord is not slow to fulfil his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Peter 3:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is so unlike the brutal warlord. With infinite patience and painstaking attention to detail, he unpicks and untangles the most intractable problems in our lives, with such gentleness and amazing kindness, prepared to take as long as is necessary, not wishing that any should perish but that all should reach repentance. It is not slowness at all. It is in fact gentleness and kindness and meticulous restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirdly and finally, let&amp;rsquo;s notice the symmetry in Peter&amp;rsquo;s characterisation: with the Lord one day is as a thousand years, and a thousand years as one day. For sure, some things take such a long time, and we struggle to understand why this would be so. But for others or even for these at just the right time, in a moment, in a twinkling of the eye, the Lord does his work of great power and quite suddenly everything is different. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave the Gordian problems to the Lord, Amy, and trust that with infinite patience, gentleness and kindness and great power, he knows just what to do! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How long, O Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 07:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/zoltan-tasi-CLJeQCr2F_A-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How long, O Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most unanswered question in the Bible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever?&lt;br&gt;
How long will you hide your face from me?&lt;br&gt;
How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day?&lt;br&gt;
How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the Lord answer? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t he know how hard it is to wait on him? Why won&amp;rsquo;t he at least tell us how long? Imagine how much more straightforward it would be if he did. “Hang in there, Amy, for eighteen months. And for you, Simon, six years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does he not answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, this is not all that hard to understand. Paul points us at two reasons in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, because I have heard of your faith in the Lord Jesus and your love toward all the saints, I do not cease to give thanks for you, remembering you in my prayers, that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of him, having the eyes of your hearts enlightened, that you may know what is the hope to which he has called you, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4, 15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the eyes of our hearts enlightened that we may know what is the hope to which he has called us⸺the first reason is our faith, which requires us to use the eyes of our hearts rather than the eyes of our faces. Waiting is faith building, oh how it is that! Waiting confidently on the Lord, not doubting⸺it changes us. It grows our faith. Hear two questions from the Lord in the waiting time: “Do you trust me, Amy?” and the second, harder one: “How much do you trust me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is what David clings to in our psalm. And knowing how long would require less trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason is our holiness. We were chosen in Christ before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. Our sanctification, our steadily increasing holiness, is a work of the Holy Spirit, but it is also our own most earnest hard work. What better work is there to do in the waiting time, that at the time of fulfilment we may be found to be holy and blameless in his sight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habbakuk also cries out with the same question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O LORD, how long shall I cry for help, and you will not hear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his particular case, the Lord answers, and praise him for that answer in which we also can rejoice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days
that you would not believe if told.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. We would not believe if told the work the Lord is doing in our own waiting time. It is a work of faith, of holiness, and of fulfilment of promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise the Lord, wonder and be astounded, Amy, for he is doing a work in our lives which we would not believe if told! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Patience in waiting</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-waiting/pavlenko-8BNO4HUQYRw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Patience in waiting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we grow in patience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; patience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dictionary defines patience like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/&lt;br&gt;
▸ noun [mass noun]&lt;br&gt;
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Oxford Dictionary of English&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on delay for now. So, how can we grow in patience in the face of delay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m asking an easy question! We grow in this patience by having to wait, and by learning to wait well. But actually waiting well is anything but easy. It is the hardest thing. And it&amp;rsquo;s harder still when we can&amp;rsquo;t understand why. Why the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to consider those who waited before us. Like Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a miraculous escape from being drowned at birth, Moses had a privileged upbringing, growing up in the royal palace of Egypt, learning leadership and what it meant to rule.  As a gifted and highly capable forty year old, he thought he was ready to lead his people out of slavery. The Lord had other plans! Moses spent the next forty years tending sheep in the wilderness. We can wonder how long it took him to come to terms with that! I&amp;rsquo;m sure he spent quite some time raging against the apparent pointlessness of his life. But what was the result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Moses was a very humble man, more humble than anyone else on the face of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/numbers&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 12:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those forty years the Lord wrought some fundamental changes in Moses&amp;rsquo; heart. Where else did that humility come from? In that waiting time, Moses had been completely transformed, and was finally ready to be used by the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting may feel like death, but in fact it can be a path to abundant life, to the mother lode of spiritual blessing and joy. It is a powerful agency of the Lord to change our heart and grow each one of us into someone who can be of some use in the Kingdom. If we can notice this happening in ourselves as it unfolds, that may help us to wait with patience, and to wait well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to wait well, Amy, and grow in patience! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/sasha-freemind-nXo2ZsKHTHg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unanswered prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7, 11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unanswered prayer is a real thing. How can we deal with it? Many have grappled with this, and much has been written. Some have said, the Lord always answers prayer: sometimes yes; sometimes no; sometimes not yet. I find this glib and unhelpful. Because sometimes there is silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a husband and father, let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mark, a faithful servant of the Lord, suffering with severe health issues for so many years, for whom we have been faithfully, earnestly praying, confident that the Lord hears and is powerful to heal. Except he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, and this man dies, leaving his grieving wife, Grace, and their eight-year-old son, Callum. And from the Lord, only silence. What kind of answer to prayer is that? How is that a reasonable response to desperate prayers offered from a broken heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another way to see this. Unanswered prayer is an &lt;em&gt;invitation into relationship&lt;/em&gt;. An invitation into intimacy. How does this work? Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Why did Mark have to die? Don&amp;rsquo;t you care?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you have done something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “He loved you, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? Did you love him? You did love him, didn&amp;rsquo;t you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Yes, Amy, I loved him. I love him still.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “What about Grace and little Callum? This is breaking my heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;long pause, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Mine too, Amy. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit together for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;intimate, healing silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father grieves over his broken world, and the suffering his people bear. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with him, and grieve also, in the intimacy of his healing presence. And in the meantime,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us. For the creation waits in eager expectation for the children of God to be revealed. For the creation was subjected to frustration, not by its own choice, but by the will of the one who subjected it, in hope that the creation itself will be liberated from its bondage to decay and brought into the freedom and glory of the children of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:18-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit with the Lord in the silence of the unanswered prayer, Amy, in the intimacy of his healing presence 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/melissa-askew-8n00CqwnqO8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 27 pretty much has it all. Here are the highlights.  “The LORD is my light and my salvation &amp;hellip; the stronghold of my life (v1). One thing I ask from the LORD &amp;hellip; that I may dwell in the house of the LORD all the days of my life (v4). He will keep me safe in his dwelling &amp;hellip; and set me high upon a rock (v5). Your face, LORD, I will seek (v8).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantly reminding ourselves of these things, and living them every day, every moment, is part of it. But then out of the blue comes v9, which suddenly expresses doubt and fear of rejection.  “Do not hide your face from me, do not turn your servant away in anger; you have been my helper. Do not reject me or forsake me, God my Saviour.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such sentiments occur throughout the Psalms, and this by the grace of God. Let&amp;rsquo;s try to understand why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s wisdom is beyond understanding, let&amp;rsquo;s first acknowledge that. He has plans and purposes, and they are good. He desires us to walk by faith, to trust him absolutely, and he loves us, ruthlessly. That&amp;rsquo;s an uncomfortable word! The walk of faith is not comfortable, nor should we expect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while it can feel, at times overwhelmingly, like he has turned his face away and rejected us, he has not. He alone knows what he is doing, and he is deeply invested in us. That rejection is what Jesus received on the cross, so we never have to. And that is why we can assert with the Psalmist, “I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living.” (v13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we live confidently? “Wait for the LORD; be strong and take heart and wait for the LORD.” (v14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be strong and take heart and wait for the Lord, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Walking by faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/walking-by-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 06:52:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/walking-by-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/walking-by-faith/jimmy-larry-7uvixXrQkfw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Walking by faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when we walk by faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest example we have is Abraham. He didn&amp;rsquo;t always get it right, nor did he manage always to trust, as shown by his shabby little misdeed with Hagar. Evidently not super-human then! But the Lord called him again out of that particular failure thirteen years later, out of the absolute mess he had made (“walk before me and be blameless” - Gen 17:1), after he had been waiting for the fulfilment of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promise to him for 25 years. Twenty-five years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul&amp;rsquo;s account in Romans 4 manages to overlook Abraham&amp;rsquo;s shameful failure (oh the grace of God!), and we find this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet Abraham did not waver through unbelief regarding the promise of God, but was strengthened in his faith and gave glory to God, being fully persuaded that God had power to do what he had promised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 4:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He believed again, and walked by faith. What then happened? He was strengthened in his faith. Notice what happened here. He believed. He exercised faith. Just enough. Perhaps barely enough, but enough all the same. And the Lord strengthened him in that faith. And it was God who was thus glorified, not Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most striking consequence is found just before this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Against all hope, Abraham in hope believed and so became the father of many nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 4:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that little word, so. What was the reason Abraham became the father of many nations? Because he believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we walk by faith, God fulfils his plans and purposes in us and through us. There is a causal link. What more motivation could we have than this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on walking by faith, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why is life so hard?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/why-is-life-so-hard/hugo-jehanne-LOHVrTsdvzY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Why is life so hard?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is life so hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider: the young person, to whom life seems so bleak they turn to self harm to try to anchor to reality; the older person who lives alone, who may go days without speaking with another, having long forgotten what it&amp;rsquo;s like to give and receive a hug; the faithful believer waiting on the Lord for the fulfilment of a promise, praising him in the heart-breaking years of waiting, or the one crying out for healing and enduring debilitating pain in the waiting and the praising; the grief in the death of a child. Why is life quite so very hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this may be a consequence of trying to live apart from the Lord, or simply failing to love one another, but some is not. What of that, then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul writes about this in Romans 8:18-27, in a passage sandwiched between two rather better known and loved celebrations of victory. If you possibly can, read it in The Message. Here&amp;rsquo;s an extract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The difficult times of pain throughout the world are simply birth pangs. But it’s not only around us; it’s within us. &amp;hellip; These sterile and barren bodies of ours are yearning for full deliverance. That is why waiting does not diminish us, any more than waiting diminishes a pregnant mother. We are enlarged in the waiting. &amp;hellip; the longer we wait, the larger we become, and the more joyful our expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s much in this world that is anaesthetic. Beware! It may dull the pain, but it will also dull the joyful expectancy. Perhaps only when we bear some pain ourselves can we be of any real use in the Kingdom. It need not be our own, but then it&amp;rsquo;s not too hard to find someone else&amp;rsquo;s, and wait with them in that. These are the places where God&amp;rsquo;s grace is most evident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait with joyful expectancy, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
