<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>waiting on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/waiting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in waiting on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/waiting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we live confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s love?
Psalm 27 pretty much has it all. Here are the highlights. “The LORD is my light and my salvation &amp;hellip; the stronghold of my life (v1). One thing I ask from the LORD &amp;hellip; that I may dwell in the house of the LORD all the days of my life (v4). He will keep me safe in his dwelling &amp;hellip; and set me high upon a rock (v5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking by faith</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 06:52:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What happens when we walk by faith?
Perhaps the greatest example we have is Abraham. He didn&amp;rsquo;t always get it right, nor did he manage always to trust, as shown by his shabby little misdeed with Hagar. Evidently not super-human then! But the Lord called him again out of that particular failure thirteen years later, out of the absolute mess he had made (“walk before me and be blameless” - Gen 17:1), after he had been waiting for the fulfillment of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promise to him for 25 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is life so hard?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Why is life so hard?
Consider: the young person, to whom life seems so bleak they turn to self harm to try to anchor to reality; the older person who lives alone, who may go days without speaking with another, having long forgotten what it&amp;rsquo;s like to give and receive a hug; the faithful believer waiting on the Lord for the fulfillment of a promise, praising him in the heart-breaking years of waiting, or the one crying out for healing and enduring debilitating pain in the waiting and the praising; the grief in the death of a child.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
