<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>holiness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/holiness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in holiness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/holiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Love and holiness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/love-and-holiness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/love-and-holiness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/love-and-holiness/kanchanara-7E3QGntO66M-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Love and holiness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If love is one side of the coin which defines how we must live our lives, what is the other?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, the coin bears the face of Jesus, for it is his currency and our lives must reflect his own. So why is it that I am wanting to further distil this? Simply so we may grasp with crystal clarity what it really means to live our lives in a way which honours him absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already seen that love is the most important thing⸺love for the Father and love for Jesus, followed by love for one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And one of the scribes came up and heard them disputing with one another, and seeing that he answered them well, asked him, “Which commandment is the most important of all?” Jesus answered, “The most important is, ‘Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. And you shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength.’ The second is this: ‘You shall love your neighbour as yourself.’ There is no other commandment greater than these.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 12:28-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One side of the coin is simply inscribed &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;. And the other side?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the LORD spoke to Moses, saying, “Speak to all the congregation of the people of Israel and say to them, You shall be holy, for I the LORD your God am holy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 19:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other side of the coin is inscribed &lt;em&gt;holiness&lt;/em&gt;. Love and holiness. Two sides of the same coin in fact. How so? Jesus tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If you love me, you will keep my commandments.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So our personal holiness must be a consequence of love. Our motivation to live with holiness must be love for the Lord, our utmost desire to honour him. There is no other way to live like this victoriously in his power and by his grace. And in this there can be no pretending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you, Solomon my son, know the God of your father and serve him with a whole heart and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches all hearts and understands every plan and thought. If you seek him, he will be found by you, but if you forsake him, he will cast you off forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hebrew word here is &lt;em&gt;yêtser&lt;/em&gt;, which means intent. &lt;em&gt;He understands every intent of the thoughts.&lt;/em&gt; Every motive. This is both confronting and liberating. Confronting obviously. But liberating because when we stumble, which we do because that is part of what it means to be human, he understands the motive behind the thoughts. If my deepest desire is to honour my Heavenly Father, he knows this, and my stumbles are easily forgiven as simply that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love and holiness⸺this is what must define us if we are to bring him glory, fulfil his mission for us, and change the world. And this too is what must define our church if we are to have any relevance in a broken and hurting world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So each morning I awake, I resolve to honour the Lord this very day through the love and holiness of my life. It is my offering of worship to him, and it is joyous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursue love and holiness, Amy, with ruthless consistency and great joy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Be holy, for I am holy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/be-holy-for-i-am-holy/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/be-holy-for-i-am-holy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/be-holy-for-i-am-holy/linda-christiansen-cybTg_gYWkw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Be holy, for I am holy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the point of Leviticus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished compiling a Scripture index of everything I&amp;rsquo;ve written to you over the last two years or so. It was really quite interesting to me! I see that I have managed to make reference to 44 out of the 66 books of the Bible, which got me thinking about those I&amp;rsquo;ve so far omitted. Why do I think this matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Timothy 3:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “man of God” is a common Old Testament expression, which can refer to male or female, and indeed the NIV translates this as servant of God. It simply means us, you or me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, all Scripture? Including Leviticus? For us?! How could that possibly be relevant for Christians living in a post-resurrection world? Let&amp;rsquo;s see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am the LORD your God. Consecrate yourselves therefore, and be holy, for I am holy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 11:44&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostle Peter endorses its relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As obedient children, do not be conformed to the passions of your former ignorance, but as he who called you is holy, you also be holy in all your conduct, since it is written, “You shall be holy, for I am holy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:14-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My study Bible summarises it like this: the book of Leviticus is concerned with what it means to be the holy people of a holy God. And what could be more relevant for us than that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gain insight from Leviticus into things we might otherwise overlook. What can we learn from the myriad of seemingly picky little laws that we would instinctively brush aside and not think about? Such things were clearly of great importance to the Lord. Ought we not at least to ponder why that was? These are not unrelated to those matters upon which Jesus expounded in the Sermon on the Mount, and Paul also has long lists over which we must take great care. The Lord is apparently greatly concerned about things we may be inclined to brush aside as “details”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to understand the sacrificial system of the Old Testament we must study Leviticus, and by this we can start to understand Jesus&amp;rsquo; own sacrifice on the cross. Why did it have to be quite so bloody? And why did he have to die such a death? Leviticus teaches us such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the life of the flesh is in the blood, and I have given it for you on the altar to make atonement for your souls, for it is the blood that makes atonement by the life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 17:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also much we can learn of God&amp;rsquo;s own heart from reading Leviticus, such that as we grow in this knowledge we can more fully honour him. For example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“When you reap the harvest of your land, you shall not reap your field right up to its edge, neither shall you gather the gleanings after your harvest. And you shall not strip your vineyard bare, neither shall you gather the fallen grapes of your vineyard. You shall leave them for the poor and for the sojourner: I am the LORD your God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 19:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What compassion there is to be found here, what concern for the poor and for the alien. The God who gave this commandment is our God, who does not change. It turns out that the book of Leviticus is a veritable treasure trove!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look into it, unpacking these treasures, let us not forget the headline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be holy, Amy, because he is holy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Biblical giants</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/biblical-giants/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/biblical-giants/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/biblical-giants/00_29_0496_Waipoua_Forest_NZ_-_Kauri_Baum_Tane_Mahuta.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Biblical giants" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you in awe of those giants of the faith we know from the Bible⸺Noah, Abraham, Moses, David⸺and how they managed to play a part in the purposes of God beyond anything we see in our times?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, don&amp;rsquo;t be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides being righteous and blameless and the reason humankind survived God&amp;rsquo;s purge of evil by the flood, Noah was just a man, and later got himself drunk and rather embarrassed himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Noah began to be a man of the soil, and he planted a vineyard. He drank of the wine and became drunk and lay uncovered in his tent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 9:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And besides being the one who in hope against all hope believed and so became the father of many nations, Abraham was previously a coward and a liar (Genesis 12:10-20) and a man who gave up waiting on the Lord (Genesis 16).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses too was a coward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to him, “Who has made man&amp;rsquo;s mouth? Who makes him mute, or deaf, or seeing, or blind? Is it not I, the LORD? Now therefore go, and I will be with your mouth and teach you what you shall speak.” But [Moses] said, “Oh, my Lord, please send someone else.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 4:11-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some time later, even having witnessed the Lord&amp;rsquo;s miraculous deliverance of the Israelites from Egypt, Moses&amp;rsquo; lack of faith caused him to make a heinous mistake at Meribah which was most severely punished by God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the LORD said to Moses and Aaron, “Because you did not believe in me, to uphold me as holy in the eyes of the people of Israel, therefore you shall not bring this assembly into the land that I have given them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 20:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses furthermore failed to take responsibility for this failure, and his later account to the Israelites was simply untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But the LORD was angry with me because of you and would not listen to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 3:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complete our quartet of heroes we have David, that man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart, that adulterer and murderer (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What instead should we notice about these giants of the faith? They were all in fact frail and flawed human beings used by a mighty God for his Kingdom purposes. What was special about each of them was that God set his love upon them, and chose to work mightily through each one⸺just as he does for you, and just as he does for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews makes exactly this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are surrounded by these heroes. They are not above or beyond us and nor should we be in awe of them. We should rather read of their best qualities and eagerly desire those, being fully persuaded that the Lord can do the same through each of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with Noah&amp;rsquo;s blamelessness and Abraham&amp;rsquo;s faith and David&amp;rsquo;s desire for the Lord, Amy, and run with endurance, knowing that the Lord will bless you with what you desire (Psalm 37:4) and use you mightily for his Kingdom purposes! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Flood</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/flood/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/flood/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/flood/kelly-sikkema-_whs7FPfkwQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Flood" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference can be made by one holy and blameless life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of things just came together: the flooding in your village and the recent floods here in Auckland and the surrounding areas. We have been praying about both, and this got me thinking about The Flood, that is, Noah&amp;rsquo;s flood, the introduction to which is simply terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. How he must have wept over that, heartbrokenly. And in more recent times? As we look around at what is going on in this broken world, perhaps we can gain some small insight into how that must have felt. This was not as he had created it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God saw everything that he had made, and behold, it was very good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something had gone terribly wrong, and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s first instinct in wrath and holiness was to eliminate the evil completely and comprehensively⸺simply terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But Noah found favour in the eyes of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could this be? Simply as we are told.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noah was a righteous man, and this was enough for the Lord to find another way to deal with the evil of humankind. And so what was the consequence of Noah&amp;rsquo;s holy and blameless life? God did indeed wipe out from the earth all of humankind, birds, animals, creeping things, &lt;em&gt;except for Noah and his family and the species-representatives which were saved in the ark&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is the difference that was made by Noah&amp;rsquo;s holy and blameless life. Life on earth was not blotted out, and we ourselves are here today, only because Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think on that for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s staggeringly, outrageously, mind-bogglingly extraordinary, isn&amp;rsquo;t it, the difference that was made by one holy and blameless life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Lord said to Abraham, so he says to each one of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we start to see from Noah&amp;rsquo;s story quite how important this is? Quite how much it matters? The Creator God of the Universe, the Lord of all creation, God Almighty calls us to it, and he is deadly serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the Lord speaking this today, Amy, and never overlook the difference that can be made by one holy and blameless life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How long, O Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 07:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/zoltan-tasi-CLJeQCr2F_A-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How long, O Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most unanswered question in the Bible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever?&lt;br&gt;
How long will you hide your face from me?&lt;br&gt;
How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day?&lt;br&gt;
How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the Lord answer? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t he know how hard it is to wait on him? Why won&amp;rsquo;t he at least tell us how long? Imagine how much more straightforward it would be if he did. “Hang in there, Amy, for eighteen months. And for you, Simon, six years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does he not answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, this is not all that hard to understand. Paul points us at two reasons in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, because I have heard of your faith in the Lord Jesus and your love toward all the saints, I do not cease to give thanks for you, remembering you in my prayers, that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of him, having the eyes of your hearts enlightened, that you may know what is the hope to which he has called you, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4, 15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the eyes of our hearts enlightened that we may know what is the hope to which he has called us⸺the first reason is our faith, which requires us to use the eyes of our hearts rather than the eyes of our faces. Waiting is faith building, oh how it is that! Waiting confidently on the Lord, not doubting⸺it changes us. It grows our faith. Hear two questions from the Lord in the waiting time: “Do you trust me, Amy?” and the second, harder one: “How much do you trust me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is what David clings to in our psalm. And knowing how long would require less trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason is our holiness. We were chosen in Christ before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. Our sanctification, our steadily increasing holiness, is a work of the Holy Spirit, but it is also our own most earnest hard work. What better work is there to do in the waiting time, that at the time of fulfilment we may be found to be holy and blameless in his sight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habbakuk also cries out with the same question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O LORD, how long shall I cry for help, and you will not hear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his particular case, the Lord answers, and praise him for that answer in which we also can rejoice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days
that you would not believe if told.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. We would not believe if told the work the Lord is doing in our own waiting time. It is a work of faith, of holiness, and of fulfilment of promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise the Lord, wonder and be astounded, Amy, for he is doing a work in our lives which we would not believe if told! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Personal holiness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/jeffery-erhunse-4XK2oKKvzVU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Personal holiness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you think of another aspect of worship which has nothing to do with singing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, I urge you, brothers and sisters, in view of God’s mercy, to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God⸺this is your spiritual act of worship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the act of worship which is personal holiness, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the most important word here: &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; links what follows to the entirety of the previous eleven chapters, which is Paul&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the wretched state of humankind without Christ, and of the magnitude and sufficiency of our rescue in Christ, God&amp;rsquo;s free and costly gift of grace to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now a righteousness from God, apart from law, has been made known, to which the Law and the Prophets testify. This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where, then, is boasting? It is excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:21-22, 27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My response then to this gift of grace and righteousness must be to live a life of personal holiness. As I live my life, each day facing temptation, and each day surrendering my will to the sanctifying work of the Spirit, I articulate each small victory as an act of worship to my Heavenly Father who loves me and has rescued me from such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; offer yourselves to God, as those who have been brought from death to life; and offer the parts of your body to him as instruments of righteousness. For sin shall not be your master, because you are not under law, but under grace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should note that God&amp;rsquo;s call to personal holiness is not to the righteous but to sinners, and we would do well to remember his call to Abraham out of the absolute mess and shame that he found himself in thirteen long years after his shabby act with Hagar. Hear the grace and love in this, right alongside the uncompromising call to holiness. Our Heavenly Father has so much love and such a high expectation for his sons and daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old, the LORD appeared to him and said, “I am God Almighty; walk before me and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only in Christ can we live like this, but in him, we can! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer your body as a living sacrifice, Amy, holy and pleasing to God, and worship him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Casting off shame</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/allef-vinicius-oe_03B2Q5A4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Casting off shame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what we do about ourselves, how can we possibly hold our head high?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David had a similar problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was chosen by the Lord because he was a man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart (1 Samuel 13:14). He earnestly sought the Lord and wrote many of the psalms which have blessed the generations.  But let us not make the mistake of thinking that he was a righteous man. His later life was in fact a catalogue of failure and shame, culminating in his most shabby and shameful moral failure, committing adultery with Bathsheba and murdering her husband Uriah the Hittite (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, David wrote Psalm 3 when he was being pursued by his son Absalom, who was trying to kill him and seize control of the kingdom. What greater failure as a father could there be than that? How utterly shameful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet we read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, LORD, are a shield around me, my glory, the One who lifts my head high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was so aware that he had no glory of his own. He had only shame. But the Lord himself was his glory, and not only the reason that he could hold his head high, but the one who actually lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course, this in no way diminishes the Lord&amp;rsquo;s condemnation of sin in one&amp;rsquo;s life. David was severely rebuked by the Lord after his wretched doings with Bathsheba. Repentance was very necessary. Forgiveness followed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. The nearer we draw to God and the more we focus on personal holiness, the more aware we become of our own failure and shame, all those reasons Christ died on the cross. We own those reasons. And yet, the Lord is my glory, the lifter of my head. Yours too, Amy! He chose us in him to be holy and blameless in his sight, and he will achieve his purposes. In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins. Cast off the shame. He alone is my glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold your head high, Amy, and know that the Lord himself is your glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Predestination</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/saiph-muhammad-CSs8aiN_LkI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Predestination" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s all this about predestination? Don&amp;rsquo;t people have a right to choose for themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I swing in my hammock on that desert island, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do except read Ephesians 1. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. In love he predestined us to be adopted as his children through Jesus Christ, in accordance with his pleasure and will &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In him we were also chosen, having been predestined according to the plan of him who works out everything in conformity with the purpose of his will, in order that we, who were the first to hope in Christ, might be for the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4-5, 11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no escaping that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s choice, rather than mine. And that is a wonderful thing. The Lord, the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, does not make mistakes. He chose me. He chose you, Amy, in accordance with his pleasure and will. As for me, I make mistakes, and my own choices are always subject to suspicion and doubt. Not so the Lord! His plans and purposes prevail, for the praise of his glory. I, you, we are both his, forever, and no mistake! And thus we have assurance of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. He chose us to be holy and blameless in his sight. Partly that is an instantaneous, Jesus-died-for-my sins-and-now-I-am-counted-righteous thing. And partly it is a rest-of-my-life thing, as the Holy Spirit continues both to convict me and to empower me to change, as I surrender my will on the pathway to holiness. Both are life-giving, lavish gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what of evangelism? If people are chosen, where is repentance and belief? See what comes next in the passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession⸺to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those to whom Paul writes &lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; the message of truth (because someone told them), and &lt;em&gt;believed&lt;/em&gt;. Predestination does not diminish the gospel message in any way. There is undeniably mystery here, but the greatest evangelist of all time was surely &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Paul himself&lt;/em&gt;, who wrote these words. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, and he is yours, forever, because he chose you in him before the creation of the world. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
