<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>holiness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/holiness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in holiness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/holiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Personal holiness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/jeffery-erhunse-4XK2oKKvzVU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Personal holiness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you think of another aspect of worship which has nothing to do with singing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, I urge you, brothers and sisters, in view of God’s mercy, to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God⸺this is your spiritual act of worship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the act of worship which is personal holiness, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the most important word here: &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; links what follows to the entirety of the previous eleven chapters, which is Paul&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the wretched state of humankind without Christ, and of the magnitude and sufficiency of our rescue in Christ, God&amp;rsquo;s free and costly gift of grace to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now a righteousness from God, apart from law, has been made known, to which the Law and the Prophets testify. This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where, then, is boasting? It is excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:21-22, 27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My response then to this gift of grace and righteousness must be to live a life of personal holiness. As I live my life, each day facing temptation, and each day surrendering my will to the sanctifying work of the Spirit, I articulate each small victory as an act of worship to my Heavenly Father who loves me and has rescued me from such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; offer yourselves to God, as those who have been brought from death to life; and offer the parts of your body to him as instruments of righteousness. For sin shall not be your master, because you are not under law, but under grace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should note that God&amp;rsquo;s call to personal holiness is not to the righteous but to sinners, and we would do well to remember his call to Abraham out of the absolute mess and shame that he found himself in thirteen long years after his shabby act with Hagar. Hear the grace and love in this, right alongside the uncompromising call to holiness. Our Heavenly Father has so much love and such a high expectation for his sons and daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old, the LORD appeared to him and said, “I am God Almighty; walk before me and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only in Christ can we live like this, but in him, we can! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer your body as a living sacrifice, Amy, holy and pleasing to God, and worship him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Casting off shame</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/allef-vinicius-oe_03B2Q5A4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Casting off shame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what we do about ourselves, how can we possibly hold our head high?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David had a similar problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was chosen by the Lord because he was a man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart (1 Samuel 13:14). He earnestly sought the Lord and wrote many of the psalms which have blessed the generations.  But let us not make the mistake of thinking that he was a righteous man. His later life was in fact a catalogue of failure and shame, culminating in his most shabby and shameful moral failure, committing adultery with Bathsheba and murdering her husband Uriah the Hittite (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, David wrote Psalm 3 when he was being pursued by his son Absalom, who was trying to kill him and seize control of the kingdom. What greater failure as a father could there be than that? How utterly shameful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet we read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, LORD, are a shield around me, my glory, the One who lifts my head high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was so aware that he had no glory of his own. He had only shame. But the Lord himself was his glory, and not only the reason that he could hold his head high, but the one who actually lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course, this in no way diminishes the Lord&amp;rsquo;s condemnation of sin in one&amp;rsquo;s life. David was severely rebuked by the Lord after his wretched doings with Bathsheba. Repentance was very necessary. Forgiveness followed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. The nearer we draw to God and the more we focus on personal holiness, the more aware we become of our own failure and shame, all those reasons Christ died on the cross. We own those reasons. And yet, the Lord is my glory, the lifter of my head. Yours too, Amy! He chose us in him to be holy and blameless in his sight, and he will achieve his purposes. In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins. Cast off the shame. He alone is my glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold your head high, Amy, and know that the Lord himself is your glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Predestination</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/saiph-muhammad-CSs8aiN_LkI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Predestination" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s all this about predestination? Don&amp;rsquo;t people have a right to choose for themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I swing in my hammock on that desert island, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do except read Ephesians 1. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. In love he predestined us to be adopted as his children through Jesus Christ, in accordance with his pleasure and will &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In him we were also chosen, having been predestined according to the plan of him who works out everything in conformity with the purpose of his will, in order that we, who were the first to hope in Christ, might be for the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4-5, 11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no escaping that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s choice, rather than mine. And that is a wonderful thing. The Lord, the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, does not make mistakes. He chose me. He chose you, Amy, in accordance with his pleasure and will. As for me, I make mistakes, and my own choices are always subject to suspicion and doubt. Not so the Lord! His plans and purposes prevail, for the praise of his glory. I, you, we are both his, forever, and no mistake! And thus we have assurance of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. He chose us to be holy and blameless in his sight. Partly that is an instantaneous, Jesus-died-for-my sins-and-now-I-am-counted-righteous thing. And partly it is a rest-of-my-life thing, as the Holy Spirit continues both to convict me and to empower me to change, as I surrender my will on the pathway to holiness. Both are life-giving, lavish gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what of evangelism? If people are chosen, where is repentance and belief? See what comes next in the passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession — to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1: 13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those to whom Paul writes &lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; the message of truth (because someone told them), and &lt;em&gt;believed&lt;/em&gt;. Predestination does not diminish the gospel message in any way. There is undeniably mystery here, but the greatest evangelist of all time was surely &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Paul himself&lt;/em&gt;, who wrote these words. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, and he is yours, forever, because he chose you in him before the creation of the world. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
