<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>fruit on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/fruit/</link>
        <description>Recent content in fruit on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/fruit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Relational authenticity</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/jingming-pan-iYsrkq5qq0Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Relational authenticity" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most important thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is love &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve left this one until last, precisely because it is the most important. Why do I say that? So many reasons, starting with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus replied: “&amp;lsquo;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.&amp;rsquo;  This is the first and greatest commandment. And the second is like it: &amp;lsquo;Love your neighbour as yourself.&amp;rsquo;  All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 22:36-40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“A new command I give you: Love one another. As I have loved you, so you must love one another. By this everyone will know that you are my disciples, if you love one another.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not optional⸺there is absolutely no wriggle room here! And yet, why is it that we do not live like this? For tragically, we do not. We should be living and breathing this, all the time. Nothing matters more. But what exactly are we supposed to do as we go about our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phrase I came upon recently has really got its hooks into me: &lt;em&gt;relational authenticity&lt;/em&gt;. This is surely the starting point. Relational authenticity recognises that the one standing before me is a real person, whoever they may be. A real person with their hopes, dreams, disappointments and hurts, just like me. And the choice which is uniquely mine is whether and how to relate, to accept, to love. How do I regard them? As background noise? A diversion? A duty? Someone to look down upon? Someone to avoid? Or a whole person, with all their value and complexity and brokenness, loved by the Lord, as am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. Relational authenticity demands radical humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no difference &amp;hellip; for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified freely by his grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How this challenges ego!  But could we live like this? The prize is glorious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him the whole building is joined together and rises to become a holy temple in the Lord. And in him you too are being built together to become a dwelling in which God lives by his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we develop relational authenticity, this is what we will find: all of us, together, a holy temple in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us not overlook that this is the fruit of the Spirit. We grow in this as the Lord does his work of transforming grace in our lives. In my life. In yours. Softening our hearts, enabling us to love, and making us more like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursue relational authenticity, Amy, and learn to love like Jesus, the most important thing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Self-control</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/self-control/peter-herrmann-9_FK2Tp-kLA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Self-control" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we travel in time, and how could that help our self-control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; self-control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact it&amp;rsquo;s easy to travel in time, in our imagination. There are two vital destinations that can help us grow in self-control, especially in the face of temptation. But first, take note of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God is faithful; he will not let you be tempted beyond what you can bear. But when you are tempted, he will also provide a way out so that you can stand up under it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should expect to be tempted. How else will we grow in self-control other than by exercising it? So we should expect also to have to work at this. It won&amp;rsquo;t be easy, obviously, since nothing worthwhile was ever gained like that. Just let us never overlook God&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in enabling us to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first destination in time is just a few minutes into the future. Let us imagine looking back, observing our own behaviour through the lens of hindsight. Do we see someone behaving honourably? Someone displaying strength of character? Someone we are pleased to be? May the Lord&amp;rsquo;s sustaining grace enable us to be that! We must be mindful that our character is defined by the accumulation of every choice that we make, no matter how small or apparently insignificant. The new viewpoint helps enormously with this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second destination is a little further, at the end of our lives. Let us imagine being welcomed into heaven by our Lord. What is it that I want to hear on that day? I will live my life to hear him say this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Well done, good and faithful servant!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do some time-travelling in your mind, Amy, and live your life to hear him say, “Well done, my good and faithful servant!” 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Joy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/joy/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 08:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/joy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/joy/mi-pham-FtZL0r4DZYk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Joy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we choose joy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; joy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t joy something that from time to time lands on us, thrills our heart, and lifts us into the Lord&amp;rsquo;s presence? How can we choose this for ourselves? In fact we can, and understanding this is the key to a deeper, richer, more joyous walk with the Lord, independent of the circumstances of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Paul&amp;rsquo;s command (a command, no less!) to the Philippians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says it again because it is of such great importance. We must understand this! But how can we rejoice when life is hard, and sorrow and pain feature so prominently in our world and in our lives? Paul tells us almost immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers and sisters, whatever is true, whatever is noble, whatever is right, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is admirable⸺if anything is excellent or praiseworthy⸺think about such things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these things we must think about, exactly? I am grateful to Jim Packer for presenting this so clearly, thus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God loves me, infinitely and eternally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything comes to me from God, at least with his permission and always under his protection, to further my eternal good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My saving knowledge of the Lord Jesus, which will eternally increase, is something supremely worth having.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel message of salvation that I seek to pass on to others is something supremely worth giving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J.I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Laid-Back Religion? Chapter 6: Joy&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By meditating on these matters constantly and faithfully, springs of joy well up in our hearts, turning our Christian walk into “an experience of contentment and exaltation of which the world knows nothing” ― &lt;em&gt;J.I. Packer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose joy, Amy, and meditate on the uplifting and glorious truths of the Lord! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Kindness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/kindness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/kindness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/kindness/limor-zellermayer-cANocSiow7g-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Kindness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is one of the most important considerations when engaging with someone in a difficult conversation? When everything within you wants to make your point, to justify yourself with great vigour? When you have waited for so long and the time is now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; kindness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How easy this is to overlook. Could I be overstating its importance though? I think not. Consider this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am the LORD, who exercises kindness, justice and righteousness on earth, for in these I delight,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 9:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kindness is remarkably prominent don&amp;rsquo;t you think? And the Lord delights in it! And what of this, which characterizes Jesus as the embodiment of kindness and love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the kindness and love of God our Saviour appeared, he saved us &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/titus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Titus 3:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider those who hurt us, and don&amp;rsquo;t even know they have.  What better way is there to bless than with kindness? There&amp;rsquo;s real power in this, power to heal, and power to save. It is a work of the Holy Spirit that we can live like this, in giving rather than receiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As God’s chosen people, holy and dearly loved, clothe yourselves with &amp;hellip; kindness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be filled with kindness, Amy, breathing it out as a blessing from the Holy Spirit! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Tranquility in the soul</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/capturing-the-human-heart-i9uIhSlOWYc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Tranquility in the soul" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know real peace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; peace&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peace here is the Greek word &lt;em&gt;eirene&lt;/em&gt;, which corresponds to the Hebrew word shalom, and could be translated as &lt;em&gt;tranquility in the soul&lt;/em&gt;. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want such a thing? But how can we possibly know such a peace in the turbulent and warmongering world in which we live?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 46 provides insight, and is worth reading in its entirety. The world it describes doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem so very different from our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mountains fall into the heart of the sea,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nations are in uproar, kingdoms fall;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 46:2, 6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an apparently chaotic and tempestuous world this is.  And yet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He lifts his voice, the earth melts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a voice that is! Tranquility in the soul is rooted in the absolute surety that the Lord is sovereign, infinite in power, so very good, and that he loves us beyond imagining. Only so can we rest in him, completely and comprehensively, and have this peace that defies circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He breaks the bow and shatters the spear;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be still, and know that I am God; I will be exalted among the nations, I will be exalted in the earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v9, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem that the world is out of control, but this is illusory and temporary.  Ultimately, God will be exalted in all the earth. In such times as these, we must be still, and in the stillness we can know this, with certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be still, and know that he is God, Amy, and grow in tranquility in the soul! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Gentleness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/gentleness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/gentleness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/gentleness/david-clode-13PjNBaDMcg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Gentleness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most Christlike response we can give to an angry, frustrated, hostile, hurting world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; gentleness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to note about the fruit of the Spirit is that there is only one fruit (“the fruit of the Spirit &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip;”), and that fruit has nine characteristics. I may take nine weeks over this, let&amp;rsquo;s see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But gentleness? Why do I start here? Let&amp;rsquo;s notice what Paul wrote to Timothy, his final urging in his first letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, man of God, flee from all this [false teaching and the love of money], and pursue righteousness, godliness, faith, love, endurance and gentleness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 6:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timothy, still young, was just starting out in ministry, but was already held in high regard by Paul, who was particularly fond of him (1 Cor 4:17; 2 Tim 1:2; Phil 2:20-22). What would we write to such a one? If we&amp;rsquo;re honest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem a little surprising to see gentleness in that list of other more obvious qualities? It must be more important than we thought!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, in his final exhortations to the Philippians:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice! Let your gentleness be evident to all. The Lord is near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is near, and what is the thing that really matters (besides rejoicing)? Our &lt;em&gt;gentleness&lt;/em&gt;. We see this in Jesus himself. How prominently is his gentleness described, both in prophecy, and by and of himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice greatly, O Daughter of Zion! Shout, Daughter of Jerusalem! See, your king comes to you, righteous and having salvation, gentle and riding on a donkey, on a colt, the foal of a donkey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/zechariah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zechariah 9:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A bruised reed he will not break, and a smouldering wick he will not snuff out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 42:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Come to me, all you who are weary and burdened, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you and learn from me, for I am gentle and humble in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. For my yoke is easy and my burden is light.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 11:28-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In gentleness and humility, Jesus offers a haven for the weary and burdened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the pressure cooker of this life, Amy, live with the gentleness of Christ! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The rescued life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 06:28:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-rescued-life/kyle-cottrell-QGSD-bfJHIw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The rescued life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference does it make to have been rescued?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycling back from Karitane on Sunday afternoon, I saw my neighbours walking up the hill and stopped to say hello. They asked about the awful thing that happened to me in Rarotonga. Word evidently gets around! Instead I told them about the wonderful, impossible thing which happened, which resulted in me being alive and not dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found myself saying, “every day feels like a bonus now.” And so it is. But this principle applies equally to the original rescue, the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saved each one of us from our sin and brought us into relationship with our Heavenly Father in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live as those rescued? We need to understand what has changed, and so experience each waking moment as a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You are not your own; you were bought at a price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 6:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rescue changes everything! Recognizing that we now belong to the one who rescued us and our lives are no longer our own, may we surrender joyfully to the Holy Spirit, live as slaves to righteousness, and know the complete life-transformation that brings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness and self-control. Against such things there is no law. Those who belong to Christ Jesus have crucified the sinful nature with its passions and desires. Since we live by the Spirit, let us keep in step with the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This crucifying of the sinful nature sounds like a one-time thing, but is in fact a lifelong journey. May we travel it with grateful hearts, never forgetting the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in step with the Spirit, Amy, and continue to live as one rescued! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/jonny-james-TE0leJlNX8Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Filled with the knowledge of his will" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
