<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fruit on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/fruit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fruit on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/fruit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrity and uprightness</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can goodness protect us?
 The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; goodness
― Galatians 5:22 The Greek word is agathōsunē, which can be translated uprightness of heart and life.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look briefly again into Psalm 25 (what a jewel of a psalm that is!), where David writes with such humility, so aware of his own shortcomings and his desire to live a life of integrity, honouring the Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindness</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/kindness/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is one of the most important considerations when engaging with someone in a difficult conversation? When everything within you wants to make your point, to justify yourself with great vigour? When you have waited for so long and the time is now?
 The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; kindness
― Galatians 5:22 How easy this is to overlook. Could I be overstating its importance though? I think not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tranquility in the soul</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we know real peace?
 The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; peace
― Galatians 5:22 Peace here is the Greek word eirene, which corresponds to the Hebrew word shalom, and could be translated as tranquility in the soul. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want such a thing? But how can we possibly know such a peace in the turbulent and warmongering world in which we live?
Psalm 46 provides insight, and is worth reading in its entirety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentleness</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/gentleness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/gentleness/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is the most Christlike response we can give to an angry, frustrated, hostile, hurting world?
 The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; gentleness
― Galatians 5:22-23 The first thing to note about the fruit of the Spirit is that there is only one fruit (“the fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip;”), and that fruit has nine characteristics. I may take nine weeks over this, let&amp;rsquo;s see!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
