<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>weariness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/weariness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in weariness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 06:15:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/weariness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The work which brings us rest</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-work-which-brings-us-rest/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 06:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-work-which-brings-us-rest/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-work-which-brings-us-rest/otto-gonzalez-LC36d0gmte8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The work which brings us rest" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does weariness come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t mean that state of emptiness and exhaustion which I wrote about previously, where we find we have absolutely nothing left in the tank. At those times we critically need the Lord&amp;rsquo;s grace and kindness and healing and restoration⸺which he is truly so ready to provide. Instead for now I mean to address those times when things are tending to get on top of us in a smaller way, when nevertheless so much of what we have to do is a trial, when everything seems unreasonably harder than it ought, when life itself has become really quite wearying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus spoke into this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Come to me, all who labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you, and learn from me, for I am gentle and lowly in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 11:28-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These words are so very familiar, and yet at the same time counter-intuitive. Why is it that our rest is found in other work, in taking his yoke upon us? Couldn&amp;rsquo;t we just, well, rest?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if by rest we mean doing nothing in particular, that is not in itself refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a major source of weariness: those many things in life that we are tempted to approach with the mindset that we can influence, that we know what to do, that we can engineer our desired outcome, for which we have our own agenda. Frustratingly though, such things are so often beyond us. Such thinking is utterly wearying and we must give it over to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, what is Jesus&amp;rsquo; work for us? To live with humility, surrendered to the Father&amp;rsquo;s will, to &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; plans and purposes, pursuing love and holiness, caring for the outcast and the brokenhearted, bringing gentleness and kindness and light and grace and hope. This is the work that brings rest to our souls. And let&amp;rsquo;s notice that a yoke is fastened over the necks of &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; animals. Jesus himself walks alongside us in this work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Which commandment is the most important of all?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus answered, “The most important is, ‘Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. And you shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength.’ The second is this: ‘You shall love your neighbour as yourself.’ There is no other commandment greater than these.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 12:28b-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love the Lord with all your heart, soul, mind, and strength, Amy, and love your neighbour as yourself, and leave the rest to him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Running with perseverance</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/cameron-venti-I1EWTM5mFEM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Running with perseverance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a long race to run. How will we not grow weary and lose heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews tells us exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us. Let us fix our eyes on Jesus, the author and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy set before him endured the cross, scorning its shame, and sat down at the right hand of the throne of God. Consider him who endured such opposition from sinful men, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? By fixing our eyes on Jesus and considering him. Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack that a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running is hard and I get tired, but by fixing my eyes on Jesus one thing is sure. I will be running towards him, always. He is the author of my story, the author of my faith, the reason that I live and the reason that I live in him. He is also the perfecter (that is completer) of my faith, sustaining me so that I can finish the race. I will not fall because &amp;hellip; Jesus. Because of all that he is and all that he has done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did he do all this? He endured such opposition from sinful men⸺those he had come to save no less! He endured the pain and humiliation of the cross, and the real agony of it all: separation from the Father. But why? Why did he do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are told why he did it and how he endured: &lt;em&gt;for the joy set before him&lt;/em&gt;. And what was that joy? That joy was the knowledge that he was saving you and me, Amy. That was what gave him the strength to endure the unendurable. That was his joy. His love for you and his love for me, and saving you and saving me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that! Consider him! How loved we are! How comprehensive Jesus&amp;rsquo; victory! How wonderful his love!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider him, Amy, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Gentleness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/gentleness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/gentleness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/gentleness/david-clode-13PjNBaDMcg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Gentleness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most Christlike response we can give to an angry, frustrated, hostile, hurting world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; gentleness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to note about the fruit of the Spirit is that there is only one fruit (“the fruit of the Spirit &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip;”), and that fruit has nine characteristics. I may take nine weeks over this, let&amp;rsquo;s see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But gentleness? Why do I start here? Let&amp;rsquo;s notice what Paul wrote to Timothy, his final urging in his first letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, man of God, flee from all this [false teaching and the love of money], and pursue righteousness, godliness, faith, love, endurance and gentleness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 6:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timothy, still young, was just starting out in ministry, but was already held in high regard by Paul, who was particularly fond of him (1 Cor 4:17; 2 Tim 1:2; Phil 2:20-22). What would we write to such a one? If we&amp;rsquo;re honest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem a little surprising to see gentleness in that list of other more obvious qualities? It must be more important than we thought!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, in his final exhortations to the Philippians:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice! Let your gentleness be evident to all. The Lord is near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is near, and what is the thing that really matters (besides rejoicing)? Our &lt;em&gt;gentleness&lt;/em&gt;. We see this in Jesus himself. How prominently is his gentleness described, both in prophecy, and by and of himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice greatly, O Daughter of Zion! Shout, Daughter of Jerusalem! See, your king comes to you, righteous and having salvation, gentle and riding on a donkey, on a colt, the foal of a donkey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/zechariah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zechariah 9:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A bruised reed he will not break, and a smouldering wick he will not snuff out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 42:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Come to me, all you who are weary and burdened, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you and learn from me, for I am gentle and humble in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. For my yoke is easy and my burden is light.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 11:28-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In gentleness and humility, Jesus offers a haven for the weary and burdened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the pressure cooker of this life, Amy, live with the gentleness of Christ! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Who am I?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/spencer-tamichi-bjH4uE6iuEo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Who am I?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a vital question that is for any of us. It could take some time to answer! In fact, I have had to revisit it myself in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valiant attempt I know of to grapple with this is by Dietrich Bonhoeffer, a German pastor who was imprisoned in Flossenbürg concentration camp by the Nazis during World War II. He was executed just one month before the end of the war. One month! He wrote the following while incarcerated. Notice that someone we might regard as a giant in the faith did not regard himself like that at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Am I?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They often tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I stepped from my cell&amp;rsquo;s confinement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Calmly, cheerfully, firmly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Like a squire from his country house.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They often tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I used to speak to my warders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Freely and friendly and clearly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As though it were mine to command.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They also tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I bore the days of misfortune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Equably, smilingly, proudly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;like one accustomed to win.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Am I then really that which other men tell of?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Or am I only what I myself know of myself?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Restless and longing and sick, like a bird in a cage,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Struggling for breath, as though hands were compressing my throat,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yearning for colours, for flowers, for the voices of birds,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Thirsting for words of kindness, for neighbourliness,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tossing in expectations of great events,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powerlessly trembling for friends at an infinite distance,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Weary and empty at praying, at thinking, at making,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Faint, and ready to say farewell to it all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? This or the other?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Am I one person today and tomorrow another?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Am I both at once? A hypocrite before others,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And before myself a contemptible woebegone weakling?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Or is something within me still like a beaten army&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fleeing in disorder from victory already achieved?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They mock me, these lonely questions of mine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Whoever I am, Thou knowest, O God, I am thine!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What courageously honest words, from someone facing the ultimate test of faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, while you continue to work out the rest 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
