<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>approval on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/approval/</link>
        <description>Recent content in approval on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 06:24:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/approval/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A labour of love for the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-labour-of-love-for-the-lord/loren-joseph-11eY-tkB9VU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A labour of love for the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you return to the village for another year of serving the Lord, know that he sees all that you do and all that you are with such approval, smiling down on you like the proud father that he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul evidently had a particular fondness for and bond with the Thessalonians. You can see it in his writing, in the phrases he uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, then, brothers and sisters, we ask and urge you in the Lord Jesus, that as you received from us how you ought to walk and to please God, just as you are doing, that you do so more and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 4:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He urges them to continue to live their lives in a way which pleases God, &lt;em&gt;just as they were doing&lt;/em&gt;. Just as &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;  are doing, Amy, and to do this more and more. And what do we know of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to God always for all of you, constantly mentioning you in our prayers, remembering before our God and Father your work of faith and labour of love and steadfastness of hope in our Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; for you received the word in much affliction, with the joy of the Holy Spirit, so that you became an example to all the believers in Macedonia and in Achaia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 1:2-3, 6b-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul had noticed their work of faith and labour of love and steadfastness of hope in Jesus, and so had the Lord, and it pleased him. And neither of them had failed to notice the affliction they endured, quite how hard it was for them to live like this, and that they did it with the joy of the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has surely not failed to notice how hard it has been for you, Amy, and how you have lived with the joy of the Holy Spirit, honouring him, an example to all the believers in Dunedin City Baptist Church and beyond. Well done indeed! We give thanks to God for you, constantly remembering you in &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt;  prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look up and see with the eyes of your heart our loving Heavenly Father taking so much joy and delight in you, Amy, gently nudging Jesus in the ribs and saying, “Look at our daughter, how she lives!” 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Symphony of Life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/jack-finnigan-aEkk0KxvPpg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Symphony of Life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when we pray? Can we actually change the Lord&amp;rsquo;s mind? How could we possibly improve upon his already perfect plans and purposes? Why even ask for anything in prayer then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are huge questions, and I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly answer them adequately. But here&amp;rsquo;s a reflection on this, somewhat of an excursion into make-believe, which nevertheless may help to shed some light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, note that we are encouraged, nay commanded to pray, and to pray boldly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pray continually&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If you believe, you will receive whatever you ask for in prayer.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 21:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine then. The Lord who created music has himself written the greatest work of all, the Symphony of Life, in 8 billion parts. He is both the composer, and the conductor for its debut and only performance. It is a glorious, majestic work featuring players both unwilling and willing, with plunging depths and soaring heights, human folly and heavenly beneficence, sorrow and joy.  It is a love story, the greatest of them all, a story of rescue and redemption of a wayward people, pieced together from fragments of ruined lives made whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the billions of orchestral members play their parts with quite some improvising, the Lord hears the prayers of the saints, our prayers, and delights to weave them in to the score, making amendments and annotations with his divine pencil even as the music unfolds, taking our imperfect petitions and making them part of his perfect plans and purposes, as it pleases him. And with each, smiling down on his beloved ones with such affection, like a proud father. Smiling on us, who are contributing somehow to his glorious work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at the mystery of his ways, Amy, praising the Lord for his majesty, grace and kindness, and continue praying Kingdom prayers! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
