<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>shame on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/shame/</link>
        <description>Recent content in shame on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/shame/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Humiliation and grace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/humiliation-and-grace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/humiliation-and-grace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/humiliation-and-grace/alwi-alaydrus-G7eGlBfJDtc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Humiliation and grace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from Matthew&amp;rsquo;s shaming and humiliation of David in his genealogy? Why is he so harsh? And is there any grace to be found here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book of the genealogy of Jesus Christ, the son of David, the son of Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and Salmon the father of Boaz by Rahab, and Boaz the father of Obed by Ruth, and Obed the father of Jesse, and Jesse the father of David the king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And David was the father of Solomon by the wife of Uriah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 1:1, 5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the humiliation⸺David&amp;rsquo;s shameful failure recorded here for all time. Notice that Bathsheba is identified but not named. Unlike Rahab and Ruth, those outsiders extraordinarily honoured by being named here, her inclusion in the genealogy isn&amp;rsquo;t remotely about her. It is in fact all about David, and it&amp;rsquo;s all about his most shameful failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was chosen by God to be king, anointed by Samuel, and blessed by the Spirit (1 Sam 16:12-13). He was the slayer of Goliath, the Philistine champion who taunted the Israelites and defied the Lord (1 Sam 17). With humility and a grateful heart he acknowledged the greatness and kindness of the Lord (2 Sam 7), and experienced victory through him (2 Sam 8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then it all went horribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the spring of the year, the time when kings go out to battle, David sent Joab, and his servants with him, and all Israel. And they ravaged the Ammonites and besieged Rabbah. But David remained at Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened, late one afternoon, when David arose from his couch and was walking on the roof of the king&amp;rsquo;s house, that he saw from the roof a woman bathing; and the woman was very beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Samuel 11:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know the rest. David lusted after Bathsheba, committed adultery with her, and made her pregnant. He called her husband Uriah back from battle (where he himself should have been) and tried to get him to go home and sleep with his wife. After failing to trick that honourable man into covering his own dishonourable act, he had him murdered, and he took Bathsheba as his own wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But the thing that David had done displeased the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Samuel 11:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a sobering story for anyone who thinks at all highly of themselves. Anyone so self-satisfied in their naivety and self-deception and complacency as to regard themselves as secure from falling. What a solemn warning for us all! But isn&amp;rsquo;t this exactly why Matthew makes reference to this shameful deed in his genealogy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which of us can say we are as sold-out for the Lord as was David? Which of us has so trusted the Lord as to go up for him armed with only with a sling and five smooth stones against a nine foot giant wearing bronze armour and bearing a huge spear? Which of us has lived such a life for the Lord as his?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, we are each as prone to shameful failure as was David. It is in our sinful nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For there is no distinction: for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where is the grace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right there in the very first verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The book of the genealogy of Jesus Christ, the son of David, the son of Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 1:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus identifies with such sinners as David, and with such sinners as us. See how David is honoured in this first verse. And we are honoured by Jesus&amp;rsquo; oh so costly choice to die for each one of us. He counted us worthy. He counts us worthy. It is so humbling! I weep in gratitude to my Lord and Saviour!  This gratitude together with the power of the indwelling Spirit keep me from falling.  Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s grace is more than our most shameful failures. David shows us that. Matthew shows us. And Jesus shows us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, Amy, that his grace is more than enough! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Two kinds of sorrow</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/brahm-meyer-xwG9LGmc1Qk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two kinds of sorrow" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can sorrow ever be a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What of this, that Paul writes to the Corinthians?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even if I caused you sorrow by my letter, I do not regret it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Paul somehow pleased with himself because he stuck it to those wretched Corinthians in his first letter? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet now I am happy, not because you were made sorry, but because your sorrow led you to repentance. For you became sorrowful as God intended and so were not harmed in any way by us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their sorrow was as God intended and led to repentance. This is Godly sorrow, and the Lord uses it to expose sin in our lives to bring repentance and healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I weep over the shame and failure in my life and cry out to the Lord, this also is Godly sorrow, a gift of love from my Heavenly Father, received through the conviction that comes by the Holy Spirit. It drives me into the arms of my loving Heavenly Father, from shame to repentance and forgiveness and healing, and is, through the healing, eventually and ultimately, a cause for rejoicing in my wonderful Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we must beware. There is another sorrow which leads to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Godly sorrow brings repentance that leads to salvation and leaves no regret, but worldly sorrow brings death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldly sorrow is what I experience out of a sense of entitlement, a sense of “it&amp;rsquo;s not fair”, an inclination to blame God for all that&amp;rsquo;s wrong in my life. It is self-indulgent and self-pitying and full of regret. This drives me away from my loving Heavenly Father and brings death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two are so very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with your sorrow into the arms of your loving Heavenly Father, Amy, and receive healing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Casting off shame</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/allef-vinicius-oe_03B2Q5A4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Casting off shame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what we do about ourselves, how can we possibly hold our head high?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David had a similar problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was chosen by the Lord because he was a man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart (1 Samuel 13:14). He earnestly sought the Lord and wrote many of the psalms which have blessed the generations.  But let us not make the mistake of thinking that he was a righteous man. His later life was in fact a catalogue of failure and shame, culminating in his most shabby and shameful moral failure, committing adultery with Bathsheba and murdering her husband Uriah the Hittite (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, David wrote Psalm 3 when he was being pursued by his son Absalom, who was trying to kill him and seize control of the kingdom. What greater failure as a father could there be than that? How utterly shameful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet we read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, LORD, are a shield around me, my glory, the One who lifts my head high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was so aware that he had no glory of his own. He had only shame. But the Lord himself was his glory, and not only the reason that he could hold his head high, but the one who actually lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course, this in no way diminishes the Lord&amp;rsquo;s condemnation of sin in one&amp;rsquo;s life. David was severely rebuked by the Lord after his wretched doings with Bathsheba. Repentance was very necessary. Forgiveness followed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. The nearer we draw to God and the more we focus on personal holiness, the more aware we become of our own failure and shame, all those reasons Christ died on the cross. We own those reasons. And yet, the Lord is my glory, the lifter of my head. Yours too, Amy! He chose us in him to be holy and blameless in his sight, and he will achieve his purposes. In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins. Cast off the shame. He alone is my glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold your head high, Amy, and know that the Lord himself is your glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The thorn in Paul&#39;s flesh</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/jacqueline-day-krUUaZ4GvHk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The thorn in Paul&#39;s flesh" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly was Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn anyway, and why does it matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been much speculation about the nature of Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn in the flesh (2 Cor 12:7-9), and of course we do not know.  Personally, I doubt it was any disability, of speech or of stature, nor any severe pain to endure. Rather I suspect it was something utterly shameful and humiliating, perhaps something in his own character. Something internal and deeply personal. Why do I think this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every other respect, Paul was the elite. Highly educated. Highly disciplined. Highly capable. Zealous. Purging every sin and making every effort to live a right life (Acts 22:3, Phil 3:4-6). These are not attributes that lead to humility! They are more likely to lead to arrogance, to smug self-satisfaction, to a sense of moral superiority. How can such a one be depending completely on the Lord, and be of any use in the Kingdom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul rather was able to live with so much humility and dependence on the Lord &lt;em&gt;because of this&lt;/em&gt; (“in order to keep me from becoming conceited”, 2 Cor 12:7), being able to say, “Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners⸺of whom I am the worst” (1 Tim 1:15). And to live with boldness. Such boldness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the shame of my past comes back to haunt me, to crush me, I do not deny it. I must not. The Lord lifts me, welcomes me, saves me, accepts me. Oh how I need him! I am not condemned. But in the rescue and the redemption, all pride is gone. My grateful heart loves the Lord, and seeks to honour him. And so I can live with levels of humility, gentleness and compassion which eluded me previously. The Lord is glorified, and I am diminished. I can die to self, and live for him, holding nothing back. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the rescue, Amy, whatever form it takes! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
