<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>goodness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/goodness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in goodness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 08:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/goodness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The goodness of God</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-goodness-of-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 08:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-goodness-of-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-goodness-of-god/simon-reza-jQhgDnovqhw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The goodness of God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that the living God, sovereign creator of the universe and Lord of all creation, terrifying in purity and holiness, a consuming fire, should be quite so very good and kind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had no right to expect that, did we? And yet that&amp;rsquo;s how it is. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just see if we can gain some insight into the astonishing goodness of God. For there is something here which may not be well understood and may in fact be slightly uncomfortable. Let the psalmist explain, as we listen in on him speaking with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You are good and do good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:68a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the heart of it, acknowledging the unconditional goodness of God. It is his very nature. Now let&amp;rsquo;s consider that in the context of the rest of what the psalmist is saying. Here&amp;rsquo;s the whole stanza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have dealt well with your servant, O LORD, according to your word. Teach me good judgment and knowledge, for I believe in your commandments. Before I was afflicted I went astray, but now I keep your word. You are good and do good; teach me your statutes. The insolent smear me with lies, but with my whole heart I keep your precepts; their heart is unfeeling like fat, but I delight in your law. It is good for me that I was afflicted, that I might learn your statutes. The law of your mouth is better to me than thousands of gold and silver pieces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:65-72&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist declares that the Lord has dealt well with him. And then we see his heartfelt cry to the Lord to teach him good judgment and knowledge. Why is this so necessary? Because as he continues we see something surprising and really quite uncomfortable. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s goodness is being outworked here through affliction. We must not fail to notice this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before I was afflicted I went astray, but now I keep your word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is good for me that I was afflicted, that I might learn your statutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:67, 71&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And somehow this is good. How can it be good for him to be afflicted? Notice that his acknowledgement of this is in immediate juxtaposition to his assertion of the goodness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth asking what is the nature of this affliction? We do not know what it comprises but if we look ahead we can determine its source and it is not what we might expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I know, O LORD, that your rules are righteous, and that in faithfulness you have afflicted me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:75&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is asserting with great determination the goodness of God and his righteousness. And that it is the Lord himself who is the source of his affliction. How are we to understand this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to remind ourselves of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s big picture plan for our lives, both now and especially in that time of affliction which may come, unsolicited and frankly unwelcome. But we can learn from the psalmist how we must respond to such. The psalmist&amp;rsquo;s reward is increased love for the Lord and greater understanding of his goodness and somehow an ability to keep his precepts with his whole heart. What a reward! What a gift! The gift is received through affliction and yet it is such a gift of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to keep you from stumbling and to present you blameless before the presence of his glory with great joy, to the only God, our Saviour, through Jesus Christ our Lord, be glory, majesty, dominion, and authority, before all time and now and forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/jude&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude 24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans and purposes are not for our comfort and ease. Not remotely so! He has a much higher purpose, and it is for our ultimate good. If we are able to grasp this it is ultimately joyous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we to do in response to this understanding? Simply trust and obey and surrender our will and all of our hopes and dreams to the one who is unfathomably good and kind⸺Jesus, the lover of our souls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that the Lord is so very good and kind, Amy, in whatever you may be experiencing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Integrity and uprightness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/chris-brignola-X2CxUXFqKcM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Integrity and uprightness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can goodness protect us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; goodness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greek word is &lt;em&gt;agathōsunē&lt;/em&gt;, which can be translated &lt;em&gt;uprightness of heart and life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look briefly again into Psalm 25 (what a jewel of a psalm that is!), where David writes with such humility, so aware of his own shortcomings and his desire to live a life of integrity, honouring the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect me, because my hope is in you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see protection there, but how does that work? Before we get to that, read the whole psalm and notice that there is not a shred of smug self-satisfaction as David seeks with all his heart to honour the Lord and live a right life. Paul also writes of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must seek with our whole heart to live as slaves to righteousness, purging every wrong thought and deed, pouring ourselves out in humility and gratitude to the Lord. The Holy Spirit enables us to do this. It is a miracle of grace that sinners such as we are, even forgiven sinners, can live with such integrity and uprightness, evidence in our own lives of the victory Jesus won on the cross. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we live with humility as slaves to righteousness, continuing to be sanctified by the Holy Spirit, integrity and uprightness keep us on the narrow path that leads to life, and it is this that protects us. The process is ongoing, and so is the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect you, Amy, as you live as a slave to righteousness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Taste and see that the Lord is good</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/joyful-vT5xrj3z1OE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taste and see that the Lord is good" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we obey a command if we don&amp;rsquo;t know what it means?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously we can&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s a rhetorical question. What of this then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Taste and see that the LORD is good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is clearly an instruction to do something. It&amp;rsquo;s a command. Notice that David could have written, Behold! The Lord is good (because he is). That&amp;rsquo;s a true statement, but it&amp;rsquo;s not what he wrote. What he wrote, rather, is something we are commanded to do. Taste! And see! Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasting is an action. There is something to do. Physically, we put food in our mouths and chew on it. As an aside, how gracious of the Lord to make this a pleasurable experience. We are really just refueling our bodies. Who else would have decided to make that something to enjoy? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s character is revealed even in this, that he found yet another way to bless us, his beloved. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us some insight. We experience the goodness of God as a result of taking some action. What action is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that more than any other the word that appears alongside the goodness of God throughout scripture is &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt;, that those who would see his goodness must trust, in his unfailing love, in his mercy, in all he is and all he has done. Grab a concordance and see for yourself! This very verse continues “blessed is the one who takes refuge in him”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we would taste and see, we must then &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;depend&lt;/em&gt;. This makes sense. When we fully commit to depending on the Lord, such that we are not trying to control our own outcome, only then may we see the goodness of God, because only then have we left him space in which to show us that goodness. As we relinquish control over our own lives, may we learn to chew on and genuinely savour the goodness of God that he reveals to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust and depend, Amy, taste and see, and leave the Lord space to show you his goodness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
