<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>goodness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/goodness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in goodness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/goodness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Integrity and uprightness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/chris-brignola-X2CxUXFqKcM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Integrity and uprightness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can goodness protect us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; goodness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greek word is &lt;em&gt;agathōsunē&lt;/em&gt;, which can be translated &lt;em&gt;uprightness of heart and life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look briefly again into Psalm 25 (what a jewel of a psalm that is!), where David writes with such humility, so aware of his own shortcomings and his desire to live a life of integrity, honouring the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect me, because my hope is in you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see protection there, but how does that work? Before we get to that, read the whole psalm and notice that there is not a shred of smug self-satisfaction as David seeks with all his heart to honour the Lord and live a right life. Paul also writes of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must seek with our whole heart to live as slaves to righteousness, purging every wrong thought and deed, pouring ourselves out in humility and gratitude to the Lord. The Holy Spirit enables us to do this. It is a miracle of grace that sinners such as we are, even forgiven sinners, can live with such integrity and uprightness, evidence in our own lives of the victory Jesus won on the cross. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we live with humility as slaves to righteousness, continuing to be sanctified by the Holy Spirit, integrity and uprightness keep us on the narrow path that leads to life, and it is this that protects us. The process is ongoing, and so is the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect you, Amy, as you live as a slave to righteousness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
