<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>power on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/power/</link>
        <description>Recent content in power on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The words we speak</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-words-we-speak/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-words-we-speak/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-words-we-speak/muhammed-nishal-qCoXBXCJcFU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The words we speak" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important are the words we speak?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reflecting again on that awesome vision of the apostle John of the throne room of heaven, and it reminded me of another time the Lord was seen seated on a throne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the year that King Uzziah died I saw the Lord sitting upon a throne, high and lifted up; and the train of his robe filled the temple.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Isaiah so far make this sound rather matter-of-fact, even commonplace? In fact it was nothing of the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Above him stood the seraphim. Each had six wings: with two he covered his face, and with two he covered his feet, and with two he flew. And one called to another and said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Holy, holy, holy is the LORD of hosts; the whole earth is full of his glory!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the foundations of the thresholds shook at the voice of him who called, and the house was filled with smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So mighty was the voice of that single seraph that it shook the very foundations of the temple. This was nothing commonplace at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s response is revealing. We would do well to pay attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I said: “Woe is me! For I am lost; for I am a man of unclean lips, and I dwell in the midst of a people of unclean lips; for my eyes have seen the King, the LORD of hosts!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How interesting. Of all the things about which Isaiah could have been convicted, of all his failures and shortcomings exposed before the Lord of hosts, he knew his doom was sealed by his unclean lips, by the words he had spoken⸺and the words of the people amongst whom he lived, their words also condemned him. His own sin was not excused by the sin of those around him. Rather their sin compounded his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our words matter to an extent that may be difficult to grasp. They carry great power⸺power to heal or power to destroy. Remember that each one of us is made in the image of the living God, the living God who, infinite in power and awesome in splendour and majesty, simply spoke the universe into existence. Words matter. Jesus said as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“For out of the abundance of the heart the mouth speaks. The good person out of his good treasure brings forth good, and the evil person out of his evil treasure brings forth evil. I tell you, on the day of judgment people will give account for every careless word they speak, for by your words you will be justified, and by your words you will be condemned.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 12:34-37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How words matter⸺and Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s words condemned him. In the presence of the holy, holy, holy Lord of hosts, he knew he was a man of unclean lips, and he was undone. He so needed what came next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then one of the seraphim flew to me, having in his hand a burning coal that he had taken with tongs from the altar. And he touched my mouth and said: “Behold, this has touched your lips; your guilt is taken away, and your sin atoned for.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How powerful are the words we speak, for good or for evil. And how we ourselves need to be saved from our own shortcomings in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But what does it say? “The word is near you, in your mouth and in your heart” (that is, the word of faith that we proclaim); because, if you confess with your mouth that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. For with the heart one believes and is justified, and with the mouth one confesses and is saved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 10:8-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise our wonderful Saviour who can rescue from words spoken foolishly or even with malice. We must repent, receive forgiveness, and know that just like Isaiah, our guilt is taken away and our sin atoned for. And then we can speak with great power for good and for healing and for the furtherance of the Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speak with great power out of the good treasure that the Lord has put in your heart, Amy, and praise him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The God of Jacob</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-jacob/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 08:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-jacob/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-jacob/fernando-paredes-murillo-Xc6gtOwSMSA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The God of Jacob" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is your least favourite Bible character?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the kings of Israel were thoroughly wicked, and Jezebel was an absolute shocker, evil beyond imagining, but for me there is one who stands out, a truly vile and revolting little man: Jacob.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacob was a man without integrity. Even his name means “he cheats”. He manipulated his starving brother Esau to give up the birthright to him. He tricked his aging, blind father to give him the blessing that was due to Esau, lying brazenly even as he was receiving it. His household was defined by immorality and unfaithfulness, as he fathered children through each and every one of Leah, Rachel, and the two servant girls Bilhah and Zilpah. He stole Laban&amp;rsquo;s livestock through a dirty little scheme of corrupting their breeding process, after which he ran away. And years later, when Esau had graciously forgiven him and was offering an emotional reconciliation (revealing the noble heart his brother lacked) Jacob still continued with his tricks and lies. What a despicable little man he was (Genesis 25-33).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all this what then happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God appeared to Jacob again, when he came from Paddan-aram, and blessed him. And God said to him, “Your name is Jacob; no longer shall your name be called Jacob, but Israel shall be your name.” So he called his name Israel. And God said to him, “I am God Almighty: be fruitful and multiply. A nation and a company of nations shall come from you, and kings shall come from your own body. The land that I gave to Abraham and Isaac I will give to you, and I will give the land to your offspring after you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 35:9-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this simply astonishing? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s covenant promise to Abraham, that man of great faith, was continued through this despicable little man. Is the Lord such a terrible judge of character that he made a rather poor choice here? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the key to understanding this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God chose what is foolish in the world to shame the wise; God chose what is weak in the world to shame the strong; God chose what is low and despised in the world, even things that are not, to bring to nothing things that are, so that no human being might boast in the presence of God. And because of him you are in Christ Jesus, who became to us wisdom from God, righteousness and sanctification and redemption, so that, as it is written, “Let the one who boasts, boast in the Lord.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 1:27-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would do well to remember this. The Lord demonstrated his sovereign power through Jacob, that despicable little man, and he continues to demonstrate it through us, in all of our foolishness and weakness and nothingness. Because of him we are in Christ Jesus. Let us boast in him, our righteousness and sanctification and redemption!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursue love and holiness, Amy, and leave it to the Lord to work out how he will achieve his Kingdom plans and purposes! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiving others</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/madhu-shesharam-KQZZCVyEWVk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving others" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we forgive those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the how, let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge that we must. This is not optional, it is commanded by Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If your brother or sister sins, rebuke them; and if they repent, forgive them. Even if they sin against you seven times in a day and seven times come back to you saying &amp;lsquo;I repent&amp;rsquo;, you must forgive them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am facing a situation in which this is a real challenge. The response I received to my articulated desire for reconciliation and relationship and mutual forgiveness and healing was a crushing and callous brush-off. What now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first attempt to forgive was a false start. I tried to diminish the magnitude of the offence, to find a way to receive it as a simple misunderstanding, to excuse the other&amp;rsquo;s behaviour. This failed because there was no truth in it. The behaviour was in fact wretched and reprehensible. I cannot deny it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then had to grapple with “if they repent”. In my situation, there is no repentance. There is stubborn and Pharisaical judgment and rejection, and refusal to engage in authentic relationship. It is crushing. Heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some writers have tried to argue that the requirement to forgive is conditional on repentance, and in this passage it indeed appears so. Is that the whole story though? I think not. But let&amp;rsquo;s not resort to a human argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this from the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer, and what Jesus said next in the Sermon on the Mount:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you forgive others when they sin against you, your heavenly Father will also forgive you. But if you do not forgive others their sins, your Father will not forgive your sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:12, 14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here our forgiveness of others is linked to God&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness of us no less. How vital then is it to forgive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When they came to the place called the Skull, there they crucified him, along with the criminals⸺one on his right, the other on his left. Jesus said, “Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they are doing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 23:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was there repentance here? Of course not! How are we called to live? Like Christ! And how can we find the power to do this? Only in him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I must die to self, again. But as I do, I find I am being transformed into Christ&amp;rsquo;s likeness. There is no greater joy, even in the midst of all this pain. The joy in that transformation is empowering indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lengthy process, an ongoing journey, and I am not yet done. May the Lord have mercy on that individual as I forgive, and continue to forgive, dying to self and becoming like Christ. And if they come to the point of repentance, may we be restored in authentic relationship again, by Christ&amp;rsquo;s power and for his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like Christ, Amy, in him and by his power and for his glory, fuelled by the joy in your own transformation! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The master craftsman</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/jonny-gios-KGL7Rw_-YPY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The master craftsman" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be completely confident in surrendering to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we retain some level of control? What might he do in our lives, by the Holy Spirit unleashed with power and authority? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it just all too scary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me ask a different question which may provide some insight. If I invite the Spirit into my situation, into my life, how can I be sure he will do what I am hoping for? What I want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many leave this question unstated, and yet it remains in their subconscious, in the background, undermining confidence in the Lord and trust in him. But it must be articulated, because only then can we repudiate it. Of course he won&amp;rsquo;t do what I want! The very idea is preposterous! He will do his own work, the work that he knows so well, at which he is the master. So the better question to ask is, what is that work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already considered this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To him who is able to keep you from falling and to present you before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy⸺to the only God our Saviour be glory, majesty, power and authority, through Jesus Christ our Lord, before all ages, now and for evermore! Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/jude&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude v24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work is to keep us from falling and to present us before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy.  It is a heart work, where he transforms us from wretches, having the smallest, meanest, most selfish lives and motives, into sons and daughters, having abundance of life and joy in the Lord, living as slaves to righteousness, with hearts bursting with love for our Saviour and for our brothers and sisters in Christ. And he will do whatever it takes to achieve this purpose, no matter the cost, to him or to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who did not spare his own Son, but gave him up for us all⸺how will he not also, along with him, graciously give us all things?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not make the mistake as some have done, of thinking this means he will give us whatever we want. By no means! But he will give us whatever &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; wants, in pursuit of his goal for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrender joyfully, Amy, and trust the master craftsman who knows his work, who along with his own Son, will graciously give you all things! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The eyes of your heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:31:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/javardh-FC59Au36moM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The eyes of your heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the eyes of our heart for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still stuck on this desert island, reading Ephesians 1. It is not a bad place to be! Consider what Paul writes about the eyes of our heart. (The heart is the seat of life and strength, the centre of one&amp;rsquo;s will. That is mind, soul, spirit, one&amp;rsquo;s entire emotional nature and understanding.)  Paul writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I pray also that the eyes of your heart may be enlightened in order that you may know the hope to which he has called you, the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and his incomparably great power for us who believe. That power is like the working of his mighty strength, which he exerted in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a prayer. Paul asks for enlightening of the eyes of our heart. We must ask for this thing that otherwise we may miss. Notice that what the enlightened eyes of our heart do is to &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;. Merely seeing is curiosity. Knowing is life-changing. What is there to know? Three things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope. My dictionary defines hope as grounds for believing that something good may happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not wishful thinking, there are actual grounds for believing this. In our context, “something good” is understated, to say the least! May the enlightened eyes of our heart know the best thing that could possibly happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our glorious inheritance in the saints. What is this? In v3 Paul writes that the Lord “has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ”. Note the tense. Something has already happened! But what of the rest? The prophetic past tense is used throughout scripture where a future event is so certain it is written as if it had already occurred. The fulfilment of our future blessing in the heavenly realms is that certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His incomparably great power for us. This is the same power that raised Christ from the dead. It is not a small thing, and it is at work in us who believe! When we feel overwhelmed or empty, and so aware of our need for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and grace, perhaps his mighty strength which raised Christ from the dead will be enough. We must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the eyes of your heart be enlightened, Amy, in order that you may know, really know, these life changing things. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
