<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>power on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/power/</link>
        <description>Recent content in power on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The master craftsman</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-master-craftsman/jonny-gios-KGL7Rw_-YPY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The master craftsman" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be completely confident in surrendering to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we retain some level of control? What might he do in our lives, by the Holy Spirit unleashed with power and authority? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it just all too scary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me ask a different question which may provide some insight. If I invite the Spirit into my situation, into my life, how can I be sure he will do what I am hoping for? What I want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many leave this question unstated, and yet it remains in their subconscious, in the background, undermining confidence in the Lord and trust in him. But it must be articulated, because only then can we repudiate it. Of course he won&amp;rsquo;t do what I want! The very idea is preposterous! He will do his own work, the work that he knows so well, at which he is the master. So the better question to ask is, what is that work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already considered this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To him who is able to keep you from falling and to present you before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy—to the only God our Saviour be glory, majesty, power and authority, through Jesus Christ our Lord, before all ages, now and for evermore! Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work is to keep us from falling and to present us before his glorious presence without fault and with exceeding joy.  It is a heart work, where he transforms us from wretches, having the smallest, meanest, most selfish lives and motives, into sons and daughters, having abundance of life and joy in the Lord, living as slaves to righteousness, with hearts bursting with love for our Saviour and for our brothers and sisters in Christ. And he will do whatever it takes to achieve this purpose, no matter the cost, to him or to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who did not spare his own Son, but gave him up for us all—how will he not also, along with him, graciously give us all things?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not make the mistake as some have done, of thinking this means he will give us whatever we want. By no means! But he will give us whatever &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; wants, in pursuit of his goal for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrender joyfully, Amy, and trust the master craftsman who knows his work, who along with his own Son, will graciously give you all things! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The eyes of your heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:31:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/javardh-FC59Au36moM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The eyes of your heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the eyes of our heart for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still stuck on this desert island, reading Ephesians 1. It is not a bad place to be! Consider what Paul writes about the eyes of our heart. (The heart is the seat of life and strength, the centre of one&amp;rsquo;s will. That is mind, soul, spirit, one&amp;rsquo;s entire emotional nature and understanding.)  Paul writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I pray also that the eyes of your heart may be enlightened in order that you may know the hope to which he has called you, the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and his incomparably great power for us who believe. That power is like the working of his mighty strength, which he exerted in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a prayer. Paul asks for enlightening of the eyes of our heart. We must ask for this thing that otherwise we may miss. Notice that what the enlightened eyes of our heart do is to &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;. Merely seeing is curiosity. Knowing is life-changing. What is there to know? Three things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope. My dictionary defines hope as grounds for believing that something good may happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not wishful thinking, there are actual grounds for believing this. In our context, “something good” is understated, to say the least! May the enlightened eyes of our heart know the best thing that could possibly happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our glorious inheritance in the saints. What is this? In v3 Paul writes that the Lord “has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ”. Note the tense. Something has already happened! But what of the rest? The prophetic past tense is used throughout scripture where a future event is so certain it is written as if it had already occurred. The fulfillment of our future blessing in the heavenly realms is that certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His incomparably great power for us. This is the same power that raised Christ from the dead. It is not a small thing, and it is at work in us who believe! When we feel overwhelmed or empty, and so aware of our need for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and grace, perhaps his mighty strength which raised Christ from the dead will be enough. We must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the eyes of your heart be enlightened, Amy, in order that you may know, really know, these life changing things. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
