<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>humility on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/humility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in humility on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/humility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sacrifice</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is the turning point in the Easter story?
In fact there are two. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to the joyous second, but let&amp;rsquo;s not rush that. Now is the time to contemplate the mournful first.
I have been reading Mark&amp;rsquo;s account of the last days of Jesus&amp;rsquo; life, from the triumphal entry into Jerusalem up until his death on the cross (Mark 11-15). There&amp;rsquo;s much that happens, starting with Jesus clearing the temple, which had become a den of robbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking offence</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/taking-offence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/taking-offence/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is the world&amp;rsquo;s favourite pastime?
What is it that people love to do? That the whole media machine is geared up to deliver? At which society has become so very accomplished? Here&amp;rsquo;s what: taking offence.
Taking offence — human nature delights in it, Christians too at times, sadly. We love to be outraged. It is almost tribal. People bond over it, which means that people also divide over it, for there is always a source of the offence, and that source is surely a person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A life worthy of our calling</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-life-worthy-of-our-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-life-worthy-of-our-calling/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How important is it to read a verse in context?
Paul writes this to the Ephesians.
 I urge you to live a life worthy of the calling you have received.
― Ephesians 4:1 I also want to live such a life! What exactly should I do then? Er &amp;hellip; live honourably, behave well, be kind to strangers, help old ladies across the street? Is this what Paul means?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relational authenticity</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is the most important thing?
 The fruit of the Spirit is love &amp;hellip;
― Galatians 5:22 I&amp;rsquo;ve left this one until last, precisely because it is the most important. Why do I say that? So many reasons, starting with this.
 “Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?”
Jesus replied: “&amp;lsquo;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The thorn in Paul&#39;s flesh</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What exactly was Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn anyway, and why does it matter?
There has been much speculation about the nature of Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn in the flesh (2 Cor 12:7-9), and of course we do not know. Personally, I doubt it was any disability, of speech or of stature, nor any severe pain to endure. Rather I suspect it was something utterly shameful and humiliating, perhaps something in his own character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On being vulnerable</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/on-being-vulnerable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/on-being-vulnerable/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Why is it so important to be vulnerable?
Our every instinct is to protect and defend, to justify ourselves, and yet we must not do it! Why is this? Paul wrote to the Corinthians about his vision and the thorn in his flesh, concluding:
 The Lord said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly about my weaknesses, so that Christ’s power may rest on me &amp;hellip; I delight in weaknesses &amp;hellip; for when I am weak, then I am strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Who am I?
What a vital question that is for any of us. It could take some time to answer! In fact, I have had to revisit it myself in recent years.
The most valiant attempt I know of to grapple with this is by Dietrich Bonhoeffer, a German pastor who was imprisoned in Flossenbürg concentration camp by the Nazis during World War II. He was executed just one month before the end of the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He guides the humble in what is right</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 06:49:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Here are a couple of verses from Psalm 25 for you:
 Good and upright is the LORD; therefore he instructs sinners in his ways. He guides the humble in what is right and teaches them his way.
― Psalm 25:8-9 Notice the therefore. Meditate on it. Revel in it. See how the Lord desires for us to be holy and blameless, and yet he does not wait for that to be so, to instruct us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
