<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>desiring God on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/desiring-god/</link>
        <description>Recent content in desiring God on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/desiring-god/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How to get what you want</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/jen-theodore-ualbj7tyJH0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to get what you want" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I told you there was a way to get exactly what you want? That the Spirit would work towards this end, and the Lord himself would make it so? Absolutely guaranteed. Are you interested in that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of promise is this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem too good to be true? Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to delight yourself in the Lord? It is no small thing. Let me paraphrase. &lt;em&gt;Make the Lord the desire of your heart, and he will give you &amp;hellip; the desire of your heart.&lt;/em&gt; Dwell in that for a while. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re not disappointed, because truth be told, it&amp;rsquo;s a phenomenal promise. Jeremiah says the same, just after that verse that everyone quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You will seek me and find me when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this look like? To seek the Lord with all your heart? To make him your heart&amp;rsquo;s desire? It is surely time-consuming. In fact, it is all-consuming. It is worth waking up early for. It is worth pursuing through the day, and resting in through the night. We cannot afford to be half-hearted in this. David said as much to his own son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“And you, my son Solomon, acknowledge the God of your father, and serve him with wholehearted devotion and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches every heart and understands every motive behind the thoughts. If you seek him, he will be found by you;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no pretending here. He &lt;em&gt;understands every motive behind the thoughts&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s confronting! So we must be absolutely ruthless, rooting out and expelling every misplaced thought and motive. This takes real work, earnest heart-work. But it is Spirit work. It is what he does. It is the work he knows so well. In him, and only in him, we can do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the Lord, Amy, and he will give you the desires of your heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How can we love the Lord this much?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/nikola-jovanovic-OBok3F8buKY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How can we love the Lord this much?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we love the Lord this much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Revelation 4:8, where the four living creatures, day and night, never stop saying: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.”  And in Revelation 5:9, where together with the twenty-four elders, they sing to Jesus, “&amp;hellip; you were slain, and by your blood you ransomed people for God from every tribe and language and people and nation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When two people are in love, truly, madly, deeply, they think about each other a lot. Like, all the time! Detachment from reality may be observed. They think about each other&amp;rsquo;s attributes, the very best, and it fuels their love. David does this of the Lord in Psalm 145.  “Every day I will praise you” (v2) because “great is the LORD and most worthy of praise” (v3) “&amp;hellip; and I will meditate on your wonderful works” (v5). He goes on to remind himself and us of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s attributes (v8-9, 13-14, 17-20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read these verses. Meditate on them. Dwell in them. Express your love for the Lord through them. Put him at the centre, and lift him high. Adore him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must do this day and night, never ceasing, all the time!  “My mouth will speak in praise of the Lord &amp;hellip; for ever and ever” (v21).  Let us detach from the pseudo-reality that deceives us, and embrace the eternal reality. Let us feed and water our love for the Lord with endless praise, so it grows and grows, for his glory, and by his power and transforming grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him more, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How much can we love the Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/aldebaran-s-uXchDIKs4qI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How much can we love the Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much can we love the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently in church we were invited to speak out our praise to God. Woefully, every single prayer was me and us. What self-obsession! Is there any deliverance from this? Wonderfully there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s to be found in Revelation, chapters 4 and 5. Lose yourself in that for a while. Hear a hundred million angels and every creature singing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength and honour and glory and praise!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are any thinking about themselves, even for a moment? Not remotely! They are wholly captivated by the presence of the risen Lord Jesus, his glory and his power, and his irresistible love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us be so, and love the Lord with such a love that we forget ourselves. With a love for him that is magnified as he enlarges our hearts with his own overflowing love. Let us adore the one who is “worthy &amp;hellip; to receive glory and honour and power” (Rev 4:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
