<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>desiring God on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/desiring-god/</link>
        <description>Recent content in desiring God on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/desiring-god/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The poor in spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-poor-in-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-poor-in-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-poor-in-spirit/jackson-david-2hJZF52UR9k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The poor in spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it that is so remarkable about the blessing for the poor in spirit, the first thing Jesus said in The Sermon on the Mount, almost the very first thing he was recorded as saying publicly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get to what is so remarkable here, let&amp;rsquo;s first unpack what it means to be poor in spirit, because poor in spirit doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound very blessed does it? Psalm 63 will help us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O God, you are my God; earnestly I seek you; my soul thirsts for you; my flesh faints for you, as in a dry and weary land where there is no water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction to the psalm tells us that David wrote this when he was in the wilderness of Judah. The physical thirst experienced in that arid land parallelled the spiritual thirst of his being poor in spirit, being so aware of his need of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t think for a moment that there is any lack of desire for God among the poor in spirit, or any lack of understanding of his goodness and mercy. The truth is the complete opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because your steadfast love is better than life, my lips will praise you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love is better than life itself. There is full understanding here, along with the most desperate longing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So I will bless you as long as I live; in your name I will lift up my hands. My soul will be satisfied as with fat and rich food, and my mouth will praise you with joyful lips, when I remember you upon my bed, and meditate on you in the watches of the night; for you have been my help, and in the shadow of your wings I will sing for joy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:4-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two things we must notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, his life is hard⸺so very hard. There is steadfast determination to praise, to trust, to honour the Lord, right alongside the sleeplessness. That&amp;rsquo;s right. In the watches of the night, in the time for sleeping, sleep does not come. So the psalmist meditates on the Lord, on his goodness and kindness and faithfulness, and so must we.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly, the blessing and satisfaction in the Lord which is so painfully longed for is in the future. It is not yet. My soul will be satisfied. I will sing for joy. There is both trust and determination here. But it is not yet. The joy is to come. And in the meantime?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to you; your right hand upholds me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are both in the present tense, right here, right now. My Heavenly Father upholds me with his right hand in the longing and the sleeplessness, and my soul clings to him. I am poor in spirit, so very aware of my need for him, and he honours that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we can understand what is so remarkable about the blessing for the poor in spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a present tense blessing, almost uniquely amidst the others (they shall be comforted; they shall inherit the earth; they shall be satisfied; they shall receive mercy; they shall see God; they shall be called sons and daughters of God — Matthew 5:4-9).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theirs is the kingdom of heaven, right now. There is nothing to wait for. There is nothing held back. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are the poor in spirit, Amy, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Biblical giants</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/biblical-giants/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/biblical-giants/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/biblical-giants/00_29_0496_Waipoua_Forest_NZ_-_Kauri_Baum_Tane_Mahuta.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Biblical giants" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you in awe of those giants of the faith we know from the Bible⸺Noah, Abraham, Moses, David⸺and how they managed to play a part in the purposes of God beyond anything we see in our times?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, don&amp;rsquo;t be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides being righteous and blameless and the reason humankind survived God&amp;rsquo;s purge of evil by the flood, Noah was just a man, and later got himself drunk and rather embarrassed himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Noah began to be a man of the soil, and he planted a vineyard. He drank of the wine and became drunk and lay uncovered in his tent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 9:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And besides being the one who in hope against all hope believed and so became the father of many nations, Abraham was previously a coward and a liar (Genesis 12:10-20) and a man who gave up waiting on the Lord (Genesis 16).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses too was a coward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to him, “Who has made man&amp;rsquo;s mouth? Who makes him mute, or deaf, or seeing, or blind? Is it not I, the LORD? Now therefore go, and I will be with your mouth and teach you what you shall speak.” But [Moses] said, “Oh, my Lord, please send someone else.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 4:11-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some time later, even having witnessed the Lord&amp;rsquo;s miraculous deliverance of the Israelites from Egypt, Moses&amp;rsquo; lack of faith caused him to make a heinous mistake at Meribah which was most severely punished by God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the LORD said to Moses and Aaron, “Because you did not believe in me, to uphold me as holy in the eyes of the people of Israel, therefore you shall not bring this assembly into the land that I have given them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/numbers&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 20:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses furthermore failed to take responsibility for this failure, and his later account to the Israelites was simply untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But the LORD was angry with me because of you and would not listen to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 3:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complete our quartet of heroes we have David, that man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart, that adulterer and murderer (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What instead should we notice about these giants of the faith? They were all in fact frail and flawed human beings used by a mighty God for his Kingdom purposes. What was special about each of them was that God set his love upon them, and chose to work mightily through each one⸺just as he does for you, and just as he does for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews makes exactly this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are surrounded by these heroes. They are not above or beyond us and nor should we be in awe of them. We should rather read of their best qualities and eagerly desire those, being fully persuaded that the Lord can do the same through each of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with Noah&amp;rsquo;s blamelessness and Abraham&amp;rsquo;s faith and David&amp;rsquo;s desire for the Lord, Amy, and run with endurance, knowing that the Lord will bless you with what you desire (Psalm 37:4) and use you mightily for his Kingdom purposes! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Praise the Lord!</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/praise-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/praise-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/praise-the-lord/oscar-ivan-esquivel-arteaga-nY1sYUoJXYE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Praise the Lord!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should we praise the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; for he is beautiful, and a song of praise is fitting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, I am quoting from the ESV alternative translation for that phrase, “for he is beautiful”.  The mainline translation is “for it is pleasant”, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to me to be such a compelling reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth looking into how Bible translation is done, what is the nature of the original language, and how it is that the translators came to the interpretations that are written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Types of textual footnotes&lt;/em&gt; — (1) Footnotes of this kind provide alternative translations for specific words or phrases when there is a strong possibility that such words or phrases could be translated in another way. &amp;hellip; In such cases, the translation deemed to have the stronger support is in the text while other possible renderings are given in the note. (2) &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;ESV Bible Explanation of Features&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrew pronouns are troublesome! The word translated “he” is the masculine third person pronoun, but this could also mean “it”, referring to the act of singing praises, itself a masculine noun. No wonder Bible translations differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then do we decide on the right translation, the one that honours the Lord and is faithful to what he is saying? And why is it that the ESV translators settled on the mainline of “for it is pleasant”, relegating to a footnote “for he is beautiful”? And furthermore, how is it that I have the cheek to call them out about that as a mistake?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered two factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what are the other occurrences of the word translated here as pleasant or beautiful, the Hebrew &lt;em&gt;nâ‛îym&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This word is used 14 times in the Old Testament, and I have to admit, mostly to describe a pleasant experience (“The lines have fallen for me in pleasant places” — Psalm 16:6; “Behold, how good and pleasant it is when brothers dwell in unity!⁠” — Psalm 133:1). Mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here I deem the second factor to carry more weight, which is, what does the rest of this psalm say? Context is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would we expect in each case? A psalm which starts off with how pleasant it is to praise the Lord could be expected to continue with and expand upon the praise experience. That&amp;rsquo;s not what happens here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, our psalm comprises an exposition of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s character, of his nature, of his deeds. It is entirely about the Lord, the beautiful one. This is why we praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD builds up Jerusalem; he gathers the outcasts of Israel.&lt;br&gt;
He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds.&lt;br&gt;
He determines the number of the stars; he gives to all of them their names.&lt;br&gt;
Great is our Lord, and abundant in power; his understanding is beyond measure.&lt;br&gt;
The LORD lifts up the humble; he casts the wicked to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:2-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it continues. And it is just like this in Psalm 135, where the same Hebrew word is used. &lt;em&gt;He is beautiful (v3).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am grateful to those learned and proficient Bible translators who have made available for us the Bible in language we can understand, I am more grateful to the Lord for how he speaks to my heart through his eternal word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise the Lord, Amy, for he is beautiful! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Present tense</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/present-tense/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/present-tense/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/present-tense/GSFC_20171208_Archive_e001661_orig.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Present tense" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference is made by the tense of a verb?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading again John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the throne room in heaven. Just as a preliminary, let me note one thing there that always makes me smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At once I was in the Spirit, and behold, a throne stood in heaven, with one seated on the throne.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Creator God of the universe is enthroned, high and exalted, and John is describing what he saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he who sat there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jasper and carnelian? Really? Come on, John, is that all you&amp;rsquo;ve got for us? Is that the best you can do? That tells us nothing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is, from which we may infer just how indescribable is the Lord. Beautiful beyond description. Holy beyond description. Good and wise and kind beyond description. Praise his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and around the throne was a rainbow that had the appearance of an emerald. Around the throne were twenty-four thrones, and seated on the thrones were twenty-four elders, clothed in white garments, with golden crowns on their heads. From the throne came flashes of lightning, and rumblings and peals of thunder, and before the throne were burning seven torches of fire, which are the seven spirits of God, and before the throne there was as it were a sea of glass, like crystal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:3b-6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the inadequacy of the description, doesn&amp;rsquo;t this quicken the pulse and thrill our hearts?⸺the awesome majesty of our great God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s what comes next that caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And around the throne, on each side of the throne, are four living creatures, full of eyes in front and behind: the first living creature like a lion, the second living creature like an ox, the third living creature with the face of a man, and the fourth living creature like an eagle in flight. And the four living creatures, each of them with six wings, are full of eyes all around and within, and day and night they never cease to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Holy, holy, holy, is the Lord God Almighty, who was and is and is to come!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:6b-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you notice that John switched to the present tense? What he describes is happening right now! The worship in heaven is ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join with them, Amy, and worship the holy, holy, holy Lord God Almighty, who was and is and is to come! 🙏🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The journey</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-journey/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-journey/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-journey/finding-dan-dan-grinwis-O35rT6OytRo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The journey" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this life for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been stated with exceeding clarity by those who went before us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the chief end of man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man’s chief end is to glorify God, and to enjoy him forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Westminster Shorter Catechism, 1647&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can refocus and reframe our whole lives, especially that word &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt;. But let me for a moment observe that our glorification of the Lord and our enjoyment of him will be so much the greater in our post resurrection life, so let me ask, what is &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; life for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a related question. Is this life more about the journey or the destination?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly I long for the destination, to arrive in the presence of my Lord and Saviour, to finally stand face to face. John describes the meeting as it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a new heaven and a new earth, for the first heaven and the first earth had passed away, and the sea was no more. And I saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the bride of Christ, his beloved church of which you and I are members, Amy, and in the words of that beautiful song,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;She will be who he adores, this is what he made her for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Casting Crowns, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyTuh0v4jnY&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Wedding Day&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is this preparation of which John speaks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preparation is this life. It is the journey. The destination that I must therefore focus on is that of &lt;em&gt;the state of my heart&lt;/em&gt;. I desire to arrive well, welcomed into heaven with smiles and joy, not as one escaping through the flames (1 Corinthians 3:15). In advance of that, there is heart-work to be done, so that on that day I will not be ashamed at the smallness of my own heart and its miserly love for my Saviour and for my fellow travellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so this realisation informs every choice I make on the journey. The Holy Spirit continues to do his work of sanctifying grace in my life and I surrender to it joyfully and my heart is transformed. Slowly. Surely. Through each painful moment, I continue to die to self and live for him, all the while longing for that day, and all the while growing in love for my wonderful Saviour and his beloved church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journey well, Amy!  🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to get what you want</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/jen-theodore-ualbj7tyJH0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to get what you want" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I told you there was a way to get exactly what you want? That the Spirit would work towards this end, and the Lord himself would make it so? Absolutely guaranteed. Are you interested in that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of promise is this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem too good to be true? Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to delight yourself in the Lord? It is no small thing. Let me paraphrase. &lt;em&gt;Make the Lord the desire of your heart, and he will give you &amp;hellip; the desire of your heart.&lt;/em&gt; Dwell in that for a while. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re not disappointed, because truth be told, it&amp;rsquo;s a phenomenal promise. Jeremiah says the same, just after that verse that everyone quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You will seek me and find me when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this look like? To seek the Lord with all your heart? To make him your heart&amp;rsquo;s desire? It is surely time-consuming. In fact, it is all-consuming. It is worth waking up early for. It is worth pursuing through the day, and resting in through the night. We cannot afford to be half-hearted in this. David said as much to his own son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you, my son Solomon, acknowledge the God of your father, and serve him with wholehearted devotion and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches every heart and understands every motive behind the thoughts. If you seek him, he will be found by you;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There can be no pretending here. He &lt;em&gt;understands every motive behind the thoughts&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s confronting! So we must be absolutely ruthless, rooting out and expelling every misplaced thought and motive. This takes real work, earnest heart-work. But it is Spirit work. It is what he does. It is the work he knows so well. In him, and only in him, we can do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the Lord, Amy, and he will give you the desires of your heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How can we love the Lord this much?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/nikola-jovanovic-OBok3F8buKY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How can we love the Lord this much?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we love the Lord this much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Revelation 4:8, where the four living creatures, day and night, never stop saying: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.”  And in Revelation 5:9, where together with the twenty-four elders, they sing to Jesus, “&amp;hellip; you were slain, and by your blood you ransomed people for God from every tribe and language and people and nation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When two people are in love, truly, madly, deeply, they think about each other a lot. Like, all the time! Detachment from reality may be observed. They think about each other&amp;rsquo;s attributes, the very best, and it fuels their love. David does this of the Lord in Psalm 145.  “Every day I will praise you” (v2) because “great is the LORD and most worthy of praise” (v3) “&amp;hellip; and I will meditate on your wonderful works” (v5). He goes on to remind himself and us of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s attributes (v8-9, 13-14, 17-20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read these verses. Meditate on them. Dwell in them. Express your love for the Lord through them. Put him at the centre, and lift him high. Adore him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must do this day and night, never ceasing, all the time!  “My mouth will speak in praise of the Lord &amp;hellip; for ever and ever” (v21).  Let us detach from the pseudo-reality that deceives us, and embrace the eternal reality. Let us feed and water our love for the Lord with endless praise, so it grows and grows, for his glory, and by his power and transforming grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him more, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How much can we love the Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/aldebaran-s-uXchDIKs4qI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How much can we love the Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much can we love the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently in church we were invited to speak out our praise to God. Woefully, every single prayer was me and us. What self-obsession! Is there any deliverance from this? Wonderfully there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s to be found in Revelation, chapters 4 and 5. Lose yourself in that for a while. Hear a hundred million angels and every creature singing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength and honour and glory and praise!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are any thinking about themselves, even for a moment? Not remotely! They are wholly captivated by the presence of the risen Lord Jesus, his glory and his power, and his irresistible love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us be so, and love the Lord with such a love that we forget ourselves. With a love for him that is magnified as he enlarges our hearts with his own overflowing love. Let us adore the one who is “worthy &amp;hellip; to receive glory and honour and power” (Rev 4:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
