<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>prayer on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/prayer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in prayer on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:36:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/prayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Throwing a mountain into the sea</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:36:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we throw a mountain into the sea?
What a ridiculous question! It&amp;rsquo;s clearly impossible. And yet, Jesus said,
 “Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.” (Mk 11:23)
 Why would Jesus say such a thing? Is he mocking us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid prayer</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Dear God, my God,
You are the Lord of all creation, majestic, sovereign, good, and wise beyond our understanding. Praise your holy name! I lift up to you the situation in Amy&amp;rsquo;s village, with Covid having arrived, and along with it, fear. Forgive us when we doubt your goodness or your sovereignty. I pray the people there would hear Jesus speaking, &amp;ldquo;Peace I leave with you; my peace I give you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace and provision</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:21:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</guid>
      <description>May you know peace from the Lord, and his provision for you, Amy, as you wait on him, and especially when things don&amp;rsquo;t turn out as you expected or hoped. Know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans prevail, and &amp;hellip; he delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love. Psalm 147:11 🙏</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
