<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>prayer on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/prayer/</link>
        <description>Recent content in prayer on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/prayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Pray in the Spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/manuel-meurisse-EuCll-F5atI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Pray in the Spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the last piece of the armour of God that is so often overlooked, indeed not even thought of as armour by many?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the Bible is about reading in paragraphs, which are the basic units of expression, things that belong together. Not every Bible translation has the same paragraph breaks, but in both of my preferred translations—the NIV 1984 and the ESV—the armour of God is described in just one paragraph, which in the NIV ends with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And pray in the Spirit on all occasions with all kinds of prayers and requests. With this in mind, be alert and always keep on praying for all the saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How interesting that Paul would conclude his writing about the armour of God with this. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider how praying in the Spirit could be considered a vital piece of the armour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what does “in the Spirit“ even mean? There seems to be much confusion today about what is the work of the Holy Spirit. Jim Packer wrote a whole book about it, &lt;em&gt;Keep in Step with the Spirit&lt;/em&gt;, in which he outlines some of the secondary aspects that seem to occupy most people&amp;rsquo;s attention, including power, revelation, and promptings, before arguing that &lt;em&gt;the primary work of the Holy Spirit is to mediate the presence of Jesus in our lives&lt;/em&gt;. And indeed, this matches with what Jesus says of the Spirit in John 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Paul writes in Romans is closely related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the same way, the Spirit helps us in our weakness. We do not know what we ought to pray for, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groans that words cannot express.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not overthink this. Praying in the Spirit is simply praying in relationship with Jesus. There is no formula, just as there is no formula in human relationship. Mutual commitment and time spent together are required for the relationship to flourish. Jesus is committed! How he is that!! Are we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must do this on all occasions, and with all kinds of prayers and requests. Let&amp;rsquo;s not get into a rut of formulaic praying. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with our wonderful Saviour and enjoy intimacy in relationship. In his presence we are protected in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice too that Paul&amp;rsquo;s instruction is to pray for all the saints, that is, all Christians. In the spiritual battle we must avoid at all cost turning in on ourselves, as if we are the ones who matter most. By no means! Our brothers and sisters in Christ are the ones we must love, and continue to lift up before the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray in the Spirit on all occasions with all kinds of prayers and requests, Amy, for all the saints! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Symphony of Life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/jack-finnigan-aEkk0KxvPpg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Symphony of Life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when we pray? Can we actually change the Lord&amp;rsquo;s mind? How could we possibly improve upon his already perfect plans and purposes? Why even ask for anything in prayer then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are huge questions, and I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly answer them adequately. But here&amp;rsquo;s a reflection on this, somewhat of an excursion into make-believe, which nevertheless may help to shed some light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, note that we are encouraged, nay commanded to pray, and to pray boldly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pray continually&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If you believe, you will receive whatever you ask for in prayer.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 21:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine then. The Lord who created music has himself written the greatest work of all, the Symphony of Life, in 8 billion parts. He is both the composer, and the conductor for its debut and only performance. It is a glorious, majestic work featuring players both unwilling and willing, with plunging depths and soaring heights, human folly and heavenly beneficence, sorrow and joy.  It is a love story, the greatest of them all, a story of rescue and redemption of a wayward people, pieced together from fragments of ruined lives made whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the billions of orchestral members play their parts with quite some improvising, the Lord hears the prayers of the saints, our prayers, and delights to weave them in to the score, making amendments and annotations with his divine pencil even as the music unfolds, taking our imperfect petitions and making them part of his perfect plans and purposes, as it pleases him. And with each, smiling down on his beloved ones with such affection, like a proud father. Smiling on us, who are contributing somehow to his glorious work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at the mystery of his ways, Amy, praising the Lord for his majesty, grace and kindness, and continue praying Kingdom prayers! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/sasha-freemind-nXo2ZsKHTHg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unanswered prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7, 11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unanswered prayer is a real thing. How can we deal with it? Many have grappled with this, and much has been written. Some have said, the Lord always answers prayer: sometimes yes; sometimes no; sometimes not yet. I find this glib and unhelpful. Because sometimes there is silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a husband and father, let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mark, a faithful servant of the Lord, suffering with severe health issues for so many years, for whom we have been faithfully, earnestly praying, confident that the Lord hears and is powerful to heal. Except he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, and this man dies, leaving his grieving wife, Grace, and their eight-year-old son, Callum. And from the Lord, only silence. What kind of answer to prayer is that? How is that a reasonable response to desperate prayers offered from a broken heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another way to see this. Unanswered prayer is an &lt;em&gt;invitation into relationship&lt;/em&gt;. An invitation into intimacy. How does this work? Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Why did Mark have to die? Don&amp;rsquo;t you care?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you have done something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “He loved you, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? Did you love him? You did love him, didn&amp;rsquo;t you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Yes, Amy, I loved him. I love him still.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “What about Grace and little Callum? This is breaking my heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;long pause, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Mine too, Amy. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit together for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;intimate, healing silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father grieves over his broken world, and the suffering his people bear. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with him, and grieve also, in the intimacy of his healing presence. And in the meantime,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us. For the creation waits in eager expectation for the children of God to be revealed. For the creation was subjected to frustration, not by its own choice, but by the will of the one who subjected it, in hope that the creation itself will be liberated from its bondage to decay and brought into the freedom and glory of the children of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:18-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit with the Lord in the silence of the unanswered prayer, Amy, in the intimacy of his healing presence 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Throwing a mountain into the sea</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:36:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/sulthan-auliya-WLORfDtl7oM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Throwing a mountain into the sea" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we throw a mountain into the sea?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a ridiculous question! It&amp;rsquo;s clearly impossible. And yet, Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would Jesus say such a thing? Is he mocking us? Is he exaggerating? Is he lying, even?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone tells us something that is hard to accept, how we receive it depends critically on who they are, and what we know of them. Can we trust? And what reason do we have for that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many years, I have learnt that I can trust Jesus absolutely. I&amp;rsquo;m quite a slow learner, and have doubted in various ways for so much of my life, but no longer. I choose therefore to believe that Jesus was telling the truth when he said this impossible thing. What do I make of it then? I have to relate it to other things I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said a similar thing to his disciples at the Last Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here we have the caveat, “in my name”. I can only ask for something in Jesus&amp;rsquo; name if he would have asked for the same. That&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful guideline for praying in power, and it defines my own expectation in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I choose to believe Jesus. I can&amp;rsquo;t throw a mountain into the sea, only because I cannot escape my own doubt about that. I acknowledge that as the reason. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t doubt, it would be so. That is on me. Jesus is trustworthy and true, and he speaks truth. And there are so many other things I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; pray for, believing, not doubting. Impossible things, even. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray in power, Amy, believing and not doubting! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Covid prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/covid-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/covid-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/covid-prayer/yannis-h-zpSXcUpmhNc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Covid prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear God, my God,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the Lord of all creation, majestic, sovereign, good, and wise beyond our understanding. Praise your holy name! I lift up to you the situation in Amy&amp;rsquo;s village, with Covid having arrived, and along with it, fear. Forgive us when we doubt your goodness or your sovereignty. I pray the people there would hear Jesus speaking, &amp;ldquo;Peace I leave with you; my peace I give you. I do not give to you as the world gives. Do not let your hearts be troubled and do not be afraid.&amp;rdquo; (John 14:27). Please keep Amy safe and well, and may she be a beacon of hope for those who may be losing theirs, pointing to Jesus and trusting him.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cc: Amy, with love&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/jonny-james-TE0leJlNX8Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Filled with the knowledge of his will" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Peace and provision</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/peace-and-provision/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:21:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/peace-and-provision/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/peace-and-provision/raimond-klavins-DDwOFA_9LiY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Peace and provision" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;May you know peace from the Lord, and his provision for you, Amy, as you wait on him, and especially when things don&amp;rsquo;t turn out as you expected or hoped. Know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans prevail, and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
