<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>comfort on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/comfort/</link>
        <description>Recent content in comfort on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 06:15:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/comfort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Comfort and healing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 06:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/kat-j-NPmR0RblyhQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Comfort and healing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing that our God is the God of all comfort and healing, how can we minister this to the brokenhearted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to write about such things when grief and loss are present and quite so raw. But it is precisely at such a time that we must engage with the Lord, and seek to understand, if he is the God of all comfort and healing, which he is, how is that outworked at such a time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At such times we are supposed to be able to comfort those in need with the comfort we ourselves have received from God. But how often do we seem to be of no use in this, not knowing even what to say or do? In the weeping face of heartbreak, how can we in fact be of any comfort at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently been gaining some experience in this, as I am continuing to care for a young friend, a believer in Christ, in the midst of his own trauma, which is ongoing, heartbreaking, and bewildering. In the face of this overwhelming need, the Lord has given me such clarity of understanding of what my friend needs from me, and it is not advice nor explanation nor anything else that I have to say. It is simply Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not matter that I do not know what to say or do. Jesus does. So we cry out to him together for mercy. And he responds, with grace and kindness, impossibly and lavishly. The peace that has come surpasses understanding. The need is ongoing, but so is the grace, and so is the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our own comfort is in Jesus and it is Jesus, and so this is what we must minister to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does it look like, to minister Jesus to the brokenhearted? It looks like gentleness, and kindness, and listening, and prayer, and probably a hug, but most especially time⸺more time than 21st Century western civilization would think is a reasonable investment for a single individual. Not much speaking though. This may come later, but is not I think where we are called to start. And above all else, absolute confidence in the one who is mighty to save, whose name is Helper, Comforter, Healer, Lord, whose name is Jesus. The one who, astonishingly, chooses to do his work of grace through us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us remind ourselves why we praise him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; for he is beautiful, and a song of praise is fitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1, 3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in this, Jesus does what we cannot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to Jesus, Amy, the source of all comfort and the source of all healing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The God of all comfort</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/helena-lopes-ikOKjyLZRno-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The God of all comfort" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the nature of the comfort we can receive from God, and how can we receive it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life can be so hard. We need this comfort. So we need to understand just what it is, and how it works. Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise be to the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of compassion and the God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our troubles, so that we can comfort those in any trouble with the comfort we ourselves have received from God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gained some insight into this recently, quite indirectly and unexpectedly. Just as I was arriving back home from a run, I bumped into a friend, a professor of theology with whom I have had some interesting and uplifting conversations over the years. I remarked that I had been struck by the incredible grace and kindness of the Lord. He then asked an interesting question: “Did something particularly good just happen?” to which the answer was no, not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I reflected on this later, it made me a little sad. So often, the grace of God is understood as being received through our circumstances, equated with something good and pleasant happening to us. How impoverished can be our understanding of grace! The grace of God is a powerful, tangible thing, which can be received and experienced in its own right, independently of any change in circumstance. And invisible to others, save perhaps for some glow about us as we receive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with comfort. If we read around those verses we see the context of the comfort is severe hardship, hardly pleasant circumstances. In particular, note this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For just as the sufferings of Christ flow over into our lives, so also through Christ our comfort overflows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering and comfort here are hand-in-hand. This comfort from God is not received through observable, physical happenings. It is received directly. It is wonderful, powerful, and oh so tangible, a gift from the Father of compassion himself. A heavenly hug, so to speak, from the one who loves us beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever is happening, Amy, receive comfort directly from the God of all comfort, the Father of compassion, the one who loves you beyond imagining! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
