<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>salvation on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/salvation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in salvation on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 06:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/salvation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Joseph son of David</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/joseph-son-of-david/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/joseph-son-of-david/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/joseph-son-of-david/chris-curry-KsSxzBnozMY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Joseph son of David" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome back⸺and how lovely it was to see you face to face again after all this time! May the Lord grant you real rest over these next few weeks, and may you be revitalised and restored in his presence. ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, have you ever been surprised to notice something afresh in a very familiar Bible story?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And isn&amp;rsquo;t the Bible truly amazing? I am continually finding such freshness, profound truths apparently plainly stated yet previously unnoticed or simply rediscovered. I came across one such only this week, in the oh-so-familiar Nativity story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When his mother Mary had been betrothed to Joseph, before they came together she was found to be with child from the Holy Spirit. And her husband Joseph, being a just man and unwilling to put her to shame, resolved to divorce her quietly. But as he considered these things, behold, an angel of the Lord appeared to him in a dream, saying, “Joseph, son of David, do not fear to take Mary as your wife, for that which is conceived in her is from the Holy Spirit. She will bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus, for he will save his people from their sins.” All this took place to fulfill what the Lord had spoken by the prophet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Behold, the virgin shall conceive and bear a son,
and they shall call his name Immanuel”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(which means, God with us).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 1:18-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into what I noticed, let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to be amazed once again at the whole Christmas story. I once read that of the incarnation and the resurrection, the incarnation is the greater miracle, and I am inclined to agree⸺God contracted to a span, incomprehensibly made man! Praise our Lord and Saviour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, what is it that I noticed afresh in this passage? Simply this: &lt;em&gt;Joseph son of David&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parentage is important in the Bible. Notice throughout that characters are introduced as so-and-so son of so-and-so. Matthew tells that Joseph&amp;rsquo;s father was Jacob, so why did the angel address him as Joseph son of David, his ancestor of a thousand years? Here&amp;rsquo;s what I take from that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s rescue mission in Christ was planned from the very beginning, in his glorious promise of defeat of Satan and rescue by Christ, the Son of God, and miraculously also a descendant of the first man and the first woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LORD God said to the serpent &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I will put enmity between you and the woman,
and between your offspring and her offspring;
he shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:14a, 15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By addressing Joseph as son of David the angel is reminding both him and us of just how long in the making has been God&amp;rsquo;s plan of rescue and redemption, and of the prophecies that foretold of the Messiah coming from David&amp;rsquo;s line. How reassuring for Joseph to know that what was happening was part of a long established plan, intricately woven from strands of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is not entirely dissimilar for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you formed my inward parts; you knitted me together in my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb. I praise you, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made. Wonderful are your works; my soul knows it very well. My frame was not hidden from you, when I was being made in secret, intricately woven in the depths of the earth. Your eyes saw my unformed substance; in your book were written, every one of them, the days that were formed for me, when as yet there was none of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 139:13-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember this, Amy, that you are loved with an ancient love, and have been from the beginning! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The helmet of salvation</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/Cypraecassis_rufaGlobal.png" alt="Featured image of post The helmet of salvation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the helmet of salvation a misnomer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the helmet of salvation &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:13, 17a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What actually is this helmet of salvation that Paul tells us to put on? It can&amp;rsquo;t be salvation per se, as that is a gift of and from the Lord, received through faith. What is it then that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; should put on, and continue to put on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is found in a similar exhortation Paul writes to the Thessalonians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But since we belong to the day, let us be self-controlled, putting on faith and love as a breastplate, and the hope of salvation as a helmet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s all about &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt;⸺the hope of salvation. Recall what hope is. It&amp;rsquo;s not some finger-crossing wishful thinking. By no means! It is grounds for believing that something good will happen, with certainty. And in this case that is something overwhelmingly wonderfully bountifully joyously good, something worth truly waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the case of salvation, what is there still to hope for? Don&amp;rsquo;t we already have it? The simple truth is this: our salvation is already accomplished, but not yet complete. One day it will be so and the battle will be over. That is a certainty, and until then this hope is stored up for us in heaven (Colossians 1:5-6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, the process by which we receive this salvation is ongoing and joyous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Though you have not seen [Jesus], you love him; and even though you do not see him now, you believe in him and are filled with an inexpressible and glorious joy, for you are receiving the goal of your faith, the salvation of your souls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the present continuous tense here. We &lt;em&gt;are receiving&lt;/em&gt; the goal of our faith, which is our salvation. The process is ongoing and will last for all of our earthly lives, but it will eventually come to an end, as recounted in John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the end of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I heard a loud voice in heaven say: “Now have come the salvation and the power and the kingdom of our God, and the authority of his Christ. For the accuser of our brothers and sisters, who accuses them before our God day and night, has been hurled down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 12:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anticipate that day with great joy, Amy, and in the meantime, put on and continue to put on the hope of salvation as a helmet! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Predestination</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/saiph-muhammad-CSs8aiN_LkI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Predestination" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s all this about predestination? Don&amp;rsquo;t people have a right to choose for themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I swing in my hammock on that desert island, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do except read Ephesians 1. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. In love he predestined us to be adopted as his children through Jesus Christ, in accordance with his pleasure and will &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In him we were also chosen, having been predestined according to the plan of him who works out everything in conformity with the purpose of his will, in order that we, who were the first to hope in Christ, might be for the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4-5, 11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no escaping that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s choice, rather than mine. And that is a wonderful thing. The Lord, the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, does not make mistakes. He chose me. He chose you, Amy, in accordance with his pleasure and will. As for me, I make mistakes, and my own choices are always subject to suspicion and doubt. Not so the Lord! His plans and purposes prevail, for the praise of his glory. I, you, we are both his, forever, and no mistake! And thus we have assurance of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. He chose us to be holy and blameless in his sight. Partly that is an instantaneous, Jesus-died-for-my sins-and-now-I-am-counted-righteous thing. And partly it is a rest-of-my-life thing, as the Holy Spirit continues both to convict me and to empower me to change, as I surrender my will on the pathway to holiness. Both are life-giving, lavish gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what of evangelism? If people are chosen, where is repentance and belief? See what comes next in the passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession⸺to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1: 13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those to whom Paul writes &lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; the message of truth (because someone told them), and &lt;em&gt;believed&lt;/em&gt;. Predestination does not diminish the gospel message in any way. There is undeniably mystery here, but the greatest evangelist of all time was surely &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Paul himself&lt;/em&gt;, who wrote these words. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, and he is yours, forever, because he chose you in him before the creation of the world. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
