<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>glory on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/glory/</link>
        <description>Recent content in glory on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 08:30:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/glory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A city on a hill</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-city-on-a-hill/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 08:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-city-on-a-hill/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-city-on-a-hill/gabriele-merlino-photographer-bnvubGJTyNg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A city on a hill" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we shine for Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Jesus⸺that&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing. Consider what Jesus said in the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You are the light of the world. A city set on a hill cannot be hidden. Nor do people light a lamp and put it under a basket, but on a stand, and it gives light to all in the house. Let your light so shine before others that they may see your good works and give glory to your Father who is in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:14-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is the pivotal word here? The answer is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt;, but it is not all that clear. To be sure, this is the alternative translation given in the footnote in the ESV. The mainline translation is like the NIV rendering, neither of which are particularly helpful: &lt;em&gt;In the same way, let your light shine before others, so that they may see your good works and give glory to your Father who is in heaven.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this phrasing obscures what really matters. At times like this I turn to the NASB, the most literal translation of them all, the one that remains closest to the original language. Here&amp;rsquo;s what we find there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let your light shine before men in such a way that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father who is in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:16 (NASB)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? &lt;em&gt;In such a way that they &amp;hellip; glorify your Father who is in heaven&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such a way. That is how we must shine, for there are two strikingly different ways shining ones could be received. “Oh wow, Simon is amazing, isn&amp;rsquo;t he?” Or, “oh wow, have you noticed the transforming grace at work in Simon&amp;rsquo;s life? The Lord is amazing, isn&amp;rsquo;t he?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ego craves one of these but it is the other that glorifies the Lord. I must confess and repent and shine in such a way that they glorify my Heavenly Father. All the glory must go to him. That must be my heart&amp;rsquo;s desire, and so I must die to self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the Apostle Paul focuses on the main point with exceeding clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For God, who said, “Let light shine out of darkness,” has shone in our hearts to give the light of the knowledge of the glory of God in the face of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we have this treasure in jars of clay, to show that the surpassing power belongs to God and not to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am merely a clay jar, really nothing to behold at all, quite unimpressive and weak and somewhat vulnerable, but oh my, the treasure that I have within! The treasure that Jesus my Saviour has given me, that the Holy Spirit living in me is guarding and growing. The treasure that others must see as I live my life as a city on a hill. The treasure that will attract those outside the Kingdom to come in, and the treasure that will encourage my brothers and sisters in Christ to live lives that are ever more characterised by love and holiness. On dying to self, I find incredible joy in this city on a hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let your light shine in such a way, Amy, that they glorify your Father who is in heaven! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From glory to glory</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/from-glory-to-glory/joshua-j-cotten-dMn92oICKFY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post From glory to glory" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can those made in the image of God be transformed into his image? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that a bit, well, circular?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we all, with unveiled face, reflecting the glory of the Lord, are being transformed into the same image from one degree of glory to another. For this comes from the Lord who is the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chapter Paul is contrasting the old and new covenants, characterising the old covenant as “the ministry of death” (v7) and “the ministry of condemnation” (v9), oh my! What do we need to know to understand what he writes here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hope in the new covenant is in the ministry of the Spirit and the ministry of righteousness⸺our righteousness in Christ, purchased at such great cost⸺a permanent glory (v8-11). In contrast, when Moses came down from Mount Sinai, while his face initially shone with the reflected glory of the Lord, he covered himself with a veil so that the Israelites would not see how quickly it faded (Exodus 34:29-35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s follow Paul&amp;rsquo;s reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since we have such a hope, we are very bold, not like Moses, who would put a veil over his face so that the Israelites might not gaze at the outcome of what was being brought to an end. But their minds were hardened. For to this day, when they read the old covenant, that same veil remains unlifted, because only through Christ is it taken away. Yes, to this day whenever Moses is read a veil lies over their hearts. But when one turns to the Lord, the veil is removed. Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:12-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who live under the old covenant live with a veil over their hearts to cover the shame of failing to live up to what is required, for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God (Romans 3:23).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why then are we so bold? Because we stand in Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness, not our own. Hallelujah! Our faces are unveiled because there is no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus (Romans 8:1). Only through Christ is the veil taken away. No condemnation. No fear. No shame. Freedom is ours! Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we, the rescued ones, beloved of God, are being transformed from one degree of glory into another. What we were created to be has not yet been seen in our lives. Assuredly we were made in the image of God, but that became so tarnished by sin, by that rebellion against God passed down through the ages from the first man and the first woman. There is, however, such a joyous anticipation in the ongoing process of sanctification, of being made holy, through which we will be made into that which we were always meant to be. And get this: &lt;em&gt;we ourselves are fully a part of that process&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For in his great wisdom, in the mystery of his marvellous ways, the Lord chooses to involve us in that transformation. It comes when we surrender our will to the Holy Spirit, and when we do, how it comes! Look at the lovely way that Paul describes those who are being transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you show that you are a letter from Christ delivered by us, written not with ink but with the Spirit of the living God, not on tablets of stone but on tablets of human hearts.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are a letter from Christ, Amy, written on the tablet of your own heart, a witness before the nations to his great love and mercy and grace and his power to transform into his own likeness! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Uneven blessing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/atul-pandey-0f3bZHXZSz8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Uneven blessing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that some seem to receive more bounteous blessing from the Lord than others? How is that fair? And how is it congruent with a God of justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with fair, and let&amp;rsquo;s be frank. What would be fair would be for each one of us to be cast into the fiery pit. And collectively, we must take responsibility through our wretched ancestors for much of the suffering of humankind, for we share the same rebellious spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Because you have &amp;hellip; eaten of the tree of which I commanded you, ‘You shall not eat of it,’ cursed is the ground because of you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, and this is a wonderful, unmerited, joyous but,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a rescue! What a Saviour! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with grateful, praising hearts, in fear and trembling, let us dare to ask again, how is it that God&amp;rsquo;s blessing is quite so unevenly distributed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul grappled with such a question in relation to the election of the Gentiles and God&amp;rsquo;s apparent rejection of the nation of Israel (Romans 9-11). That he takes three chapters over this shows us that such questions are no small matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take some of his arguments and apply them to the more general question of uneven blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What shall we say then? Is there injustice on God&amp;rsquo;s part? By no means! For he says to Moses, “I will have mercy on whom I have mercy, and I will have compassion on whom I have compassion.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is all mercy, and it is all undeserved. And let us not forget that the giver is the Creator God of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Has the potter no right over the clay, to make out of the same lump one vessel for honourable use and another for dishonourable use? What if God, desiring to show his wrath and to make known his power, has endured with much patience vessels of wrath prepared for destruction, in order to make known the riches of his glory for vessels of mercy, which he has prepared beforehand for glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow in the unevenness of the blessing, God is making known the riches of his glory. Paul also shows us how to respond in the face of the apparent injustice of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Brothers, my heart&amp;rsquo;s desire and prayer to God for them is that they may be saved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 10:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And observe the extent of his love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have great sorrow and unceasing anguish in my heart. For I could wish that I myself were accursed and cut off from Christ for the sake of my brothers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this then the key to understanding? Even as we cry out to God over the unevenness of the blessing, is this our opportunity to learn how to truly love, and in so doing to glorify God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I was hungry and you gave me food, I was thirsty and you gave me drink, I was a stranger and you welcomed me, I was naked and you clothed me, I was sick and you visited me, I was in prison and you came to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Truly, I say to you, as you did it to one of the least of these my brothers, you did it to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:35-36, 40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the Lord enlarge our hearts for this broken world as we look around and see places where his blessing seems to be absent. And let us cry out to him for mercy, to the Lord, our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you think we have arrived at a place of only partial understanding, let us observe that Paul himself, the great apostle and teacher, is in just that place after three chapters of his own wrestling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, the depth of the riches and wisdom and knowledge of God! How unsearchable are his judgments and how inscrutable his ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 11:33, 36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cry out, Amy, to the one who is wise beyond understanding, and in places of meagre blessing love with his own love, from him and through him and to him, for his glory forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Casting off shame</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/casting-off-shame/allef-vinicius-oe_03B2Q5A4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Casting off shame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what we do about ourselves, how can we possibly hold our head high?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David had a similar problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was chosen by the Lord because he was a man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart (1 Samuel 13:14). He earnestly sought the Lord and wrote many of the psalms which have blessed the generations.  But let us not make the mistake of thinking that he was a righteous man. His later life was in fact a catalogue of failure and shame, culminating in his most shabby and shameful moral failure, committing adultery with Bathsheba and murdering her husband Uriah the Hittite (2 Samuel 11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, David wrote Psalm 3 when he was being pursued by his son Absalom, who was trying to kill him and seize control of the kingdom. What greater failure as a father could there be than that? How utterly shameful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet we read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, LORD, are a shield around me, my glory, the One who lifts my head high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David was so aware that he had no glory of his own. He had only shame. But the Lord himself was his glory, and not only the reason that he could hold his head high, but the one who actually lifted his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course, this in no way diminishes the Lord&amp;rsquo;s condemnation of sin in one&amp;rsquo;s life. David was severely rebuked by the Lord after his wretched doings with Bathsheba. Repentance was very necessary. Forgiveness followed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. The nearer we draw to God and the more we focus on personal holiness, the more aware we become of our own failure and shame, all those reasons Christ died on the cross. We own those reasons. And yet, the Lord is my glory, the lifter of my head. Yours too, Amy! He chose us in him to be holy and blameless in his sight, and he will achieve his purposes. In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins. Cast off the shame. He alone is my glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold your head high, Amy, and know that the Lord himself is your glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The heavens declare the glory of God</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 06:26:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/martin-jernberg-UdURxHDhrgY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The heavens declare the glory of God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 19 starts like this. The heavens declare the glory of God; the skies proclaim the work of his hands. Day after day they pour forth speech; night after night they display knowledge. There is no speech or language where their voice is not heard. Their voice goes out into all the earth, their words to the ends of the world. (And it continues with real soul food.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole of creation bears witness to the glory and majesty of the Lord!  Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is indeed awe and wonder to be found in the night sky. As a Northerner, however, from where I live now it is quite unsettling to see Orion doing a hand stand. I wonder how he behaves on the equator. 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems appropriate therefore to turn these verses upside down. So my prayer is that you experience the Lord revealing himself to you in the small things too. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How much can we love the Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/aldebaran-s-uXchDIKs4qI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How much can we love the Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much can we love the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently in church we were invited to speak out our praise to God. Woefully, every single prayer was me and us. What self-obsession! Is there any deliverance from this? Wonderfully there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s to be found in Revelation, chapters 4 and 5. Lose yourself in that for a while. Hear a hundred million angels and every creature singing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength and honour and glory and praise!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are any thinking about themselves, even for a moment? Not remotely! They are wholly captivated by the presence of the risen Lord Jesus, his glory and his power, and his irresistible love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us be so, and love the Lord with such a love that we forget ourselves. With a love for him that is magnified as he enlarges our hearts with his own overflowing love. Let us adore the one who is “worthy &amp;hellip; to receive glory and honour and power” (Rev 4:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
