<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>trust on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/trust/</link>
        <description>Recent content in trust on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 06:24:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/trust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Green pastures</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/green-pastures/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/green-pastures/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/green-pastures/benjamin-davies-Zm2n2O7Fph4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Green pastures" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the greatest gift that can be given?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question came into my head after listening to your voice on Monday, and my heart went out to you. At once I wanted to type out a message of love and encouragement for you. I wanted to reach out and give you a hug. Then I realised my question wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite right. The greatest gift isn&amp;rsquo;t mine to give. It is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s. The greatest gift that is mine to give is to remind you of his gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I&amp;rsquo;m doing as I write to you is to remind you of things you already know. I am very aware of that! And I am not writing as someone who has it all together, as someone who has arrived, so to speak. By no means! I write as a fellow traveller, still on the journey, seeking to honour the Lord with every fibre of my being, with every breath of my life, as are you. Facing knocks and pitfalls and discouragements and sorrow and pain and weariness, as are you. I write what encourages my own heart on this journey, praying that it may also bless you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh Amy, know this, which is so familiar, and yet may be overlooked. Here is my gift of love and encouragement for you, this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is my shepherd, I shall not be in want. He makes me lie down in green pastures, he leads me beside quiet waters, he restores my soul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 23:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I need that. You need that. Let us receive it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He makes me lie down in green pastures. He knows what I need. Oh how he knows that! He knows what you need, Amy. He leads me beside quiet waters. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider for a moment how to receive this gift from the one who knows us and loves us beyond understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what I wrote to you right back in the beginning, when you had only just arrived in the village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed is the one who trusts in the LORD, whose confidence is in him. They will be like a tree planted by the water that sends out its roots by the stream. It does not fear when heat comes; its leaves are always green. It has no worries in a year of drought and never fails to bear fruit.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 17:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here then is how we receive this gift from Psalm 23. &lt;em&gt;We trust the Lord&lt;/em&gt;. We choose to trust him, even though the way ahead is hard and we are weary. His grace is sufficient for us. For me. For you. I choose to trust that it is, casting myself upon him, depending on him, his power made perfect in my weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as I trust him in this way, what does he do? &lt;em&gt;He restores my soul&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust that he knows you, Amy, trust that he loves you, lie down in his green pastures and have your soul restored! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Perfect timing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-timing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-timing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-timing/mads-schmidt-rasmussen-v0PWN7Z38ag-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Perfect timing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does perfect timing look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some think it looks like that scene at Helm&amp;rsquo;s Deep, where Aragorn, Legolas and Gimli with some of the Rohirrim defend against an overwhelming army of orcs. They are expecting Gandalf to show up with the Riders of Rohan, but for so long he doesn&amp;rsquo;t come. After the longest time, when it looks like all may be lost, finally he arrives, riding Shadowfax and wielding his staff with great power against the evil hordes. Victory is won and the friends are reunited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen? Consider this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now a man named Lazarus was sick. He was from Bethany, the village of Mary and her sister Martha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the sisters sent word to Jesus, “Lord, the one you love is sick.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he heard that Lazarus was sick, Jesus stayed where he was two more days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On his arrival, Jesus found that Lazarus had already been in the tomb for four days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Lord,” Martha said to Jesus, “if you had been here, my brother would not have died.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 11:1, 3, 6, 17, 21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a moment you don&amp;rsquo;t know what happens next — in our own lives that is certainly the case. If we are to learn anything here, we have to enter into the story, and right now it looks like callous disregard by Jesus for the ones who love and trust him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what it looks like and what it actually is are poles apart, here and so often in our own lives. What have we missed? Here&amp;rsquo;s what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Jesus loved Martha and her sister and Lazarus. So when he heard that Lazarus was sick, he stayed where he was two more days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 11:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus stayed where he was for two more days &lt;em&gt;precisely because he loved them&lt;/em&gt;. How perplexed were those who were depending on him. How abandoned they must have felt. Just like us they couldn&amp;rsquo;t see what was actually happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did happen next? Jesus wept with the sisters, joining with them in their grief and their pain. So much pain. How he shared in their grief. His tears were real, because the pain was real, even knowing what he was about to do. And then he raised Lazarus to life! Hallelujah! What a saviour! It was precisely because he loved them that he chose this path, revealing to them both his unfathomable love and his incomparably great power for those who believe. For us too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust him, Amy, even when it looks like he hasn&amp;rsquo;t come through for you in time. He most certainly is doing exactly that! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Taste and see that the Lord is good</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/joyful-vT5xrj3z1OE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taste and see that the Lord is good" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we obey a command if we don&amp;rsquo;t know what it means?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously we can&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s a rhetorical question. What of this then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Taste and see that the LORD is good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is clearly an instruction to do something. It&amp;rsquo;s a command. Notice that David could have written, Behold! The Lord is good (because he is). That&amp;rsquo;s a true statement, but it&amp;rsquo;s not what he wrote. What he wrote, rather, is something we are commanded to do. Taste! And see! Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasting is an action. There is something to do. Physically, we put food in our mouths and chew on it. As an aside, how gracious of the Lord to make this a pleasurable experience. We are really just refueling our bodies. Who else would have decided to make that something to enjoy? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s character is revealed even in this, that he found yet another way to bless us, his beloved. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us some insight. We experience the goodness of God as a result of taking some action. What action is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that more than any other the word that appears alongside the goodness of God throughout scripture is &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt;, that those who would see his goodness must trust, in his unfailing love, in his mercy, in all he is and all he has done. Grab a concordance and see for yourself! This very verse continues “blessed is the one who takes refuge in him”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we would taste and see, we must then &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;depend&lt;/em&gt;. This makes sense. When we fully commit to depending on the Lord, such that we are not trying to control our own outcome, only then may we see the goodness of God, because only then have we left him space in which to show us that goodness. As we relinquish control over our own lives, may we learn to chew on and genuinely savour the goodness of God that he reveals to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust and depend, Amy, taste and see, and leave the Lord space to show you his goodness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/sasha-freemind-nXo2ZsKHTHg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unanswered prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;[Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you &amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7, 11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unanswered prayer is a real thing. How can we deal with it? Many have grappled with this, and much has been written. Some have said, the Lord always answers prayer: sometimes yes; sometimes no; sometimes not yet. I find this glib and unhelpful. Because sometimes there is silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a husband and father, let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mark, a faithful servant of the Lord, suffering with severe health issues for so many years, for whom we have been faithfully, earnestly praying, confident that the Lord hears and is powerful to heal. Except he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, and this man dies, leaving his grieving wife, Grace, and their eight-year-old son, Callum. And from the Lord, only silence. What kind of answer to prayer is that? How is that a reasonable response to desperate prayers offered from a broken heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another way to see this. Unanswered prayer is an &lt;em&gt;invitation into relationship&lt;/em&gt;. An invitation into intimacy. How does this work? Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Why did Mark have to die? Don&amp;rsquo;t you care?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you have done something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “He loved you, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? Did you love him? You did love him, didn&amp;rsquo;t you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Yes, Amy, I loved him. I love him still.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “What about Grace and little Callum? This is breaking my heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;long pause, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Mine too, Amy. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit together for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;intimate, healing silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father grieves over his broken world, and the suffering his people bear. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with him, and grieve also, in the intimacy of his healing presence. And in the meantime,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us. For the creation waits in eager expectation for the children of God to be revealed. For the creation was subjected to frustration, not by its own choice, but by the will of the one who subjected it, in hope that the creation itself will be liberated from its bondage to decay and brought into the freedom and glory of the children of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:18-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit with the Lord in the silence of the unanswered prayer, Amy, in the intimacy of his healing presence 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Receiving the kingdom of God like a little child</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/joice-kelly-38MGlMtsZyc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Receiving the kingdom of God like a little child" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to receive the kingdom of God like a little child?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a vital question!  Jesus himself said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, anyone who will not receive the kingdom of God like a little child will never enter it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must fathom this then!  Let&amp;rsquo;s consider three aspects of a little child&amp;rsquo;s relationship with their earthly parents, and infer how to receive from our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the little child trusts, absolutely. When the parent says it is so, or tells of something they will do, the child never doubts for a moment. The child wastes no energy at all worrying about it. They count on it, as if it were already so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the little child depends, completely. In fact their life makes no sense unless the parent provides, protects, cares, loves. They are wholly dependent. It is the very nature of the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, have you ever observed a little child anticipating something to come, something wonderful, like Christmas? They are so excited! The expectation can be almost too much to bear. And as the event approaches, the excitement grows, contagiously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us receive the kingdom of God like this. Our Heavenly Father is utterly reliable, and so very good. We can wholly lean on him, fully committed. He loves us deeply, has promised so much, and is able to do immeasurably more than all we ask or imagine. Could anything be more exciting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust, depend, and be excited, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Throwing a mountain into the sea</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:36:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/sulthan-auliya-WLORfDtl7oM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Throwing a mountain into the sea" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we throw a mountain into the sea?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a ridiculous question! It&amp;rsquo;s clearly impossible. And yet, Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would Jesus say such a thing? Is he mocking us? Is he exaggerating? Is he lying, even?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone tells us something that is hard to accept, how we receive it depends critically on who they are, and what we know of them. Can we trust? And what reason do we have for that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many years, I have learnt that I can trust Jesus absolutely. I&amp;rsquo;m quite a slow learner, and have doubted in various ways for so much of my life, but no longer. I choose therefore to believe that Jesus was telling the truth when he said this impossible thing. What do I make of it then? I have to relate it to other things I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said a similar thing to his disciples at the Last Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here we have the caveat, “in my name”. I can only ask for something in Jesus&#39; name if he would have asked for the same. That&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful guideline for praying in power, and it defines my own expectation in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I choose to believe Jesus. I can&amp;rsquo;t throw a mountain into the sea, only because I cannot escape my own doubt about that. I acknowledge that as the reason. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t doubt, it would be so. That is on me. Jesus is trustworthy and true, and he speaks truth. And there are so many other things I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; pray for, believing, not doubting. Impossible things, even. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray in power, Amy, believing and not doubting! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hard teaching</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 06:39:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/maranda-vandergriff-9mqdPNk2Xwc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hard teaching" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain passages or verses in the Bible are really hard to understand. How should we approach them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intention this week was to write about telling a mountain to throw itself into the sea, not doubting. But when I looked into the context, I found that Jesus said it after cursing the fig tree on approaching Jerusalem for the last week of his life. How do we understand that? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about that first, and I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to the mountain another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The next day as they were leaving Bethany, Jesus was hungry. Seeing in the distance a fig tree in leaf, he went to find out if it had any fruit. When he reached it, he found nothing but leaves, because it was not the season for figs. Then he said to the tree, “May no one ever eat fruit from you again.” And his disciples heard him say it. &amp;hellip; In the morning, as they went along, they saw the fig tree withered from the roots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:12-14, 20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this reasonable? It was not the season for figs! This seems so harsh. It is certainly hard to understand. What should we do with passages like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we ought not to anthropomorphize the tree. It was just a tree. It served a purpose, to illustrate a teaching point of Jesus. Nobody suffered in the making of this point. But still!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst comment I read about this explained that first fruits appear early, and Jesus would have expected there to be figs for that reason. But Mark would have known that, and would have said, there were no first fruits. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t the reason given! Let us not second guess the gospel writers. The Lord is responsible for his own reputation, and has no need of our defence, no need of our pitiful attempts to make him look good. Let us not brush aside these difficulties with bogus explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was about to suffer and die, for the sins of all humanity. This was God&amp;rsquo;s plan, and it required rejection and brutal treatment of the Son of God by those who should have been fruitful for the Kingdom, but were not. Was the fig tree a symbol of the Jews who rejected Jesus? It was not their season to be fruitful, and they were severely judged. Is this harsh? It is a hard teaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cannot claim perfect understanding of the mysteries of God. But as we grapple, let us do so with intellectual integrity, being faithful to Scripture, and honouring the Lord. And may we continue to love and trust him when the limits of our understanding are exceeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love and trust, Amy, and don&amp;rsquo;t stop grappling! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/melissa-askew-8n00CqwnqO8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 27 pretty much has it all. Here are the highlights.  “The LORD is my light and my salvation &amp;hellip; the stronghold of my life (v1). One thing I ask from the LORD &amp;hellip; that I may dwell in the house of the LORD all the days of my life (v4). He will keep me safe in his dwelling &amp;hellip; and set me high upon a rock (v5). Your face, LORD, I will seek (v8).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantly reminding ourselves of these things, and living them every day, every moment, is part of it. But then out of the blue comes v9, which suddenly expresses doubt and fear of rejection.  “Do not hide your face from me, do not turn your servant away in anger; you have been my helper. Do not reject me or forsake me, God my Saviour.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such sentiments occur throughout the Psalms, and this by the grace of God. Let&amp;rsquo;s try to understand why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s wisdom is beyond understanding, let&amp;rsquo;s first acknowledge that. He has plans and purposes, and they are good. He desires us to walk by faith, to trust him absolutely, and he loves us, ruthlessly. That&amp;rsquo;s an uncomfortable word! The walk of faith is not comfortable, nor should we expect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while it can feel, at times overwhelmingly, like he has turned his face away and rejected us, he has not. He alone knows what he is doing, and he is deeply invested in us. That rejection is what Jesus received on the cross, so we never have to. And that is why we can assert with the Psalmist, “I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living.” (v13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we live confidently? “Wait for the LORD; be strong and take heart and wait for the LORD.” (v14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be strong and take heart and wait for the Lord, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently when the future is uncertain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/arthur-ogleznev-rWDumHFt8E8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently when the future is uncertain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently when the future is uncertain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things we would like to know. What will I do with my life? Will it be worthwhile? How will I live? Will I be able to use the talents God has given me for his glory? Where will I go? Is my soul mate out there somewhere? Will I be alone? How can I know I will be ok? Why won&amp;rsquo;t God tell me these things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the Lord does not tell us such things ahead of time, and nor should we expect it. If he does reveal something, as he occasionally does, even an incredible and specific promise, it is unlikely to be how or when. What is my part then? What must I do? I must trust him, and I must live for him with my whole heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the first thing I wrote to you Amy, back in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By choosing to trust, to walk by faith, with all of our hope in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s unfailing love, we can delight him. I will say it again. We can delight him! Without uncertainty there can be no faith, so let us embrace it, and show the Lord that we really can walk by faith. What an opportunity to show him that! There is no risk, really. Read Psalm 145 again, and believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 06:54:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/joe-johannes-qVcs4k1H_4k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just wondering how you are coping with the heat over there, Amy. And that made me think of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But blessed is the one who trusts in the LORD, whose confidence is in him. They will be like a tree planted by the water that sends out its roots by the stream. It does not fear when heat comes; its leaves are always green. It has no worries in a year of drought and never fails to bear fruit.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 17:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s monsoon season there, so enjoy the irony. Praying for you 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
