<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>creation on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/creation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in creation on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/creation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Soaring on wings like an eagle</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/soaring-on-wings-like-an-eagle/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/soaring-on-wings-like-an-eagle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/soaring-on-wings-like-an-eagle/marcus-woodbridge-0s81Kf6lWzY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Soaring on wings like an eagle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often do you soar like an eagle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But they who wait for the LORD shall renew their strength; they shall mount up with wings like eagles; they shall run and not be weary; they shall walk and not faint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you journey through each day faithfully serving the Lord, is this your experience? My utmost desire for you is that it is! But as I observe those around me here also faithfully serving the Lord, I don&amp;rsquo;t see much soaring. Instead I see the opposite⸺weariness and exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that? Why is it so hard to experience this? And why was it also not the experience of those to whom these words were originally spoken? For it was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two reasons. For the first we must consider these words in their original context. They are such familiar words but perhaps the context gets overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These words were spoken to the Israelites in their exile in Babylon⸺that exile which was the judgment of a holy God upon an unholy people, a people chosen by the Lord but characterised by stubbornly ongoing waywardness and apostasy. It was a just and righteous judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these words were delivered with a sharp rebuke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why do you say, O Jacob, and speak, O Israel, “My way is hidden from the LORD, and my right is disregarded by my God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the first reason for absence of soaring: believing that the Lord is ignorant of or indifferent to one&amp;rsquo;s situation. That is, thinking he either does not know or does not care. We could observe that perhaps the Israelites in their Babylonian exile more than anyone else were justified in thinking this. But no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the rebuke:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have you not known? Have you not heard? The LORD is the everlasting God, the Creator of the ends of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not one who is ignorant of anything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of that insidious presumption of indifference? For this there&amp;rsquo;s another rebuke. Isaiah has another rebuke for anyone who even flirts with the idea that the Lord is indifferent to their cause. It is a rebuke bound up in his prophecy of the Messiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Out of the anguish of his soul he shall see and be satisfied; by his knowledge shall the righteous one, my servant, make many to be accounted righteous, and he shall bear their iniquities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 53:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contemplate the anguish of his soul that Jesus would endure, out of which he would make many to be accounted righteous, bearing their iniquities. He was and is so invested in his rescued ones! We can be sure of that because of the enormous price that he would pay, the cost that he would bear. How could anyone possibly behold that and surmise indifference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only the first of the two reasons that prevent one soaring like an eagle. It must be thoroughly repudiated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:31-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father both knows each one of us intimately and cares so tenderly and he will not hold back rescue and blessing beyond imagining. This is the first and foremost enabler for soaring, that we rest confidently in that glorious truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest confidently in the unfailing love and faithfulness and boundless generosity and kindness of our most wonderful God, Amy, so you may be ready to soar on wings like an eagle! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Creation</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/creation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/creation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/creation/apollo_17_blue_marble_photo_dec_7_1972_as17-148-22727.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Creation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we reclaim the glorious and majestic creation story of Genesis 1 from those who would have us cringe in embarrassment at the naivety of it all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hasn&amp;rsquo;t science come along and explained the universe? Hasn&amp;rsquo;t evolution come along and explained life itself? In these modern times hadn&amp;rsquo;t we better simply keep our heads down about this whole outdated, unsophisticated, and frankly ignominious description? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth. The earth was without form and void, and darkness was over the face of the deep. And the Spirit of God was hovering over the face of the waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light. And God saw that the light was good. And God separated the light from the darkness. God called the light Day, and the darkness he called Night. And there was evening and there was morning, the first day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since what I wrote last week began with what was so very dark, I have been musing on light, and my musing brought me to this. Let&amp;rsquo;s revel in the first day of creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have Father, Son, and Holy Spirit in intimate relationship, in the dance of the Trinity, an articulation of mutual love even before humankind is brought into existence. Can you sense the delight in anticipation in the hovering even before God speaks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need the introduction to John&amp;rsquo;s gospel to compete our picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through him, and without him was not any thing made that was made. In him was life, and the life was the light of men. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 1:1-5, 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the brief account in Genesis 1, God the Father speaks the universe into existence, and Jesus is the agent of creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this work? Wow! How bold am I even to try to dig into such a mystery?! But I have a simple analogy that has helped my own understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want to scratch my ear, I merely think it and it is so. You could say I speak to my arm and it lifts, and to my finger and it scratches. It works like this because it is my own body and I have power over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entirety of the universe belongs to the Lord and he has absolute power over it. It is as much connected to his commands as my own arm is to mine. What an awesome God we serve! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then we come to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And there was evening and there was morning, the first day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here some people start wringing their hands in embarrassment, and others start trying to calculate the age of the earth. But both responses are inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hebrew word here translated day is &lt;em&gt;yôm&lt;/em&gt;. The same word appears throughout the Old Testament with various translations. Here&amp;rsquo;s just one example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus David the son of Jesse reigned over all Israel. The &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt; that he reigned over Israel was forty years. He reigned seven years in Hebron and thirty-three years in Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 29:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;yôm&lt;/em&gt; for reigning over Israel was forty years. And furthermore, when we notice that God didn&amp;rsquo;t even create the sun, moon, and stars until the fourth day, perhaps we can stop worrying about what a day means in the creation story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God the Father who loves us, Jesus his only Son who saves us, and the Holy Spirit who lives in us, together created the universe and all that is in it, in a display of unspeakable power and wisdom and creativity. Let&amp;rsquo;s rest unashamedly in the mystery and majesty of that and praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise the Three in One who created it all, Amy, and try not to let your head explode with the vastness and wonder of it all! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The heavens declare the glory of God</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 06:26:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/martin-jernberg-UdURxHDhrgY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The heavens declare the glory of God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 19 starts like this. The heavens declare the glory of God; the skies proclaim the work of his hands. Day after day they pour forth speech; night after night they display knowledge. There is no speech or language where their voice is not heard. Their voice goes out into all the earth, their words to the ends of the world. (And it continues with real soul food.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole of creation bears witness to the glory and majesty of the Lord!  Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is indeed awe and wonder to be found in the night sky. As a Northerner, however, from where I live now it is quite unsettling to see Orion doing a hand stand. I wonder how he behaves on the equator. 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems appropriate therefore to turn these verses upside down. So my prayer is that you experience the Lord revealing himself to you in the small things too. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
