<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>mystery on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/mystery/</link>
        <description>Recent content in mystery on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/mystery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The desire of the sower</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-desire-of-the-sower/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-desire-of-the-sower/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-desire-of-the-sower/melissa-askew-y4xZxzN754M-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The desire of the sower" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the desire of the sower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when a great crowd was gathering and people from town after town came to him, [Jesus] said in a parable, “A sower went out to sow his seed. And as he sowed, some fell along the path and was trampled underfoot, and the birds of the air devoured it. And some fell on the rock, and as it grew up, it withered away, because it had no moisture. And some fell among thorns, and the thorns grew up with it and choked it. And some fell into good soil and grew and yielded a hundredfold.” As he said these things, he called out, “He who has ears to hear, let him hear.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 8:4-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all three synoptic gospels where Jesus refers to the prophecy from Isaiah 6:9-10 it is in the context of the parable of the sower (Matthew 13:1-23, Mark 4:1-20, Luke 8:4-15). Let&amp;rsquo;s ponder that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when his disciples asked him what this parable meant, he said, “To you it has been given to know the secrets of the kingdom of God, but for others they are in parables, so that ‘seeing they may not see, and hearing they may not understand.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 8:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This prophecy is just so uncomfortable, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Let&amp;rsquo;s just see if we can relate it to what we know of the goodness and kindness and steadfast love and faithfulness of our heavenly father by asking, what is the desire of the sower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t you ever wondered this: the sower was really quite a bad farmer, wasn&amp;rsquo;t he? Why was he so profligate in his sowing? What a waste to sow that precious seed in all the wrong places! But was it really wasteful? Or is this nothing less than God&amp;rsquo;s super-abundant generosity and grace towards unrepentant sinners?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And consider Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent cry, his most impassioned invitation: “He who has ears to hear, let him hear.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is the desire of the sower? And why is the message of salvation wrapped up in parables, shrouded in mystery? Jeremiah has a clue for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you, declares the LORD &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus underlines exactly this in the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one who seeks, and seeks with all their heart, that one will find. The gospel is not a spectator sport. But for those who cry out for mercy and seek with all their heart, to these is the Kingdom revealed. In his great wisdom and mercy and kindness, so has the Lord made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust the Lord, Amy, in his plans and purposes to rescue and redeem all of humankind, he knows what he is doing and it is very good! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The elephant in the room</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-elephant-in-the-room/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-elephant-in-the-room/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-elephant-in-the-room/atwena-goodman-PB4dNSELi_E-unsplash-cropped.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The elephant in the room" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the elephant in the room of Isaiah 6?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s vision of the Lord seated on a throne, high and exalted, is a glimpse into heaven itself and convicts him deeply of his own sinfulness. We should be similarly convicted. But immediately after his guilt is taken away and his sin atoned for, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And I heard the voice of the Lord saying, “Whom shall I send, and who will go for us?” Then I said, “Here I am! Send me.” And he said, “Go, and say to this people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘Keep on hearing, but do not understand; keep on seeing, but do not perceive.’ Make the heart of this people dull, and their ears heavy, and blind their eyes; lest they see with their eyes, and hear with their ears, and understand with their hearts,
and turn and be healed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:8-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we to make of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said a similar thing to his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the disciples came and said to him, “Why do you speak to them in parables?” And he answered them, “To you it has been given to know the secrets of the kingdom of heaven, but to them it has not been given. For to the one who has, more will be given, and he will have an abundance, but from the one who has not, even what he has will be taken away. This is why I speak to them in parables, because seeing they do not see, and hearing they do not hear, nor do they understand. Indeed, in their case the prophecy of Isaiah is fulfilled &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:10-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must understand this in the context of the verbs that the Lord uses when commanding Isaiah: make the heart of this people dull, and their ears heavy, and blind their eyes. This is not a passive observation of failure to understand. It is the actual cause. To them it has not been given. The Lord himself confounds the understanding of the lost, lest they turn and be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we to make of it? And how is it remotely fair?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we must not brush this aside merely because it offends our sensibilities. May we never presume so to stand in judgment on the revealed word of God. He is sovereign, not us. So we must grapple, and we must grapple in the context of what we know to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then do we know to be true? Behold God&amp;rsquo;s own description of himself, his response to Moses&amp;rsquo; request, please show me now your ways, that I may know you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had no right to expect that the infinitely powerful creator God of the universe, glorious in splendour and terrifying in holiness, would be quite so good and kind. But we must not overlook that the Lord, whose name is Jealous, is a jealous God (Exodus 34:14). Nor must we overlook the judgment to the third and fourth generation, nor the steadfast love to the thousandth generation, nor the orders of magnitude difference between these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately our response will be the same as Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I said, “How long, O Lord?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord? We have grappled with this before. But here we must notice something else, even after the land has become a desolate waste, and after the burning again of the tenth that remains⸺terebinth or oak, whose stump remains when it is felled: &lt;em&gt;the holy seed is its stump&lt;/em&gt; (Isaiah 6:13)⸺hope remains! With God, all things are possible, and hope remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in the mystery of the confounding, Amy, know that all his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness, and that hope remains! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The visit of the magi</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-visit-of-the-magi/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 08:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-visit-of-the-magi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-visit-of-the-magi/inbal-malca-NhlKx6Uvm3E-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The visit of the magi" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from the visit of the magi?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much in this story which is noteworthy. Let&amp;rsquo;s notice afresh just three of these oddities, and see if we can understand in them something of the mystery of God&amp;rsquo;s ways, remembering that such Bible stories were not written to satisfy our curiosity nor merely for our edification. Rather they were written to bring us into relationship with our Heavenly Father and to grow us in that relationship. So, who they were, their strange gifts, and the nature of that star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now after Jesus was born in Bethlehem of Judea in the days of Herod the king, behold, wise men from the east came to Jerusalem, saying, “Where is he who has been born king of the Jews? For we saw his star when it rose and have come to worship him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After listening to the king, they went on their way. And behold, the star that they had seen when it rose went before them until it came to rest over the place where the child was. When they saw the star, they rejoiced exceedingly with great joy. And going into the house, they saw the child with Mary his mother, and they fell down and worshipped him. Then, opening their treasures, they offered him gifts, gold and frankincense and myrrh. And being warned in a dream not to return to Herod, they departed to their own country by another way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 2:1-2, 9-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the east we don&amp;rsquo;t know where they came from⸺perhaps Babylon or maybe somewhere further afield⸺but we do know they weren&amp;rsquo;t Jews. They were pagans from a faraway land, nevertheless coming to worship the Son of God. Jesus was so much more than the king of the Jews. He came to save all of humankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, those strange gifts: gold for kingship, frankincense for deity, and myrrh for death. Can you imagine the conversation when they were packing? “Hey Melchior, why are you taking myrrh? That&amp;rsquo;s for embalming dead bodies. It&amp;rsquo;s such a weird gift for a baby!” Surely he didn&amp;rsquo;t even know why myrrh was the right gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that “star” which the magi first saw when it rose, which then seems to have disappeared on them such that they had to enter Jerusalem and ask around, where was the one they had come to worship? The result of which was, rather than quietly arriving at their precise destination, the whole of Jerusalem got to know what was happening. How interesting! As soon as that had happened, the star reappeared and guided them right to the house where Jesus was. Clearly no kind of star or celestial object then, but surely rather some angelic guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now consider, how could it all have happened like this? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s ways are so deeply mysterious and here rather opaque. He is however so fully able to achieve his plans and purposes, outworking them even through fallible individuals lacking understanding, but nevertheless bringing glory to his name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And going into the house, they saw the child with Mary his mother, and they fell down and worshipped him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank the Lord, Amy, for his wisdom, for the mystery of his ways, and for the greatest gift which is Christ the Lord, and worship him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A mystery revealed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 06:38:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/david-clode-EDfZ0Sjmp_w-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A mystery revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know a mystery?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God’s grace that he lavished on us. With all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will according to his good pleasure, which he purposed in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an alternate reality, the Lord could have dealt with our sin as he did, and simply told us, it&amp;rsquo;s ok, we can be friends again, I&amp;rsquo;ve sorted it out. But in our reality, &lt;em&gt;with all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will&lt;/em&gt;. He desires us to know just what our rescue cost him, and what it cost his only son, as he lavished his grace on us. As he continues to lavish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have redemption &lt;em&gt;through his blood&lt;/em&gt;. The cost was enormous. The love that paid this price, unfathomable. The forgiveness of sins and restoration of relationship with our Heavenly Father, beyond all worth. And the revelation of this mystery, according to his good pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we understand what has been done for us, and why? The Lord desires that we do. If we really grasp this, won&amp;rsquo;t it magnify our love for him a hundredfold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know the mystery, Amy, and love the author of the mystery who has made it known! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
