<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>mystery on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/mystery/</link>
        <description>Recent content in mystery on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 08:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/mystery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The visit of the magi</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-visit-of-the-magi/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 08:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-visit-of-the-magi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-visit-of-the-magi/inbal-malca-NhlKx6Uvm3E-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The visit of the magi" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from the visit of the magi?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much in this story which is noteworthy. Let&amp;rsquo;s notice afresh just three of these oddities, and see if we can understand in them something of the mystery of God&amp;rsquo;s ways, remembering that such Bible stories were not written to satisfy our curiosity nor merely for our edification. Rather they were written to bring us into relationship with our Heavenly Father and to grow us in that relationship. So, who they were, their strange gifts, and the nature of that star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now after Jesus was born in Bethlehem of Judea in the days of Herod the king, behold, wise men from the east came to Jerusalem, saying, “Where is he who has been born king of the Jews? For we saw his star when it rose and have come to worship him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After listening to the king, they went on their way. And behold, the star that they had seen when it rose went before them until it came to rest over the place where the child was. When they saw the star, they rejoiced exceedingly with great joy. And going into the house, they saw the child with Mary his mother, and they fell down and worshipped him. Then, opening their treasures, they offered him gifts, gold and frankincense and myrrh. And being warned in a dream not to return to Herod, they departed to their own country by another way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 2:1-2, 9-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the east we don&amp;rsquo;t know where they came from⸺perhaps Babylon or maybe somewhere further afield⸺but we do know they weren&amp;rsquo;t Jews. They were pagans from a faraway land, nevertheless coming to worship the Son of God. Jesus was so much more than the king of the Jews. He came to save all of humankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, those strange gifts: gold for kingship, frankincense for deity, and myrrh for death. Can you imagine the conversation when they were packing? “Hey Melchior, why are you taking myrrh? That&amp;rsquo;s for embalming dead bodies. It&amp;rsquo;s such a weird gift for a baby!” Surely he didn&amp;rsquo;t even know why myrrh was the right gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that “star” which the magi first saw when it rose, which then seems to have disappeared on them such that they had to enter Jerusalem and ask around, where was the one they had come to worship? The result of which was, rather than quietly arriving at their precise destination, the whole of Jerusalem got to know what was happening. How interesting! As soon as that had happened, the star reappeared and guided them right to the house where Jesus was. Clearly no kind of star or celestial object then, but surely rather some angelic guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now consider, how could it all have happened like this? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s ways are so deeply mysterious and here rather opaque. He is however so fully able to achieve his plans and purposes, outworking them even through fallible individuals lacking understanding, but nevertheless bringing glory to his name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And going into the house, they saw the child with Mary his mother, and they fell down and worshipped him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank the Lord, Amy, for his wisdom, for the mystery of his ways, and for the greatest gift which is Christ the Lord, and worship him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A mystery revealed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 06:38:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/david-clode-EDfZ0Sjmp_w-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A mystery revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know a mystery?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God’s grace that he lavished on us. With all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will according to his good pleasure, which he purposed in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an alternate reality, the Lord could have dealt with our sin as he did, and simply told us, it&amp;rsquo;s ok, we can be friends again, I&amp;rsquo;ve sorted it out. But in our reality, &lt;em&gt;with all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will&lt;/em&gt;. He desires us to know just what our rescue cost him, and what it cost his only son, as he lavished his grace on us. As he continues to lavish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have redemption &lt;em&gt;through his blood&lt;/em&gt;. The cost was enormous. The love that paid this price, unfathomable. The forgiveness of sins and restoration of relationship with our Heavenly Father, beyond all worth. And the revelation of this mystery, according to his good pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we understand what has been done for us, and why? The Lord desires that we do. If we really grasp this, won&amp;rsquo;t it magnify our love for him a hundredfold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know the mystery, Amy, and love the author of the mystery who has made it known! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
