<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patience in waiting</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-waiting/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we grow in patience?
 The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; patience
― Galatians 5:22 My dictionary defines patience like this:
 patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/
▸ noun [mass noun]
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious
― Oxford Dictionary of English Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on delay for now. So, how can we grow in patience in the face of delay?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentleness</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/gentleness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/gentleness/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is the most Christlike response we can give to an angry, frustrated, hostile, hurting world?
 The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; gentleness
― Galatians 5:22-23 The first thing to note about the fruit of the Spirit is that there is only one fruit (“the fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip;”), and that fruit has nine characteristics. I may take nine weeks over this, let&amp;rsquo;s see!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rescued life</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-rescued-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 06:28:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-rescued-life/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What difference does it make to have been rescued?
Cycling back from Karitane on Sunday afternoon, I saw my neighbours walking up the hill and stopped to say hello. They asked about the awful thing that happened to me in Rarotonga. Word evidently gets around! Instead I told them about the wonderful, impossible thing which happened, which resulted in me being alive and not dead.
Then I found myself saying, “every day feels like a bonus now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiant disciples</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?
 Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.
― Psalm 34:5 When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:
 His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescue</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/rescue/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How many times will the Lord rescue? Isn&amp;rsquo;t once enough?
 “Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”
― Psalm 91:14 To be honest, my Bible actually says this:
 “Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”
 But gender is of no consequence here. What matters is this: the pronoun is singular.
Some think the only rescue is the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saves us from our sin and brings us into relationship with our Heavenly Father, but that&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taste and see that the Lord is good</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we obey a command if we don&amp;rsquo;t know what it means?
Obviously we can&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s a rhetorical question. What of this then?
 Taste and see that the LORD is good.
― Psalm 34:8 This is clearly an instruction to do something. It&amp;rsquo;s a command. Notice that David could have written, Behold! The Lord is good (because he is). That&amp;rsquo;s a true statement, but it&amp;rsquo;s not what he wrote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?
 [Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you &amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”
― Matthew 7:7, 11  “You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”
― John 14:14 But unanswered prayer is a real thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we know for sure that all we are hoping for in eternity is real, and that it will be as promised?
I think I&amp;rsquo;m just about ready to leave this desert island, and I see a boat on the horizon (yay!), but first let&amp;rsquo;s look into Ephesians 1 for one last time.
 And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A mystery revealed</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-mystery-revealed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 06:38:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-mystery-revealed/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we know a mystery?
 In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God’s grace that he lavished on us. With all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will according to his good pleasure, which he purposed in Christ.
― Ephesians 1:7-9 In an alternate reality, the Lord could have dealt with our sin as he did, and simply told us, it&amp;rsquo;s ok, we can be friends again, I&amp;rsquo;ve sorted it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The eyes of your heart</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:31:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What are the eyes of our heart for?
I&amp;rsquo;m still stuck on this desert island, reading Ephesians 1. It is not a bad place to be! Consider what Paul writes about the eyes of our heart. (The heart is the seat of life and strength, the centre of one&amp;rsquo;s will. That is mind, soul, spirit, one&amp;rsquo;s entire emotional nature and understanding.) Paul writes:
 I pray also that the eyes of your heart may be enlightened in order that you may know the hope to which he has called you, the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and his incomparably great power for us who believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predestination</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/predestination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/predestination/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What&amp;rsquo;s all this about predestination? Don&amp;rsquo;t people have a right to choose for themselves?
As I swing in my hammock on that desert island, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do except read Ephesians 1. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I find.
 He chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. In love he predestined us to be adopted as his children through Jesus Christ, in accordance with his pleasure and will (v4, 5) &amp;hellip; In him we were also chosen, having been predestined according to the plan of him who works out everything in conformity with the purpose of his will, in order that we, who were the first to hope in Christ, might be for the praise of his glory (v11, 12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desert island</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/desert-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 06:43:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/desert-island/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
If you could take only one chapter of the Bible with you to a desert island, which would you choose?
Without a doubt, my pick would be Ephesians Chapter One. I cannot possibly do the whole chapter justice in this short letter, so for now let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one verse. (I may have to return to the wider chapter another time. Perhaps several times!)
“I keep asking that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the glorious Father, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and revelation, so that you &amp;hellip; ” (v17)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith that changes the course of nations</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What does faith that changes the course of nations look like?
We see something of it in the story of Naaman, in 2 Kings 5. The Lord had given victory to Syria through Naaman, the commander of the Syrian army (v1, how interesting), who suffered from leprosy. Previously, the Syrians had taken captives from Israel, and among them was a young girl, now a slave in the house of Naaman (v2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greetings</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/greetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/greetings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What&amp;rsquo;s in a greeting?
To Amy, who is loved by God and called to be one of the saints (Rom 1:7).
To Amy, sanctified in Christ Jesus and called to be holy (1 Cor 1:2).
To Amy, one of the faithful in Christ Jesus (Eph 1:1).
To Amy, one of the saints in Christ Jesus (Phil 1:1).
To Amy, a faithful sister in Christ (Col 1:2).
To Amy in God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ (1 Thes 1:1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Receiving the kingdom of God like a little child</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What does it mean to receive the kingdom of God like a little child?
What a vital question! Jesus himself said:
 “Truly I tell you, anyone who will not receive the kingdom of God like a little child will never enter it.”
― Luke 18:17 We must fathom this then! Let&amp;rsquo;s consider three aspects of a little child&amp;rsquo;s relationship with their earthly parents, and infer how to receive from our Heavenly Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The thorn in Paul&#39;s flesh</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What exactly was Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn anyway, and why does it matter?
There has been much speculation about the nature of Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn in the flesh (2 Cor 12:7-9), and of course we do not know. Personally, I doubt it was any disability, of speech or of stature, nor any severe pain to endure. Rather I suspect it was something utterly shameful and humiliating, perhaps something in his own character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Throwing a mountain into the sea</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:36:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we throw a mountain into the sea?
What a ridiculous question! It&amp;rsquo;s clearly impossible. And yet, Jesus said,
 “Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.”
― Mark 11:23 Why would Jesus say such a thing? Is he mocking us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard teaching</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/hard-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 06:39:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/hard-teaching/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Certain passages or verses in the Bible are really hard to understand. How should we approach them?
My intention this week was to write about telling a mountain to throw itself into the sea, not doubting. But when I looked into the context, I found that Jesus said it after cursing the fig tree on approaching Jerusalem for the last week of his life. How do we understand that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectant and not disappointed</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we be expectant and not disappointed?
Living with high expectations of oneself and others is surely right, but can lead to ongoing disappointment, as we and those around us fall short of what we aspired to do and to be. How can the same not be true of the Lord?
What should we expect of the Lord anyway? “I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full” (Jn 10:10).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we live confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s love?
Psalm 27 pretty much has it all. Here are the highlights. “The LORD is my light and my salvation &amp;hellip; the stronghold of my life (v1). One thing I ask from the LORD &amp;hellip; that I may dwell in the house of the LORD all the days of my life (v4). He will keep me safe in his dwelling &amp;hellip; and set me high upon a rock (v5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the Lord want us to do?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 06:51:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What does the Lord want us to do?
Surely there must be some special work that he&amp;rsquo;s calling us to. Something that we have to carefully and prayerfully uncover, so we can live the life he has planned, and do the work he has for us. Surely?
Jesus was once asked exactly this.
 “What must we do to do the works God requires?” Jesus answered, “The work of God is this: to believe in the one he has sent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The heavens declare the glory of God</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 06:26:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Psalm 19 starts like this. The heavens declare the glory of God; the skies proclaim the work of his hands. Day after day they pour forth speech; night after night they display knowledge. There is no speech or language where their voice is not heard. Their voice goes out into all the earth, their words to the ends of the world. (And it continues with real soul food.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing grace</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/experiencing-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 06:32:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/experiencing-grace/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we better perceive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s grace in all we experience, and what would that mean?
Life is full of frustrations and disappointments. Even for the Christian seeking the Lord with all of our heart, living a surrendered life, putting him first in everything, things may not turn out as we would have wished. And that&amp;rsquo;s not just small things. The whole course of one&amp;rsquo;s life could turn out to be so different from what was desired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking by faith</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 06:52:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What happens when we walk by faith?
Perhaps the greatest example we have is Abraham. He didn&amp;rsquo;t always get it right, nor did he manage always to trust, as shown by his shabby little misdeed with Hagar. Evidently not super-human then! But the Lord called him again out of that particular failure thirteen years later, out of the absolute mess he had made (“walk before me and be blameless” - Gen 17:1), after he had been waiting for the fulfillment of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promise to him for 25 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living confidently when the future is uncertain</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we live confidently when the future is uncertain?
There are so many things we would like to know. What will I do with my life? Will it be worthwhile? How will I live? Will I be able to use the talents God has given me for his glory? Where will I go? Is my soul mate out there somewhere? Will I be alone? How can I know I will be ok?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On being vulnerable</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/on-being-vulnerable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/on-being-vulnerable/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Why is it so important to be vulnerable?
Our every instinct is to protect and defend, to justify ourselves, and yet we must not do it! Why is this? Paul wrote to the Corinthians about his vision and the thorn in his flesh, concluding:
 The Lord said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly about my weaknesses, so that Christ’s power may rest on me &amp;hellip; I delight in weaknesses &amp;hellip; for when I am weak, then I am strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pharisaical heart</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-pharisaical-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 06:46:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-pharisaical-heart/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What breaks our Father&amp;rsquo;s heart? That would be a long list to be sure. I&amp;rsquo;ll pick one thing.
Recently I got to see Les Misérables at the Regent. What a tremendous story of redemption, the power of love flowing through a redeemed life, and the triumph of love over adversity. But also so very sad — I was grateful for the darkness in the theatre, so no-one could see my tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Who am I?
What a vital question that is for any of us. It could take some time to answer! In fact, I have had to revisit it myself in recent years.
The most valiant attempt I know of to grapple with this is by Dietrich Bonhoeffer, a German pastor who was imprisoned in Flossenbürg concentration camp by the Nazis during World War II. He was executed just one month before the end of the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is life so hard?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Why is life so hard?
Consider: the young person, to whom life seems so bleak they turn to self harm to try to anchor to reality; the older person who lives alone, who may go days without speaking with another, having long forgotten what it&amp;rsquo;s like to give and receive a hug; the faithful believer waiting on the Lord for the fulfillment of a promise, praising him in the heart-breaking years of waiting, or the one crying out for healing and enduring debilitating pain in the waiting and the praising; the grief in the death of a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we love the Lord this much?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we love the Lord this much?
There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Revelation 4:8, where the four living creatures, day and night, never stop saying: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.” And in Revelation 5:9, where together with the twenty-four elders, they sing to Jesus, “&amp;hellip; you were slain, and by your blood you ransomed people for God from every tribe and language and people and nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much can we love the Lord?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How much can we love the Lord?
Recently in church we were invited to speak out our praise to God. Woefully, every single prayer was me and us. What self-obsession! Is there any deliverance from this? Wonderfully there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s to be found in Revelation, chapters 4 and 5. Lose yourself in that for a while. Hear a hundred million angels and every creature singing:
 “Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength and honour and glory and praise!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The truth will set you free</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 06:42:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
 Jesus said, “If you hold to my teaching &amp;hellip; then you will know the truth &amp;hellip;”
― John 8:31-32 Truth is more important now than ever, given the post-truth world in which we live, where people are inclined to define their own truth. Christians are not immune.
We are never more vulnerable than when we say, “the Lord told me &amp;hellip;” What exactly do we mean by this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect love drives out fear</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Here&amp;rsquo;s another observation on plain old fear, also from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter. The punchline is &amp;ldquo;perfect love drives out fear&amp;rdquo; (1 Jn 4:18), but to understand what he is saying you have to read the whole passage — the golden rule, always!
I&amp;rsquo;ll string some of it together. &amp;ldquo;If we love one another, God lives in us and his love is made complete in us&amp;rdquo; (v12). &amp;ldquo;Love is made complete &amp;hellip; because in this world we are like him&amp;rdquo; (v17).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain old fear</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
There&amp;rsquo;s the fear of the Lord, and there&amp;rsquo;s plain old fear, and the two are mutually exclusive. Consider plain old fear. Fear that disempowers. Debilitates. Disembowels. Fear that blinds, and blindness that feeds fear, in a downward spiral. To see how to end it, understand how it begins. It begins with lies.
God doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about me (1 Jn 4:9-10). God has no use for me (Jer 29:11). God won&amp;rsquo;t keep his promises (Josh 23:14).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid prayer</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Dear God, my God,
You are the Lord of all creation, majestic, sovereign, good, and wise beyond our understanding. Praise your holy name! I lift up to you the situation in Amy&amp;rsquo;s village, with Covid having arrived, and along with it, fear. Forgive us when we doubt your goodness or your sovereignty. I pray the people there would hear Jesus speaking, &amp;ldquo;Peace I leave with you; my peace I give you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness and purification</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 06:44:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Here&amp;rsquo;s a well loved verse from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter, that we may be in danger of reading too quickly and missing the most important word.
 If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.
― 1 John 1:9 There are some important words here. Confess. Sins. And some wonderful, lifting words. Faithful. Forgive. Purify. But what am I referring to?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to grow in reverent awe and wonder</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
So, how do we grow in reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done? Because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just happen. It takes serious get-up-early-and-cry-out-to-God hard work, every single day. Work. But not without incredible joy.
Psalm 119 helps. I won&amp;rsquo;t quote it here, because, well, it&amp;rsquo;s quite long. I have been including the first 32 verses in my daily readings for several years now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 06:43:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we know the will of the Lord? Let&amp;rsquo;s look again into the treasure trove which is Psalm 25.
Who, then, are those who fear the LORD? He will instruct them in the ways he chooses (v12). The LORD confides in those who fear him; he makes his covenant known to them (v14).
Tim Keller defines the fear of the Lord as this, in a sermon from Proverbs on the fear of the Lord being the beginning of wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He guides the humble in what is right</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 06:49:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Here are a couple of verses from Psalm 25 for you:
 Good and upright is the LORD; therefore he instructs sinners in his ways. He guides the humble in what is right and teaches them his way.
― Psalm 25:8-9 Notice the therefore. Meditate on it. Revel in it. See how the Lord desires for us to be holy and blameless, and yet he does not wait for that to be so, to instruct us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 06:54:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</guid>
      <description>Just wondering how you are coping with the heat over there, Amy. And that made me think of this.
 “But blessed is the one who trusts in the LORD, whose confidence is in him. They will be like a tree planted by the water that sends out its roots by the stream. It does not fear when heat comes; its leaves are always green. It has no worries in a year of drought and never fails to bear fruit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace and provision</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:21:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</guid>
      <description>May you know peace from the Lord, and his provision for you, Amy, as you wait on him, and especially when things don&amp;rsquo;t turn out as you expected or hoped. Know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans prevail, and:
 The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.
― Psalm 147:11 🙏</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
