<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sovereignty on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/sovereignty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sovereignty on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/sovereignty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Symphony of Life</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What happens when we pray? Can we actually change the Lord&amp;rsquo;s mind? How could we possibly improve upon his already perfect plans and purposes? Why even ask for anything in prayer then?
These are huge questions, and I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly answer them adequately. But here&amp;rsquo;s a reflection on this, somewhat of an excursion into make-believe, which nevertheless may help to shed some light.
Firstly, note that we are encouraged, nay commanded to pray, and to pray boldly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predestination</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What&amp;rsquo;s all this about predestination? Don&amp;rsquo;t people have a right to choose for themselves?
As I swing in my hammock on that desert island, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do except read Ephesians 1. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I find.
 He chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. In love he predestined us to be adopted as his children through Jesus Christ, in accordance with his pleasure and will (v4, 5) &amp;hellip; In him we were also chosen, having been predestined according to the plan of him who works out everything in conformity with the purpose of his will, in order that we, who were the first to hope in Christ, might be for the praise of his glory (v11, 12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing grace</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 06:32:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we better perceive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s grace in all we experience, and what would that mean?
Life is full of frustrations and disappointments. Even for the Christian seeking the Lord with all of our heart, living a surrendered life, putting him first in everything, things may not turn out as we would have wished. And that&amp;rsquo;s not just small things. The whole course of one&amp;rsquo;s life could turn out to be so different from what was desired.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
