<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>sovereignty on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/sovereignty/</link>
        <description>Recent content in sovereignty on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 06:31:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/sovereignty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Symphony of Life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-symphony-of-life/jack-finnigan-aEkk0KxvPpg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Symphony of Life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when we pray? Can we actually change the Lord&amp;rsquo;s mind? How could we possibly improve upon his already perfect plans and purposes? Why even ask for anything in prayer then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are huge questions, and I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly answer them adequately. But here&amp;rsquo;s a reflection on this, somewhat of an excursion into make-believe, which nevertheless may help to shed some light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, note that we are encouraged, nay commanded to pray, and to pray boldly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pray continually&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you believe, you will receive whatever you ask for in prayer.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 21:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine then. The Lord who created music has himself written the greatest work of all, the Symphony of Life, in 8 billion parts. He is both the composer, and the conductor for its debut and only performance. It is a glorious, majestic work featuring players both unwilling and willing, with plunging depths and soaring heights, human folly and heavenly beneficence, sorrow and joy.  It is a love story, the greatest of them all, a story of rescue and redemption of a wayward people, pieced together from fragments of ruined lives made whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the billions of orchestral members play their parts with quite some improvising, the Lord hears the prayers of the saints, our prayers, and delights to weave them in to the score, making amendments and annotations with his divine pencil even as the music unfolds, taking our imperfect petitions and making them part of his perfect plans and purposes, as it pleases him. And with each, smiling down on his beloved ones with such affection, like a proud father. Smiling on us, who are contributing somehow to his glorious work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at the mystery of his ways, Amy, praising the Lord for his majesty, grace and kindness, and continue praying Kingdom prayers! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Predestination</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/predestination/saiph-muhammad-CSs8aiN_LkI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Predestination" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s all this about predestination? Don&amp;rsquo;t people have a right to choose for themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I swing in my hammock on that desert island, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do except read Ephesians 1. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. In love he predestined us to be adopted as his children through Jesus Christ, in accordance with his pleasure and will (v4, 5) &amp;hellip; In him we were also chosen, having been predestined according to the plan of him who works out everything in conformity with the purpose of his will, in order that we, who were the first to hope in Christ, might be for the praise of his glory (v11, 12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no escaping that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s choice, rather than mine. And that is a wonderful thing. The Lord, the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, does not make mistakes. He chose me. He chose you, Amy, in accordance with his pleasure and will. As for me, I make mistakes, and my own choices are always subject to suspicion and doubt. Not so the Lord! His plans and purposes prevail, for the praise of his glory. I, you, we are both his, forever, and no mistake! And thus we have assurance of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. He chose us to be holy and blameless in his sight. Partly that is an instantaneous, Jesus-died-for-my sins-and-now-I-am-counted-righteous thing. And partly it is a rest-of-my-life thing, as the Holy Spirit continues both to convict me and to empower me to change, as I surrender my will on the pathway to holiness. Both are life-giving, lavish gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what of evangelism? If people are chosen, where is repentance and belief? See what comes next in the passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession — to the praise of his glory (v13, 14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those to whom Paul writes &lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; the message of truth (because someone told them), and &lt;em&gt;believed&lt;/em&gt;. Predestination does not diminish the gospel message in any way. There is undeniably mystery here, but the greatest evangelist of all time was surely &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Paul himself&lt;/em&gt;, who wrote these words. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, and he is yours, forever, because he chose you in him before the creation of the world. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Experiencing grace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 06:32:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/denise-jans-IJy2ZUex0-Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Experiencing grace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we better perceive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s grace in all we experience, and what would that mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is full of frustrations and disappointments. Even for the Christian seeking the Lord with all of our heart, living a surrendered life, putting him first in everything, things may not turn out as we would have wished. And that&amp;rsquo;s not just small things. The whole course of one&amp;rsquo;s life could turn out to be so different from what was desired. Where is our loving Heavenly Father in this? Does he not want to bless his children? Absolutely he does! So what is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote to the Romans this oft-quoted verse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And we know that in all things God works for the good of those who love him, who have been called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider that in the context of Solomon&amp;rsquo;s wisdom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In his heart a man plans his course, but the LORD determines his steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 16:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has hopes and desires for their own life. Some may be sufficiently well organised to have a plan! But the Lord determines their steps. It is his plans and purposes that prevail. Let us not delude ourselves that we can control our own destiny, and somehow plan our way there. That is for the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to dispel a misconception. Paul is not saying that everything that happens is good and is caused by God. That is observably false — terrible things do happen. Rather he is saying that whatever happens, God works in it and through it “for the good of those who love him”. Let us be those!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us learn to see the world through the lens of Romans 8:28 as it actually is then. May we consciously receive God&amp;rsquo;s grace in all that happens. “In all things” let us submit to his superior wisdom, knowing that there is no better eternal outcome than the one he has for us. When apparent disappointments come, let us receive them with a grateful heart. The Lord has seen things that we have not. His love is unfailing. He may very well be rescuing us from something we thought was better, but is in fact not.  He is the one who determines our steps, and it is very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive his grace with a grateful heart in all things, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
