<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>unity on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/unity/</link>
        <description>Recent content in unity on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Taking offence</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/taking-offence/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/taking-offence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/taking-offence/martin-olsen-szfPB4X-FWk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taking offence" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the world&amp;rsquo;s favourite pastime?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it that people love to do? That the whole media machine is geared up to deliver? At which society has become so very accomplished? Here&amp;rsquo;s what: &lt;em&gt;taking offence&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking offence⸺human nature delights in it, Christians too at times, sadly. We love to be outraged. It is almost tribal. People bond over it, which means that people also divide over it, for there is always a source of the offence, and that source is surely a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satan has a field day with this⸺oh how he uses it! What is to be done? Two things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize it for what it is. Offence-taking is not of the Lord. In these days in which we live perhaps it is one of Satan&amp;rsquo;s most potent weapons to bring division in the world, and even between the people of God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live differently. Paul tells us how, and we only just considered this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As a prisoner for the Lord, then, I urge you to live a life worthy of the calling you have received. Be completely humble and gentle; be patient, bearing with one another in love. Make every effort to keep the unity of the Spirit through the bond of peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bearing with one another in love is the key. This is the opposite of offence-taking. What does it look like, this bearing with one another, in love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bear with someone means to be patient, to be tolerant. We are all imperfect, and sometimes we say things that could be misconstrued. Let us receive one another with humility, gentleness and patience, bearing with one another in love. May generous hearts enable us to navigate with wisdom and kindness those pinch points at which offence could so easily be taken. The Lord is glorified as we do, for it is in his Spirit that we are able to do this. Bearing with one another in love is powerfully and relationally healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like this, Amy, and know the joy of the Lord in keeping the unity of the Spirit through the bond of peace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
