<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>healing on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/healing/</link>
        <description>Recent content in healing on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 06:15:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/healing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Comfort and healing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 06:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/kat-j-NPmR0RblyhQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Comfort and healing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing that our God is the God of all comfort and healing, how can we minister this to the brokenhearted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to write about such things when grief and loss are present and quite so raw. But it is precisely at such a time that we must engage with the Lord, and seek to understand, if he is the God of all comfort and healing, which he is, how is that outworked at such a time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At such times we are supposed to be able to comfort those in need with the comfort we ourselves have received from God. But how often do we seem to be of no use in this, not knowing even what to say or do? In the weeping face of heartbreak, how can we in fact be of any comfort at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently been gaining some experience in this, as I am continuing to care for a young friend, a believer in Christ, in the midst of his own trauma, which is ongoing, heartbreaking, and bewildering. In the face of this overwhelming need, the Lord has given me such clarity of understanding of what my friend needs from me, and it is not advice nor explanation nor anything else that I have to say. It is simply Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not matter that I do not know what to say or do. Jesus does. So we cry out to him together for mercy. And he responds, with grace and kindness, impossibly and lavishly. The peace that has come surpasses understanding. The need is ongoing, but so is the grace, and so is the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our own comfort is in Jesus and it is Jesus, and so this is what we must minister to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does it look like, to minister Jesus to the brokenhearted? It looks like gentleness, and kindness, and listening, and prayer, and probably a hug, but most especially time⸺more time than 21st Century western civilization would think is a reasonable investment for a single individual. Not much speaking though. This may come later, but is not I think where we are called to start. And above all else, absolute confidence in the one who is mighty to save, whose name is Helper, Comforter, Healer, Lord, whose name is Jesus. The one who, astonishingly, chooses to do his work of grace through us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us remind ourselves why we praise him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; for he is beautiful, and a song of praise is fitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1, 3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in this, Jesus does what we cannot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to Jesus, Amy, the source of all comfort and the source of all healing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Two kinds of sorrow</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/two-kinds-of-sorrow/brahm-meyer-xwG9LGmc1Qk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two kinds of sorrow" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can sorrow ever be a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What of this, that Paul writes to the Corinthians?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even if I caused you sorrow by my letter, I do not regret it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Paul somehow pleased with himself because he stuck it to those wretched Corinthians in his first letter? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet now I am happy, not because you were made sorry, but because your sorrow led you to repentance. For you became sorrowful as God intended and so were not harmed in any way by us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their sorrow was as God intended and led to repentance. This is Godly sorrow, and the Lord uses it to expose sin in our lives to bring repentance and healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I weep over the shame and failure in my life and cry out to the Lord, this also is Godly sorrow, a gift of love from my Heavenly Father, received through the conviction that comes by the Holy Spirit. It drives me into the arms of my loving Heavenly Father, from shame to repentance and forgiveness and healing, and is, through the healing, eventually and ultimately, a cause for rejoicing in my wonderful Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we must beware. There is another sorrow which leads to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Godly sorrow brings repentance that leads to salvation and leaves no regret, but worldly sorrow brings death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldly sorrow is what I experience out of a sense of entitlement, a sense of “it&amp;rsquo;s not fair”, an inclination to blame God for all that&amp;rsquo;s wrong in my life. It is self-indulgent and self-pitying and full of regret. This drives me away from my loving Heavenly Father and brings death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two are so very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with your sorrow into the arms of your loving Heavenly Father, Amy, and receive healing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/sasha-freemind-nXo2ZsKHTHg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unanswered prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7, 11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unanswered prayer is a real thing. How can we deal with it? Many have grappled with this, and much has been written. Some have said, the Lord always answers prayer: sometimes yes; sometimes no; sometimes not yet. I find this glib and unhelpful. Because sometimes there is silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a husband and father, let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mark, a faithful servant of the Lord, suffering with severe health issues for so many years, for whom we have been faithfully, earnestly praying, confident that the Lord hears and is powerful to heal. Except he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, and this man dies, leaving his grieving wife, Grace, and their eight-year-old son, Callum. And from the Lord, only silence. What kind of answer to prayer is that? How is that a reasonable response to desperate prayers offered from a broken heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another way to see this. Unanswered prayer is an &lt;em&gt;invitation into relationship&lt;/em&gt;. An invitation into intimacy. How does this work? Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Why did Mark have to die? Don&amp;rsquo;t you care?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you have done something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “He loved you, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? Did you love him? You did love him, didn&amp;rsquo;t you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Yes, Amy, I loved him. I love him still.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “What about Grace and little Callum? This is breaking my heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;long pause, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Mine too, Amy. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit together for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;intimate, healing silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father grieves over his broken world, and the suffering his people bear. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with him, and grieve also, in the intimacy of his healing presence. And in the meantime,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us. For the creation waits in eager expectation for the children of God to be revealed. For the creation was subjected to frustration, not by its own choice, but by the will of the one who subjected it, in hope that the creation itself will be liberated from its bondage to decay and brought into the freedom and glory of the children of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:18-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit with the Lord in the silence of the unanswered prayer, Amy, in the intimacy of his healing presence 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faith that changes the course of nations</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/vladislav-klapin-YeO44yVTl20-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faith that changes the course of nations" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does faith that changes the course of nations look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see something of it in the story of Naaman, in 2 Kings 5. The Lord had given victory to Syria through Naaman, the commander of the Syrian army (v1, how interesting), who suffered from leprosy. Previously, the Syrians had taken captives from Israel, and among them was a young girl, now a slave in the house of Naaman (v2). Not even named, and yet her faith makes her the hero of this story.  How would you expect a young girl, captive in a foreign land, to live? Not like this, surely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said to her mistress, “If only my master would see the prophet who is in Samaria! He would cure him of his leprosy” (v3).  Talk about not playing it safe and keeping your head down! What can we learn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She was simply and humbly living her life, a slave in Naaman&amp;rsquo;s house, with no resentment or discontent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She had a generous heart, wishing good and not harm upon her captors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She had such a conviction that through Elisha the Lord would heal Naaman the commander of the army of a hostile nation, that she was prepared to put herself on the line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did she speak out like this? What trouble would have come her way if there had not been a miraculous healing? Certainly the king of Israel himself expected the outcome to be conflict between nations (v7). Her faith is ridiculous. And so she is the reason that a pagan general&amp;rsquo;s life is turned around, he becomes a worshipper of the Lord, and takes his faith back to a pagan land, into the royal palace, no less (v18).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to conclude that the Lord placed this on her heart, as he does. These were his plans and purposes, and they rested on the faith of a humble slave girl, who otherwise might simply have been living in obscurity. And on her obedience, oh my! Risk-taking, reckless obedience, to the one who is faithful beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with a faith that changes the course of nations, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Expectant and not disappointed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/patrick-fore-T2S4CatGdfQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Expectant and not disappointed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be expectant and not disappointed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living with high expectations of oneself and others is surely right, but can lead to ongoing disappointment, as we and those around us fall short of what we aspired to do and to be. How can the same not be true of the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should we expect of the Lord anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 27:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is anyone among you sick? &amp;hellip; the prayer offered in faith will make the sick person well; the Lord will raise them up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 5:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 91:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You know with all your heart and soul that not one of all the good promises the LORD your God gave you has failed. Every promise has been fulfilled; not one has failed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am the LORD, the God of all mankind. Is anything too hard for me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 32:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are we not just setting ourselves up for disappointment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However we deal with this, we must never lower our expectation of the Lord. He is the Creator, Almighty, Sovereign Lord, infinite in power and wisdom. He loves us his children absolutely, and he blesses us richly and without bounds. May we never doubt that!  And may we never limit our praying to what seems reasonable. If someone is sick, shame on me if I pray merely for their comfort rather than for miraculous healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To live with such expectation makes me so vulnerable, though. Vulnerable to disappointment. Vulnerable to the scorn of the sceptics. Vulnerable and defenceless. How can my faith survive this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that Abraham was strengthened in his faith (Rom 4:20). It is a work of the Lord. I commit completely, in faith, trusting. The Lord defends me.  It is miraculous grace.  The heartache may remain as I wait, in that amalgam of joy and pain which characterises the Christian life as we engage with the Lord&amp;rsquo;s work in this broken world. But disappointment does not crush me, does not crush my faith. How does this work? It is a mystery, a wondrous gift of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my, I seem to have written another tome. Good job I do this only once a week, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lean on him, trust him for his impossible promises, and praise him for his miraculous grace, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
