<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>faith on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/faith/</link>
    <description>Recent content in faith on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tags/faith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A great cloud of witnesses</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Apparently we are surrounded by a great cloud of witnesses, and this is a reason to run the race with perseverance. What&amp;rsquo;s all that about?!
 Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us.
― Hebrews 12:1 It&amp;rsquo;s important that we understand this, because doesn&amp;rsquo;t it sound just a little bit creepy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faithfulness</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faithfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faithfulness/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What fuels faithfulness?
 The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; faithfulness
― Galatians 5:22 Faithfulness is such an honourable character trait, perhaps the noblest of them all. To be loyal, steadfast, trustworthy and true — surely these words make our hearts soar. They speak to the very heart of noble character, of character that honours the Lord. So where does faithfulness come from? There are two answers to this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patience in affliction</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-affliction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-affliction/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Is there any more to patience than waiting well?
 patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/
▸ noun [mass noun]
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious
― Oxford Dictionary of English There most certainly is! What of patience in affliction then?
Job is an interesting book. Mostly we find mysteries are revealed at the end of a story, but with Job that is not so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith that changes the course of nations</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What does faith that changes the course of nations look like?
We see something of it in the story of Naaman, in 2 Kings 5. The Lord had given victory to Syria through Naaman, the commander of the Syrian army (v1, how interesting), who suffered from leprosy. Previously, the Syrians had taken captives from Israel, and among them was a young girl, now a slave in the house of Naaman (v2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectant and not disappointed</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we be expectant and not disappointed?
Living with high expectations of oneself and others is surely right, but can lead to ongoing disappointment, as we and those around us fall short of what we aspired to do and to be. How can the same not be true of the Lord?
What should we expect of the Lord anyway? “I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full” (Jn 10:10).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we live confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s love?
Psalm 27 pretty much has it all. Here are the highlights. “The LORD is my light and my salvation &amp;hellip; the stronghold of my life (v1). One thing I ask from the LORD &amp;hellip; that I may dwell in the house of the LORD all the days of my life (v4). He will keep me safe in his dwelling &amp;hellip; and set me high upon a rock (v5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking by faith</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 06:52:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What happens when we walk by faith?
Perhaps the greatest example we have is Abraham. He didn&amp;rsquo;t always get it right, nor did he manage always to trust, as shown by his shabby little misdeed with Hagar. Evidently not super-human then! But the Lord called him again out of that particular failure thirteen years later, out of the absolute mess he had made (“walk before me and be blameless” - Gen 17:1), after he had been waiting for the fulfillment of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promise to him for 25 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living confidently when the future is uncertain</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we live confidently when the future is uncertain?
There are so many things we would like to know. What will I do with my life? Will it be worthwhile? How will I live? Will I be able to use the talents God has given me for his glory? Where will I go? Is my soul mate out there somewhere? Will I be alone? How can I know I will be ok?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
