<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>faith on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/faith/</link>
        <description>Recent content in faith on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/faith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Blinded by seeing </title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/blinded-by-seeing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/blinded-by-seeing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/blinded-by-seeing/matrix-digital-rain.png" alt="Featured image of post Blinded by seeing " /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a mighty prophet of God lose his faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re surely familiar with the glorious story of Elijah on Mount Carmel, where he defeated the prophets of Baal and so was revealed who is the true God (1 Kings 18).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But look what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Jezebel sent a messenger to Elijah, saying, “So may the gods do to me and more also, if I do not make your life as the life of one of them by this time tomorrow.” Then he was afraid, and he arose and ran for his life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notwithstanding Jezebel&amp;rsquo;s threat to kill him, how does “he was afraid” make any sense given what had just happened? In fact it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a fascinating paper about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pivotal term in our text is the Hebrew word &lt;em&gt;wayyarʼ&lt;/em&gt;, the first word in verse three. This common verbal form should be translated “then he saw” (from &lt;em&gt;rāʼâ&lt;/em&gt;). &amp;hellip; Virtually all of the more recent translations of the Bible have opted for another reading, the Hebrew &lt;em&gt;wayyîrāʼ&lt;/em&gt;, “and he was afraid” (from &lt;em&gt;yārēʼ&lt;/em&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against this &amp;hellip; most Hebrew manuscripts read “and he saw”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ronald Barclay Allen, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etsjets.org/files/JETS-PDFs/22/22-3/22-3-pp193-202_JETS.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Elijah the Broken Prophet, Journal of the Evangelical Theological Society 22/3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen goes on to argue how “he saw” is surely what was originally written, and is in fact the only translation which makes any sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then does it mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How had Elijah defeated the Baals? By exercising incredible faith in the infinite power and steadfast faithfulness of the invisible God. The invisible God who cannot be seen is the one who defines reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what did Elijah do next. He saw. He looked at the so-called real world, and the pseudo-reality that he saw defeated him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul writes about the reason for our courage and confidence in the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we walk by faith, not by sight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 5:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking by sight means looking at the visible world around us as all there is, or at least the most part of it. How this defeats us! It defeated Elijah, that mighty prophet of God, who ran for his life and hid in a cave, where he was rebuked by the Lord (albeit with great tenderness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There he came to a cave and lodged in it. And behold, the word of the LORD came to him, and he said to him, “What are you doing here, Elijah?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the love in that rebuke? Read the rest of 1 Kings 19 for further insight into the loving kindness and provision of our Heavenly Father. Elijah had gone off-script. He had momentarily lost his faith, precisely because he saw, and he thought that what he saw was the true reality. It was not, as the Lord showed him with such patience and love and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the infinite power and the steadfast love and faithfulness and the great kindness of the invisible God, Amy, and walk by faith not by sight! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The shield of faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/Cap-s_Shield.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shield of faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have so many Christians thrown away the shield of faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In addition to all this, take up the shield of faith, with which you can extinguish all the flaming arrows of the evil one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, understand the nature of these flaming arrows. They are lies. Lies about us and lies about the Lord and what he has done. Jesus says of the devil,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“When he lies, he speaks his native language, for he is a liar and the father of lies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:44b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lies can be insidious. They must be stamped out before they take hold, like flames licking around. What do these lies do? They create doubt. And how do we combat doubt? By exercising and building faith! But how do we do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is faith anyway? Those who think it is an intellectual acceptance of some revealed truth are so far away from real understanding. Faith is a &lt;em&gt;life lived&lt;/em&gt; upon the foundation of this truth from the Lord, upon Christ himself, fully committed, trusting and even depending on him to keep his promises. (And he will.) So, how to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is again the key. I have to ask myself with brutal honesty, does my life reflect that I will one day stand before the Lord and give an account? Does my life reflect that I have understood Jesus teaching and am living by it in full obedience to him, joyously surrendered? Many seem not to understand this and then wonder why their faith is so small and why doubt is creeping in. Half-hearted belief is no belief at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider even this one thing that Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But many who are first will be last, and many who are last will be first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context of this is the rich young ruler, earnestly seeking but tragically unable to give up this life&amp;rsquo;s riches and pleasures for the Kingdom, just like so many today. Why is it that even within the church so many are trying to be first? Do we really not believe Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may need some help with this. So let us ask our heavenly Father, who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open my eyes that I may see wonderful things in your law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May this be our most earnest prayer as we learn to wield the shield of faith and extinguish those flaming arrows. And let us observe the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in our lives as we live this life of faith, recognising that his faithfulness is in fact the ultimate faith builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take up your shield of faith, Amy, and know that he who promised is faithful! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The breastplate of righteousness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 07:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/Lorica_segmentata.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The breastplate of righteousness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the breastplate of righteousness, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand firm then &amp;hellip; with the breastplate of righteousness in place &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the function of the breastplate is to protect the torso, the heart and lungs, those vital organs without which we cannot live. But what is the nature of this righteousness without which we cannot live before the Lord? It is interesting to see how writers disagree about this, because there are two possible answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the gospel a righteousness from God is revealed, a righteousness that is by faith from first to last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first view is that the breastplate is Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to us, a free gift of grace received entirely through &lt;em&gt;faith&lt;/em&gt;. We can stand firm irrespective of our own wretchedness and sin and failure because of this righteousness from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is profound truth in this. But there is another view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But thanks be to God that, though you used to be slaves to sin, you wholeheartedly obeyed the form of teaching to which you were entrusted. You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:17-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Very truly I tell you, whoever keeps my word will never see death.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:51&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being slaves to righteousness and living in total surrender and complete obedience to God is about our sanctification, and ultimately our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;, as we are transformed into the likeness of Christ and live lives that reflect that. Faith or works? Are these contradictory? Jim Packer has a helpful explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final judgment, as we saw, will be according to our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;—that is, our &lt;em&gt;doings&lt;/em&gt;, our whole course of life. The relevance of our &amp;lsquo;doings&amp;rsquo; is not that they ever merit an award from the court—they are too far short of perfection to do that—but that they provide an index of what is in the heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that one way of acting was meritorious while the other was not, but that from these actions one can tell whether there was love to Christ, the love that springs from faith, in the
heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Knowing God, Chapter 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James takes up this very idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Show me your faith without deeds, and I will show you my faith by my deeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 2:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we can see it clearly. The righteousness is Christ&amp;rsquo;s alone, freely given and received through faith by us who believe, and initiating in us an ongoing transformation into slaves to righteousness. Through this we live ever more radically changed lives, and through this we have assurance of salvation. The merit is all Christ&amp;rsquo;s and so is the glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand firm in the battle, Amy, wholly depending on Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to you, and have assurance of that by the evidence of your own transformed life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faith vs reason</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/dan-cristian-padure-h3kuhYUCE9A-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faith vs reason" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does radical faith require us to switch off our intellect?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dear friend of mine has been having what I would call a faith crisis. In the context of my ongoing waiting on an impossible promise from the Lord, he cannot relate to someone who he would say is living in the hope of something that contradicts the observed and obvious reality. He asks, how could I have abandoned reason and switched off the rational part of my brain in quite such a naive way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I argue that in fact the opposite is true, and that I have brought all my intellect and understanding to bear in my faith situation. How so? And what does the Bible have to say about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom, and knowledge of the Holy One is understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 9:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One aspect of wisdom is &lt;em&gt;applied intellect&lt;/em&gt;, that is intellect used to align a life with knowledge of the Holy One in a practical way, in order to live that life on the right path.  And wisdom begins with the fear of the Lord. Recall Tim Keller&amp;rsquo;s definition: “The fear of the Lord is a reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Lord of all creation loves me to the extent that he gave up his only Son to an excruciating death in order to rescue me, and has promised abundant life and ongoing rescue in him, the only rational response is to completely cast myself upon his love, trusting him, absolutely. Anything less betrays a lack of understanding of the eternal reality. (Sadly it seems to me that few indeed are able to rationalize to this extent.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this rational response look like then? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. Diving headfirst into the wellspring of life. Living confidently on the firm foundation of such a promise from the Lord.  Ruthless consistency is the key which unlocks the understanding to be able to live like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so radical faith in the one who is faithful and true is in fact the only way to live with intellectual integrity. Having tested it, we must lean into it as the foundation of our life. Nothing else makes any sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with radical faith, Amy, employing all of your intellect to live a life increasingly aligned with your growing knowledge of the Holy One! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Impossible</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/isaac-quesada-dZYI4ga2eUA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Impossible" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we receive it when God speaks the impossible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have many examples of God speaking something impossible. Why does he do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua was told to march the Israelite army around the walls of Jericho for seven days, and the walls would collapse, but even before he was so instructed, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Joshua, “See, I have delivered Jericho into your hands, along with its king and its fighting men.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 6:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if it had already happened! Joshua had to act on the basis that something impossible would happen. (And it did.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably Abraham had it even harder. He had to wait on an impossible promise, for twenty-five years! Waiting is perhaps harder than doing. And waiting for twenty-five years?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other examples in the Bible of God speaking the impossible. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: &lt;em&gt;he is still doing it today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I the LORD do not change.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 13:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bible itself teaches that we are to understand it in terms of our own experience when it says that Paul, Barnabas and Elijah were human beings like us and that Jesus knows how we feel in our weaknesses because he himself “in every respect has been tested as we are” (Heb 4:15). It means that &lt;em&gt;their experience was substantially like our own&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must pray for the faith and for the experiences that would enable us to believe that &lt;em&gt;such things could happen to us&lt;/em&gt;. Only then will we be able to recognize, accept and dwell in them when they come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dallas Willard, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hearing God, Chapter 2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we receive it when God speaks the impossible? It is in fact a high honour, an invitation to demonstrate radical faith, and to grow in that faith. Perhaps God reserves such things for those for whom he has great plans, which will require great faith. (That&amp;rsquo;s a little scary, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?)  No-one starts with such faith, but the Lord in his wisdom knows what he is doing.  Again, consider Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I hold on to this verse, which has kept me going for some years, and was itself given to me in a miraculous way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God is not a man, that he should lie, nor a son of man, that he should change his mind. Does he speak and then not act? Does he promise and not fulfill?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 23:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This remains even if the promise is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the word of the LORD came to Jeremiah: “I am the LORD, the God of all mankind. Is anything too hard for me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 32:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait on the Lord in faith, Amy, knowing that he who promised is faithful (Heb 10:23), even if it seems impossible!  🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A great cloud of witnesses</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/sandeep-damre-14IPTP-6mTc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A great cloud of witnesses" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently we are surrounded by a great cloud of witnesses, and this is a reason to run the race with perseverance. What&amp;rsquo;s all that about?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important that we understand this, because doesn&amp;rsquo;t it sound just a little bit creepy? Are all these witnesses sitting in heaven watching us, and so had we better not embarrass ourselves for that reason? By no means! (as Paul would say). That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what this is not saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these witnesses are listed in Chapter 11, with this introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now faith is being sure of what we hope for and certain of what we do not see. This is what the ancients were commended for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer then goes on to list the incredible demonstrations of faith by these witnesses, and they are incredible. But what is it that they are witnessing? Is it us? No, it&amp;rsquo;s not us. Here&amp;rsquo;s what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By their faith they are &lt;em&gt;witnesses to the Lord&lt;/em&gt;, to his goodness and kindness and faithfulness. When we live lives of radical faith it points to the one who enables us to do that, to the one for whom we live. And they were commended for it and highly honoured because this is glorious, to live in such a way that our very lives bear testimony to the Lord. This is a powerful witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is why &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; run the race with perseverance. It is a powerful witness. The only ones watching are our contemporaries (oh, and the Lord, obviously — Ps 139, Rev 20:12). But if we run this race well, the Lord may choose to use &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; witness to save some of &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with perseverance, Amy, and join the great cloud of witnesses in testifying to the goodness, kindness and faithfulness of the Lord! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faithfulness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faithfulness/sean-benesh-VnmbcgAfL3Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faithfulness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fuels faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; faithfulness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness is such an honourable character trait, perhaps the noblest of them all. To be loyal, steadfast, trustworthy and true — surely these words make our hearts soar. They speak to the very heart of noble character, of character that honours the Lord. So where does faithfulness come from? There are two answers to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness, evident throughout Scripture, from where he first introduces himself to Moses, right up to John&amp;rsquo;s vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, the rider on the white horse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [the LORD] passed in front of Moses, proclaiming, “The LORD, the LORD, the compassionate and gracious God, slow to anger, abounding in love and faithfulness, maintaining love to thousands, and forgiving wickedness, rebellion and sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the ways of the LORD are loving and faithful for those who keep the demands of his covenant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the word of the LORD is right and true; he is faithful in all he does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 33:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your love, O LORD, reaches to the heavens, your faithfulness to the skies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 36:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet this I call to mind and therefore I have hope: Because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great love we are not consumed, for his compassions never fail. They are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who calls you is faithful and he will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I saw heaven standing open and there before me was a white horse, whose rider is called Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness to us makes our hearts burn with fire, fuelling our own faithfulness, our noblest thoughts and deeds, through and for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, consider the word itself, &lt;em&gt;pistis&lt;/em&gt; in the original Greek. Mostly that word is not in fact translated as faithfulness, but rather faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pistis — persuasion that is credence; moral conviction (of religious truth or the truthfulness of God or a religious teacher) especially reliance upon Christ for salvation; abstractly constancy in such profession; by extension the system of religious (Gospel) truth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Strong&amp;#39;s Greek Lexicon&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness then is fueled by being full of faith. Genuine, all-in, life-changing faith in the one who is faithful to all he has said, and indeed all he is, gives us the power to live lives that are worthy of our calling, manifesting in the noblest of hearts, and lasting faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him Amy, whose name is Faithful and True, be full of faith, and let that fuel your own faithfulness, to him and for him, forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Patience in affliction</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-affliction/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-affliction/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/patience-in-affliction/zac-durant-_6HzPU9Hyfg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Patience in affliction" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any more to patience than waiting well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/&lt;br&gt;
▸ noun [mass noun]&lt;br&gt;
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Oxford Dictionary of English&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There most certainly is! What of patience in affliction then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job is an interesting book. Mostly we find mysteries are revealed at the end of a story, but with Job that is not so. There is no explanation when the Lord finally appears. We could summarise Job 38-42 like this: “I am the LORD Most High, Creator of Heaven and Earth. Who are you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explanation rather is where the story begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Satan, “Have you considered my servant Job? There is no one on earth like him; he is blameless and upright, a man who fears God and shuns evil.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Does Job fear God for nothing?” Satan replied.  “Have you not put a hedge around him and his household and everything he has? You have blessed the work of his hands, so that his flocks and herds are spread throughout the land. But stretch out your hand and strike everything he has, and he will surely curse you to your face.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 1:8-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostle Peter takes this principle and expands upon it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For a little while you may have had to suffer grief in all kinds of trials. These have come so that your faith &amp;hellip; may be proved genuine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we truly grasp this, it empowers us to respond with patience in affliction. How else can I show the Lord that my love for him is real and not merely cupboard love, that my trust is absolute, and my faith genuine? I rejoice when I find that I can do these things! And I am mindful that this is a heart-work of the Holy Spirit. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; patience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be patient in affliction, Amy, and show the Lord that your faith is genuine! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faith that changes the course of nations</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/vladislav-klapin-YeO44yVTl20-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faith that changes the course of nations" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does faith that changes the course of nations look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see something of it in the story of Naaman, in 2 Kings 5. The Lord had given victory to Syria through Naaman, the commander of the Syrian army (v1, how interesting), who suffered from leprosy. Previously, the Syrians had taken captives from Israel, and among them was a young girl, now a slave in the house of Naaman (v2). Not even named, and yet her faith makes her the hero of this story.  How would you expect a young girl, captive in a foreign land, to live? Not like this, surely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said to her mistress, “If only my master would see the prophet who is in Samaria! He would cure him of his leprosy” (v3).  Talk about not playing it safe and keeping your head down! What can we learn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She was simply and humbly living her life, a slave in Naaman&amp;rsquo;s house, with no resentment or discontent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She had a generous heart, wishing good and not harm upon her captors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She had such a conviction that through Elisha the Lord would heal Naaman the commander of the army of a hostile nation, that she was prepared to put herself on the line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did she speak out like this? What trouble would have come her way if there had not been a miraculous healing? Certainly the king of Israel himself expected the outcome to be conflict between nations (v7). Her faith is ridiculous. And so she is the reason that a pagan general&amp;rsquo;s life is turned around, he becomes a worshipper of the Lord, and takes his faith back to a pagan land, into the royal palace, no less (v18).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to conclude that the Lord placed this on her heart, as he does. These were his plans and purposes, and they rested on the faith of a humble slave girl, who otherwise might simply have been living in obscurity. And on her obedience, oh my! Risk-taking, reckless obedience, to the one who is faithful beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with a faith that changes the course of nations, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/melissa-askew-8n00CqwnqO8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 27 pretty much has it all. Here are the highlights.  “The LORD is my light and my salvation &amp;hellip; the stronghold of my life (v1). One thing I ask from the LORD &amp;hellip; that I may dwell in the house of the LORD all the days of my life (v4). He will keep me safe in his dwelling &amp;hellip; and set me high upon a rock (v5). Your face, LORD, I will seek (v8).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantly reminding ourselves of these things, and living them every day, every moment, is part of it. But then out of the blue comes v9, which suddenly expresses doubt and fear of rejection.  “Do not hide your face from me, do not turn your servant away in anger; you have been my helper. Do not reject me or forsake me, God my Saviour.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such sentiments occur throughout the Psalms, and this by the grace of God. Let&amp;rsquo;s try to understand why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s wisdom is beyond understanding, let&amp;rsquo;s first acknowledge that. He has plans and purposes, and they are good. He desires us to walk by faith, to trust him absolutely, and he loves us, ruthlessly. That&amp;rsquo;s an uncomfortable word! The walk of faith is not comfortable, nor should we expect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while it can feel, at times overwhelmingly, like he has turned his face away and rejected us, he has not. He alone knows what he is doing, and he is deeply invested in us. That rejection is what Jesus received on the cross, so we never have to. And that is why we can assert with the Psalmist, “I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living.” (v13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we live confidently? “Wait for the LORD; be strong and take heart and wait for the LORD.” (v14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be strong and take heart and wait for the Lord, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Walking by faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/walking-by-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 06:52:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/walking-by-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/walking-by-faith/jimmy-larry-7uvixXrQkfw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Walking by faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when we walk by faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest example we have is Abraham. He didn&amp;rsquo;t always get it right, nor did he manage always to trust, as shown by his shabby little misdeed with Hagar. Evidently not super-human then! But the Lord called him again out of that particular failure thirteen years later, out of the absolute mess he had made (“walk before me and be blameless” - Gen 17:1), after he had been waiting for the fulfillment of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promise to him for 25 years. Twenty-five years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul&amp;rsquo;s account in Romans 4 manages to overlook Abraham&amp;rsquo;s shameful failure (oh the grace of God!), and we find this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet Abraham did not waver through unbelief regarding the promise of God, but was strengthened in his faith and gave glory to God, being fully persuaded that God had power to do what he had promised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 4:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He believed again, and walked by faith. What then happened? He was strengthened in his faith. Notice what happened here. He believed. He exercised faith. Just enough. Perhaps barely enough, but enough all the same. And the Lord strengthened him in that faith. And it was God who was thus glorified, not Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most striking consequence is found just before this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Against all hope, Abraham in hope believed and so became the father of many nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 4:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that little word, so. What was the reason Abraham became the father of many nations? Because he believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we walk by faith, God fulfills his plans and purposes in us and through us. There is a causal link. What more motivation could we have than this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on walking by faith, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently when the future is uncertain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/arthur-ogleznev-rWDumHFt8E8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently when the future is uncertain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently when the future is uncertain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things we would like to know. What will I do with my life? Will it be worthwhile? How will I live? Will I be able to use the talents God has given me for his glory? Where will I go? Is my soul mate out there somewhere? Will I be alone? How can I know I will be ok? Why won&amp;rsquo;t God tell me these things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the Lord does not tell us such things ahead of time, and nor should we expect it. If he does reveal something, as he occasionally does, even an incredible and specific promise, it is unlikely to be how or when. What is my part then? What must I do? I must trust him, and I must live for him with my whole heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the first thing I wrote to you Amy, back in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By choosing to trust, to walk by faith, with all of our hope in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s unfailing love, we can delight him. I will say it again. We can delight him! Without uncertainty there can be no faith, so let us embrace it, and show the Lord that we really can walk by faith. What an opportunity to show him that! There is no risk, really. Read Psalm 145 again, and believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
