<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>grace on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/grace/</link>
        <description>Recent content in grace on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/grace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The desire of the sower</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-desire-of-the-sower/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-desire-of-the-sower/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-desire-of-the-sower/melissa-askew-y4xZxzN754M-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The desire of the sower" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the desire of the sower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when a great crowd was gathering and people from town after town came to him, [Jesus] said in a parable, “A sower went out to sow his seed. And as he sowed, some fell along the path and was trampled underfoot, and the birds of the air devoured it. And some fell on the rock, and as it grew up, it withered away, because it had no moisture. And some fell among thorns, and the thorns grew up with it and choked it. And some fell into good soil and grew and yielded a hundredfold.” As he said these things, he called out, “He who has ears to hear, let him hear.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 8:4-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all three synoptic gospels where Jesus refers to the prophecy from Isaiah 6:9-10 it is in the context of the parable of the sower (Matthew 13:1-23, Mark 4:1-20, Luke 8:4-15). Let&amp;rsquo;s ponder that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when his disciples asked him what this parable meant, he said, “To you it has been given to know the secrets of the kingdom of God, but for others they are in parables, so that ‘seeing they may not see, and hearing they may not understand.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 8:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This prophecy is just so uncomfortable, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Let&amp;rsquo;s just see if we can relate it to what we know of the goodness and kindness and steadfast love and faithfulness of our heavenly father by asking, what is the desire of the sower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t you ever wondered this: the sower was really quite a bad farmer, wasn&amp;rsquo;t he? Why was he so profligate in his sowing? What a waste to sow that precious seed in all the wrong places! But was it really wasteful? Or is this nothing less than God&amp;rsquo;s super-abundant generosity and grace towards unrepentant sinners?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And consider Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent cry, his most impassioned invitation: “He who has ears to hear, let him hear.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is the desire of the sower? And why is the message of salvation wrapped up in parables, shrouded in mystery? Jeremiah has a clue for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you, declares the LORD &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus underlines exactly this in the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one who seeks, and seeks with all their heart, that one will find. The gospel is not a spectator sport. But for those who cry out for mercy and seek with all their heart, to these is the Kingdom revealed. In his great wisdom and mercy and kindness, so has the Lord made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust the Lord, Amy, in his plans and purposes to rescue and redeem all of humankind, he knows what he is doing and it is very good! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Comfort and healing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 06:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/comfort-and-healing/kat-j-NPmR0RblyhQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Comfort and healing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing that our God is the God of all comfort and healing, how can we minister this to the brokenhearted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to write about such things when grief and loss are present and quite so raw. But it is precisely at such a time that we must engage with the Lord, and seek to understand, if he is the God of all comfort and healing, which he is, how is that outworked at such a time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At such times we are supposed to be able to comfort those in need with the comfort we ourselves have received from God. But how often do we seem to be of no use in this, not knowing even what to say or do? In the weeping face of heartbreak, how can we in fact be of any comfort at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently been gaining some experience in this, as I am continuing to care for a young friend, a believer in Christ, in the midst of his own trauma, which is ongoing, heartbreaking, and bewildering. In the face of this overwhelming need, the Lord has given me such clarity of understanding of what my friend needs from me, and it is not advice nor explanation nor anything else that I have to say. It is simply Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not matter that I do not know what to say or do. Jesus does. So we cry out to him together for mercy. And he responds, with grace and kindness, impossibly and lavishly. The peace that has come surpasses understanding. The need is ongoing, but so is the grace, and so is the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our own comfort is in Jesus and it is Jesus, and so this is what we must minister to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does it look like, to minister Jesus to the brokenhearted? It looks like gentleness, and kindness, and listening, and prayer, and probably a hug, but most especially time⸺more time than 21st Century western civilization would think is a reasonable investment for a single individual. Not much speaking though. This may come later, but is not I think where we are called to start. And above all else, absolute confidence in the one who is mighty to save, whose name is Helper, Comforter, Healer, Lord, whose name is Jesus. The one who, astonishingly, chooses to do his work of grace through us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us remind ourselves why we praise him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; for he is beautiful, and a song of praise is fitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1, 3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in this, Jesus does what we cannot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to Jesus, Amy, the source of all comfort and the source of all healing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Led by the Spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/led-by-the-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 07:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/led-by-the-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/led-by-the-spirit/KTutanssail.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Led by the Spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is there so much confusion today around what it means to be led by the Spirit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote recently about being led by the Spirit in the context of the grace-filled life, focusing on loving the Lord with all our heart, soul, mind and strength, and loving one another, unconditionally and without exception, in joyful surrender. Surrender is in fact the key word here and there is a bit more that needs to be said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is remarkably easy to tell when someone is confused about what it means to be led by the Spirit, because you will hear them use words like “discern”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider the context in which Paul uses this expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For if you live according to the flesh you will die, but if by the Spirit you put to death the deeds of the body, you will live. For all who are led by the Spirit of God are sons [and daughters] of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I say, walk by the Spirit, and you will not gratify the desires of the flesh. For the desires of the flesh are against the Spirit, and the desires of the Spirit are against the flesh, for these are opposed to each other, to keep you from doing the things you want to do. But if you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that being led by the Spirit is about putting to death the deeds of the body and not gratifying the desires of the flesh. This has nothing to do with understanding or insight! It is all about the power of the sanctified will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t do better than to quote Jim Packer on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Twice Paul speaks of being “led” by the Spirit (Romans 8:14; Galatians 5:18). Both times the reference is to resisting one&amp;rsquo;s own sinful impulses as the flip side of one&amp;rsquo;s practice of righteousness. Leads is rightly taken to mean “guides”, but the guidance in view here is not a revealing to the mind of divine directives hitherto unknown; it is, rather, an impelling of our wills to pursue and practice and hold fast that sanctity whose terms we know already. Thus to be led and guided, says Paul, is the mark of a Christian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J.I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Keep in Step with the Spirit, Chapter 3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An impelling of our wills to pursue and practice and hold fast that sanctity whose terms we know already. Now recall Packer&amp;rsquo;s premise from Chapter 1 of the very same book. &lt;em&gt;The primary work of the Holy Spirit is to mediate the presence of Jesus in our lives.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presence of Jesus in our lives is glorious, victorious, powerful, sanctifying. It enables us to surrender our will to what is right and true and pleasing to the Lord, &lt;em&gt;and to do it&lt;/em&gt;, for his glory and for our own eternal blessing. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrender your will, Amy, to the one who is faithful and true, to our glorious Saviour, and be led by the Spirit into a victorious life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What to pray for</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/what-to-pray-for/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/what-to-pray-for/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/what-to-pray-for/marcel-smits-Wt6JoSxrsvU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What to pray for" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know what we should pray for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s quite a responsibility here, don&amp;rsquo;t you think? After all, Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Whatever you ask in my name, this I will do, that the Father may be glorified in the Son. If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been in a prayer meeting where someone was sharing a prayer request, and they seemed to take aeons to lay out every painstaking detail about their situation? Well, we can&amp;rsquo;t risk praying for the wrong thing, can we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But could there be another way to see this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re surely familiar with the story of Joseph. After being sold into slavery by his brothers and thrown into prison in Egypt for a crime he didn&amp;rsquo;t commit, God raised him up to be second only to Pharaoh himself in all the land, and used him to deliver the Israelites from famine. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus Israel settled in the land of Egypt, in the land of Goshen. And they gained possessions in it, and were fruitful and multiplied greatly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 47:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some years later, however, things apparently weren&amp;rsquo;t going quite so well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During those many days the king of Egypt died, and the people of Israel groaned because of their slavery and cried out for help. Their cry for rescue from slavery came up to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 2:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this really what God had intended? Had it somehow all gone horribly wrong? Not really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God heard their groaning, and God remembered his covenant with Abraham, with Isaac, and with Jacob. God saw the people of Israel⸺and God knew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 2:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God knew. He didn&amp;rsquo;t need to be told. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t as if he hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed what was happening to his people, his chosen ones, his beloved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then what happened? What happened is that God met with Moses in the burning bush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, and I have come down to deliver them out of the hand of the Egyptians and to bring them up out of that land to a good and broad land, a land flowing with milk and honey.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God already knew what he was going to do and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t merely to alleviate the suffering of the Israelites. He was going to bless them far beyond that, far beyond imagining, gifting to them a land flowing with milk and honey⸺a land that would demonstrate his sovereign choice, his faithfulness to his covenant promise, his grace and kindness to his people, and ultimately his rescue for all of humankind. No-one was asking for this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 3:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply cry out to God, Amy, Lord have mercy! He already knows what to do. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The grace-filled life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/tom-morbey-r1SwcagHVG0-unsplash-cropped.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The grace-filled life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are not under law but under grace, does it even matter what we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It matters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What shall we say then? Are we to continue in sin that grace may abound? By no means! How can we who died to sin still live in it? Do you not know that all of us who have been baptized into Christ Jesus were baptized into his death? We were buried therefore with him by baptism into death, in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, we too might walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we learn to walk in newness of life, not under law but under grace? If all those long lists of commandments still apply, how are we not under law? And if not, how can we avoid living in sin? Certainly not by overlooking what Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Do not think that I have come to abolish the Law or the Prophets; I have not come to abolish them but to fulfil them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like us, the fledgling church in Galatia was under threat from those preaching works. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider what Paul wrote to them. Here&amp;rsquo;s the key:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, but that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big if! How can we know, and how can we be secure in that knowledge? Because there&amp;rsquo;s a grievous trap here which snares many, namely equating being led by the Spirit with living according to the convictions of one&amp;rsquo;s own heart. This is fraught with danger! Satan is the father of lies and the great deceiver, and by stroking our egos and flattering our vanity he can manipulate our feelings even and perhaps especially in this realm. How can we escape this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the desires of the flesh are against the Spirit, and the desires of the Spirit are against the flesh, for these are opposed to each other, to keep you from doing the things you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the works of the flesh are evident: sexual immorality, impurity, sensuality, idolatry, sorcery, enmity, strife, jealousy, fits of anger, rivalries, dissensions, divisions, envy, drunkenness, orgies, and things like these. I warn you, as I warned you before, that those who do such things will not inherit the kingdom of God. But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:17, 19-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first list is truly shocking, and we might be tempted to think is far from where we live our lives, but consider idolatry for one⸺in regard to career, reputation, and respectability, how evident is this in every church! Now, notice that eight out of these fifteen works of the flesh comprise dysfunctional relationship and unlove. There&amp;rsquo;s a clue here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could being led by the Spirit in fact be quite straightforward? The opposite of dysfunctional relationship and unlove is simply, love. There&amp;rsquo;s more than love in the second list, of course, but that&amp;rsquo;s surely the headline. And what does Paul say elsewhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here indeed is the answer. We can live not under law but under grace by loving the Lord with all our heart, soul, mind and strength, and loving one another, unconditionally and without exception, in joyful surrender. Love that starts small must grow and grow and continue to grow⸺this is the fruit of the Spirit. So simple, and yet learning to do this adequately will take each one of us the rest of our earthly lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live a life of love, Amy, led by the Spirit, as one not under law but under grace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Black and white?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/black-and-white/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/black-and-white/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/black-and-white/rafael-rex-felisilda-U_Kz2RnfFAk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Black and white?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean in practice to be a people not under law but under grace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For sin will have no dominion over you, since you are not under law but under grace. What then? Are we to sin because we are not under law but under grace? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Law and grace: are these in opposition? Jesus sets the highest standards in the Sermon on the Mount, then freely forgives and restores, refusing to let law limit grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a couple of contemporary issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I do not permit a woman to teach or to exercise authority over a man; rather, she is to remain quiet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 2:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely this was a cultural thing that no longer applies, and so surely these days women are free to pursue a preaching ministry? Surely? Except for the very next verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Adam was formed first, then Eve; and Adam was not deceived, but the woman was deceived and became a transgressor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 2:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh dear. Paul is making a creational argument here, which seems to be as clear as it is harsh. Not something that can be so easily brushed aside then!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose however to hold no opinion about this, and instead I choose to honour those women who have wrestled with this themselves and are honouring and serving the Lord through a preaching ministry. Wrestling is certainly required, but who am I to seek to impose my own view into someone else&amp;rsquo;s life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, I have my own issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said to them, “Because of your hardness of heart Moses allowed you to divorce your wives, but from the beginning it was not so. And I say to you: whoever divorces his wife, except for sexual immorality, and marries another, commits adultery.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this prevent the Lord from rescuing me from the shame of my own life after a failed marriage? Is grace trumped by law here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How tempted we are to be black and white about the lives of others, yet rather grey about our own. Show me the one who does not find themselves on the wrong side of particular verses in the Bible, and does not have to cast themselves upon God&amp;rsquo;s mercy even to live their life. Does such a one exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus himself faced a law versus grace issue in relation to the Fourth Commandment, and on one occasion when confronted by the Pharisees, he related the story of David apparently breaking the law by eating with his men consecrated bread from the temple, before concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I tell you, something greater than the temple is here. And if you had known what this means, &amp;lsquo;I desire mercy, and not sacrifice,&amp;rsquo; you would not have condemned the guiltless. For the Son of Man is lord of the Sabbath.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 12:6-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that under grace everything is in fact somewhat grey? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything rather is lit by a dazzling technicolour explosion of grace and redemption from the Lord, and that particular mercy which triumphs over judgment. This enables some women to pursue a preaching ministry for his glory, some divorced men to remarry by his grace, and others to live their lives in dependence on the riches of his mercy. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that this in no way removes or diminishes our call to live as slaves to righteousness, fully surrendered and walking in obedience with the Lord. (I will undoubtedly have to revisit this aspect of “not under law but under grace”.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live your life for his glory, Amy, as one not under law but under grace, and praise the Lord! 🙏🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Uneven blessing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/uneven-blessing/atul-pandey-0f3bZHXZSz8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Uneven blessing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that some seem to receive more bounteous blessing from the Lord than others? How is that fair? And how is it congruent with a God of justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with fair, and let&amp;rsquo;s be frank. What would be fair would be for each one of us to be cast into the fiery pit. And collectively, we must take responsibility through our wretched ancestors for much of the suffering of humankind, for we share the same rebellious spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Because you have &amp;hellip; eaten of the tree of which I commanded you, ‘You shall not eat of it,’ cursed is the ground because of you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, and this is a wonderful, unmerited, joyous but,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a rescue! What a Saviour! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with grateful, praising hearts, in fear and trembling, let us dare to ask again, how is it that God&amp;rsquo;s blessing is quite so unevenly distributed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul grappled with such a question in relation to the election of the gentiles and God&amp;rsquo;s apparent rejection of the nation of Israel (Romans 9-11). That he takes three chapters over this shows us that such questions are no small matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take some of his arguments and apply them to the more general question of uneven blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What shall we say then? Is there injustice on God&amp;rsquo;s part? By no means! For he says to Moses, “I will have mercy on whom I have mercy, and I will have compassion on whom I have compassion.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is all mercy, and it is all undeserved. And let us not forget that the giver is the Creator God of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Has the potter no right over the clay, to make out of the same lump one vessel for honourable use and another for dishonourable use? What if God, desiring to show his wrath and to make known his power, has endured with much patience vessels of wrath prepared for destruction, in order to make known the riches of his glory for vessels of mercy, which he has prepared beforehand for glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow in the unevenness of the blessing, God is making known the riches of his glory. Paul also shows us how to respond in the face of the apparent injustice of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Brothers, my heart&amp;rsquo;s desire and prayer to God for them is that they may be saved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 10:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And observe the extent of his love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have great sorrow and unceasing anguish in my heart. For I could wish that I myself were accursed and cut off from Christ for the sake of my brothers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 9:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this then the key to understanding? Even as we cry out to God over the unevenness of the blessing, is this our opportunity to learn how to truly love, and in so doing to glorify God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I was hungry and you gave me food, I was thirsty and you gave me drink, I was a stranger and you welcomed me, I was naked and you clothed me, I was sick and you visited me, I was in prison and you came to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Truly, I say to you, as you did it to one of the least of these my brothers, you did it to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:35-36, 40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the Lord enlarge our hearts for this broken world as we look around and see places where his blessing seems to be absent. And let us cry out to him for mercy, to the Lord, our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you think we have arrived at a place of only partial understanding, let us observe that Paul himself, the great apostle and teacher, is in just that place after three chapters of his own wrestling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, the depth of the riches and wisdom and knowledge of God! How unsearchable are his judgments and how inscrutable his ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 11:33, 36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cry out, Amy, to the one who is wise beyond understanding, and in places of meagre blessing love with his own love, from him and through him and to him, for his glory forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An axe-head floats</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/hendrik-cornelissen-x59BNivBcQ8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post An axe-head floats" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can a floating axe-head provide insight into the Father-heart of God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Elisha and his servants and the company of the prophets] went to the Jordan and began to cut down trees [to build a place for them to live]. As one of them was cutting down a tree, the iron axe-head fell into the water. “Oh, my lord,” he cried out, “it was borrowed!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man of God asked, “Where did it fall?” When he showed him the place, Elisha cut a stick and threw it there, and made the iron float. “Lift it out,” he said. Then the man reached out his hand and took it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Kings 6:4-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a curious little account. How are we to understand it? Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s note just what a man of God Elisha was. When Elijah was handing down to him the mantle of being the Lord&amp;rsquo;s prophet, Elisha asked to inherit a double portion of his spirit. (How cheeky was that? — 2 Kings 2:1-15) He certainly received it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the axe-head then. Losing an axe-head would have been no small matter⸺there was certainly no Mitre 10 Mega to provide a replacement. And consider the shame of losing borrowed equipment, especially something so valuable. But still, surely a trivial thing in the light of eternity? Why would the Lord even care? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t he be more concerned with the learning and growth opportunity afforded by suffering such a loss? Isn&amp;rsquo;t this life supposed to be about learning to suffer and submit to such? How easily we could fail to understand the Father-heart of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we actually see revealed here then? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. A lavish, gratuitously kind and compassionate miraculous response to a material loss. Yes, the man had been careless, and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have let this happen. But it did, and the Lord stepped in with no rebuke, demonstrating through his servant Elisha such affection and concern for one he loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with us. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s kindness and compassion for us is rooted in the reality of our situation. How ready he is to step in and rescue! He understands us, he understands our need, and his response is love and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run to your Heavenly Father, Amy, with any and all of your needs, because he cares for you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A mystery revealed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 06:38:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/david-clode-EDfZ0Sjmp_w-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A mystery revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know a mystery?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God’s grace that he lavished on us. With all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will according to his good pleasure, which he purposed in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an alternate reality, the Lord could have dealt with our sin as he did, and simply told us, it&amp;rsquo;s ok, we can be friends again, I&amp;rsquo;ve sorted it out. But in our reality, &lt;em&gt;with all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will&lt;/em&gt;. He desires us to know just what our rescue cost him, and what it cost his only son, as he lavished his grace on us. As he continues to lavish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have redemption &lt;em&gt;through his blood&lt;/em&gt;. The cost was enormous. The love that paid this price, unfathomable. The forgiveness of sins and restoration of relationship with our Heavenly Father, beyond all worth. And the revelation of this mystery, according to his good pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we understand what has been done for us, and why? The Lord desires that we do. If we really grasp this, won&amp;rsquo;t it magnify our love for him a hundredfold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know the mystery, Amy, and love the author of the mystery who has made it known! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Expectant and not disappointed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/patrick-fore-T2S4CatGdfQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Expectant and not disappointed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be expectant and not disappointed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living with high expectations of oneself and others is surely right, but can lead to ongoing disappointment, as we and those around us fall short of what we aspired to do and to be. How can the same not be true of the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should we expect of the Lord anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 27:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is anyone among you sick? &amp;hellip; the prayer offered in faith will make the sick person well; the Lord will raise them up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 5:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 91:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You know with all your heart and soul that not one of all the good promises the LORD your God gave you has failed. Every promise has been fulfilled; not one has failed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am the LORD, the God of all mankind. Is anything too hard for me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 32:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are we not just setting ourselves up for disappointment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However we deal with this, we must never lower our expectation of the Lord. He is the Creator, Almighty, Sovereign Lord, infinite in power and wisdom. He loves us his children absolutely, and he blesses us richly and without bounds. May we never doubt that!  And may we never limit our praying to what seems reasonable. If someone is sick, shame on me if I pray merely for their comfort rather than for miraculous healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To live with such expectation makes me so vulnerable, though. Vulnerable to disappointment. Vulnerable to the scorn of the sceptics. Vulnerable and defenceless. How can my faith survive this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that Abraham was strengthened in his faith (Rom 4:20). It is a work of the Lord. I commit completely, in faith, trusting. The Lord defends me.  It is miraculous grace.  The heartache may remain as I wait, in that amalgam of joy and pain which characterises the Christian life as we engage with the Lord&amp;rsquo;s work in this broken world. But disappointment does not crush me, does not crush my faith. How does this work? It is a mystery, a wondrous gift of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my, I seem to have written another tome. Good job I do this only once a week, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lean on him, trust him for his impossible promises, and praise him for his miraculous grace, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Experiencing grace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 06:32:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/experiencing-grace/denise-jans-IJy2ZUex0-Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Experiencing grace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we better perceive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s grace in all we experience, and what would that mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is full of frustrations and disappointments. Even for the Christian seeking the Lord with all of our heart, living a surrendered life, putting him first in everything, things may not turn out as we would have wished. And that&amp;rsquo;s not just small things. The whole course of one&amp;rsquo;s life could turn out to be so different from what was desired. Where is our loving Heavenly Father in this? Does he not want to bless his children? Absolutely he does! So what is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote to the Romans this oft-quoted verse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that in all things God works for the good of those who love him, who have been called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider that in the context of Solomon&amp;rsquo;s wisdom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In his heart a man plans his course, but the LORD determines his steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 16:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has hopes and desires for their own life. Some may be sufficiently well organised to have a plan! But the Lord determines their steps. It is his plans and purposes that prevail. Let us not delude ourselves that we can control our own destiny, and somehow plan our way there. That is for the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to dispel a misconception. Paul is not saying that everything that happens is good and is caused by God. That is observably false⸺terrible things do happen. Rather he is saying that whatever happens, God works in it and through it “for the good of those who love him”. Let us be those!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us learn to see the world through the lens of Romans 8:28 as it actually is then. May we consciously receive God&amp;rsquo;s grace in all that happens. “In all things” let us submit to his superior wisdom, knowing that there is no better eternal outcome than the one he has for us. When apparent disappointments come, let us receive them with a grateful heart. The Lord has seen things that we have not. His love is unfailing. He may very well be rescuing us from something we thought was better, but is in fact not.  He is the one who determines our steps, and it is very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive his grace with a grateful heart in all things, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Pharisaical heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-pharisaical-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 06:46:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-pharisaical-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-pharisaical-heart/tamara-gore-P4mxBJtINCw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Pharisaical heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What breaks our Father&amp;rsquo;s heart? That would be a long list to be sure. I&amp;rsquo;ll pick one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I got to see Les Misérables at the Regent. What a tremendous story of redemption, the power of love flowing through a redeemed life, and the triumph of love over adversity. But also so very sad⸺I was grateful for the darkness in the theatre, so no-one could see my tears. The saddest song? Some would say I Dreamed a Dream, and that is indeed crushing (“now life has killed the dream I dreamed”), or On My Own, Éponine&amp;rsquo;s song of unrequited love for Marius (“the trees are bare and everywhere the streets are full of strangers”). But there is another: Javert&amp;rsquo;s soliloquy, Stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Javert is the policeman who pursues the protagonist Jean Valjean through the decades, after he breaks parole from a 19 year sentence of slavery for stealing a loaf of bread to feed his starving family. Valjean receives unexpected grace and repents (“I feel my shame inside me like a knife. He told me that I have a soul. How does he know? What spirit comes to move my life? Is there another way to go?”). Thus he begins a sacrificial life of love, but Javert cannot accept this. Stars is his vow to pursue Valjean and never rest until he is again behind bars. He sings, “mine is the way of the Lord” (he is so wrong), and “those who falter and those who fall must pay the price” (wrong again, Javert — Rom 8:1-4, 31-39).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An isolated sad event cannot be a tragedy, no matter how heart-rending, as explained by Educating Rita&amp;rsquo;s teacher. Rather, a tragedy is the long and apparently inescapable trajectory of a life, set in motion by a particular course of events or an attitude of the heart, leading inexorably to one&amp;rsquo;s own destruction. It is the prolonged inevitability which makes it so. Javert eventually takes his own life, the only possible consequence given his Pharisaical heart, hardened over so many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many today live Javert&amp;rsquo;s life, bereft of grace. Each one is a tragedy, and each one breaks our Father&amp;rsquo;s heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love with the Father&amp;rsquo;s love, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
