<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>joy on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/joy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in joy on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/joy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Forgiving others</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/madhu-shesharam-KQZZCVyEWVk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving others" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we forgive those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the how, let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge that we must. This is not optional, it is commanded by Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If your brother or sister sins, rebuke them; and if they repent, forgive them. Even if they sin against you seven times in a day and seven times come back to you saying &amp;lsquo;I repent&amp;rsquo;, you must forgive them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am facing a situation in which this is a real challenge. The response I received to my articulated desire for reconciliation and relationship and mutual forgiveness and healing was a crushing and callous brush-off. What now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first attempt to forgive was a false start. I tried to diminish the magnitude of the offence, to find a way to receive it as a simple misunderstanding, to excuse the other&amp;rsquo;s behaviour. This failed because there was no truth in it. The behaviour was in fact wretched and reprehensible. I cannot deny it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then had to grapple with “if they repent”. In my situation, there is no repentance. There is stubborn and Pharisaical judgment and rejection, and refusal to engage in authentic relationship. It is crushing. Heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some writers have tried to argue that the requirement to forgive is conditional on repentance, and in this passage it indeed appears so. Is that the whole story though? I think not. But let&amp;rsquo;s not resort to a human argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this from the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer, and what Jesus said next in the Sermon on the Mount:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you forgive others when they sin against you, your heavenly Father will also forgive you. But if you do not forgive others their sins, your Father will not forgive your sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:12, 14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here our forgiveness of others is linked to God&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness of us no less. How vital then is it to forgive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When they came to the place called the Skull, there they crucified him, along with the criminals—one on his right, the other on his left. Jesus said, “Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they are doing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 23:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was there repentance here? Of course not! How are we called to live? Like Christ! And how can we find the power to do this? Only in him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I must die to self, again. But as I do, I find I am being transformed into Christ&amp;rsquo;s likeness. There is no greater joy, even in the midst of all this pain. The joy in that transformation is empowering indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lengthy process, an ongoing journey, and I am not yet done. May the Lord have mercy on that individual as I forgive, and continue to forgive, dying to self and becoming like Christ. And if they come to the point of repentance, may we be restored in authentic relationship again, by Christ&amp;rsquo;s power and for his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like Christ, Amy, in him and by his power and for his glory, fuelled by the joy in your own transformation! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Running with perseverance</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/running-with-perseverance/cameron-venti-I1EWTM5mFEM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Running with perseverance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a long race to run. How will we not grow weary and lose heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews tells us exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us. Let us fix our eyes on Jesus, the author and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy set before him endured the cross, scorning its shame, and sat down at the right hand of the throne of God. Consider him who endured such opposition from sinful men, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? By fixing our eyes on Jesus and considering him. Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack that a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running is hard and I get tired, but by fixing my eyes on Jesus one thing is sure. I will be running towards him, always. He is the author of my story, the author of my faith, the reason that I live and the reason that I live in him. He is also the perfecter (that is completer) of my faith, sustaining me so that I can finish the race. I will not fall because &amp;hellip; Jesus. Because of all that he is and all that he has done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did he do all this? He endured such opposition from sinful men — those he had come to save no less! He endured the pain and humiliation of the cross, and the real agony of it all: separation from the Father. But why? Why did he do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are told why he did it and how he endured: &lt;em&gt;for the joy set before him&lt;/em&gt;. And what was that joy? That joy was the knowledge that he was saving you and me, Amy. That was what gave him the strength to endure the unendurable. That was his joy. His love for you and his love for me, and saving you and saving me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that! Consider him! How loved we are! How comprehensive Jesus&#39; victory! How wonderful his love!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider him, Amy, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Joy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/joy/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 08:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/joy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/joy/mi-pham-FtZL0r4DZYk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Joy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we choose joy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; joy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t joy something that from time to time lands on us, thrills our heart, and lifts us into the Lord&amp;rsquo;s presence? How can we choose this for ourselves? In fact we can, and understanding this is the key to a deeper, richer, more joyous walk with the Lord, independent of the circumstances of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Paul&amp;rsquo;s command (a command, no less!) to the Philippians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says it again because it is of such great importance. We must understand this! But how can we rejoice when life is hard, and sorrow and pain feature so prominently in our world and in our lives? Paul tells us almost immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers and sisters, whatever is true, whatever is noble, whatever is right, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is admirable—if anything is excellent or praiseworthy—think about such things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these things we must think about, exactly? I am grateful to Jim Packer for presenting this so clearly, thus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God loves me, infinitely and eternally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything comes to me from God, at least with his permission and always under his protection, to further my eternal good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My saving knowledge of the Lord Jesus, which will eternally increase, is something supremely worth having.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel message of salvation that I seek to pass on to others is something supremely worth giving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Laid-Back Religion? Chapter 6: Joy&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By meditating on these matters constantly and faithfully, springs of joy well up in our hearts, turning our Christian walk into “an experience of contentment and exaltation of which the world knows nothing” ― &lt;em&gt;J.I. Packer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose joy, Amy, and meditate on the uplifting and glorious truths of the Lord! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Radiant disciples</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/autumn-goodman-vTL_qy03D1I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Radiant disciples" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t look at the sun, it&amp;rsquo;s far too bright. Any attempt even to look nearby overloads our retina, so all else fades into nothing. And so it is with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the source of the radiance. Ours is merely a reflection, unlikely to cause blindness, but bright and shining nonetheless, and enormously attractive to those who don&amp;rsquo;t have it. How does this work, then? We must consider how to be those who &lt;em&gt;look to him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with forgiveness — &lt;em&gt;their faces are never covered with shame&lt;/em&gt;. All is forgiven, all debt is cancelled and all shame is gone. This is the glorious truth that underpins everything we are as children of God. Rejoice in that forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues with hope. As we look to the Lord, we look with the hope that notwithstanding all that we have already received, his work in us is not yet complete. There&amp;rsquo;s more to come, and what is to come is so certain and so very good, and so much more than we could possibly ask or imagine. This is our source of joy, our source of radiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we love the Lord, with a grateful heart that magnifies that love, and irrepressible hope that fuels it with tremendous power. When someone is in love, absolutely captivated, they have a glow about them, evidenced in shining eyes and wonder. This is powerful and joyous, and others desire it. May we know this as we look to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him, Amy, bask in his glory which shines like the sun in all its brilliance, and be radiant! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
