<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>hope on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/hope/</link>
        <description>Recent content in hope on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 09:11:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/hope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Two victories</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 09:11:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/jordan-wozniak-xP_AGmeEa6s-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two victories" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, why am I writing to you on a Tuesday rather than a Wednesday? As you know, I like to ask the big questions, so let&amp;rsquo;s start with that! In fact, Megan and I are in Glenorchy, just about to embark on the Rees-Dart track, so we&amp;rsquo;ll be out of coverage for the next four days, and that&amp;rsquo;s the reason. With that out of the way, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the next big question. 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the first Easter victory, and how did that lead to the second?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two victories?  Yes, really!  The first victory was won on the cross, as Jesus died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jesus said, “It is finished.” With that, he bowed his head and gave up his spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished here means completed, fulfilled, accomplished. A triumphant, “I have done it!” This is the first victory, won at inconceivable cost, to the Son and the Father both. It is victory over sin, in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did this lead to the second? Paul explains exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your attitude should be the same as that of Christ Jesus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, being in very nature God, did not consider equality with God something to be grasped, but made himself nothing, taking the very nature of a servant, being made in human likeness. And being found in appearance as a man, he humbled himself and became obedient to death—even death on a cross! Therefore God exalted him to the highest place and gave him the name that is above every name, that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:5-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The how is in the therefore. Jesus made himself obedient even to death on a cross, and &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; God exalted him to the highest place and gave him the name that is above every name. This is the second victory, resurrection victory over death itself, in his life and ours both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how exalted is Jesus? &lt;em&gt;Every knee&lt;/em&gt; should bow, and &lt;em&gt;every tongue&lt;/em&gt; confess. Here&amp;rsquo;s John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the end of time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I heard every creature in heaven and on earth and under the earth and on the sea, and all that is in them, singing: “To him who sits on the throne and to the Lamb be praise and honour and glory and power, for ever and ever!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four living creatures said, “Amen”, and the elders fell down and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall down with them, Amy,  and worship the one who is worthy to receive praise and honour and glory and power, for ever and ever! 🙏🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Radiant disciples</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/autumn-goodman-vTL_qy03D1I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Radiant disciples" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t look at the sun, it&amp;rsquo;s far too bright. Any attempt even to look nearby overloads our retina, so all else fades into nothing. And so it is with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the source of the radiance. Ours is merely a reflection, unlikely to cause blindness, but bright and shining nonetheless, and enormously attractive to those who don&amp;rsquo;t have it. How does this work, then? We must consider how to be those who &lt;em&gt;look to him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with forgiveness — &lt;em&gt;their faces are never covered with shame&lt;/em&gt;. All is forgiven, all debt is cancelled and all shame is gone. This is the glorious truth that underpins everything we are as children of God. Rejoice in that forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues with hope. As we look to the Lord, we look with the hope that notwithstanding all that we have already received, his work in us is not yet complete. There&amp;rsquo;s more to come, and what is to come is so certain and so very good, and so much more than we could possibly ask or imagine. This is our source of joy, our source of radiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we love the Lord, with a grateful heart that magnifies that love, and irrepressible hope that fuels it with tremendous power. When someone is in love, absolutely captivated, they have a glow about them, evidenced in shining eyes and wonder. This is powerful and joyous, and others desire it. May we know this as we look to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him, Amy, bask in his glory which shines like the sun in all its brilliance, and be radiant! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The eyes of your heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:31:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/javardh-FC59Au36moM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The eyes of your heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the eyes of our heart for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still stuck on this desert island, reading Ephesians 1. It is not a bad place to be! Consider what Paul writes about the eyes of our heart. (The heart is the seat of life and strength, the centre of one&amp;rsquo;s will. That is mind, soul, spirit, one&amp;rsquo;s entire emotional nature and understanding.)  Paul writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I pray also that the eyes of your heart may be enlightened in order that you may know the hope to which he has called you, the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and his incomparably great power for us who believe. That power is like the working of his mighty strength, which he exerted in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a prayer. Paul asks for enlightening of the eyes of our heart. We must ask for this thing that otherwise we may miss. Notice that what the enlightened eyes of our heart do is to &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;. Merely seeing is curiosity. Knowing is life-changing. What is there to know? Three things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope. My dictionary defines hope as grounds for believing that something good may happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not wishful thinking, there are actual grounds for believing this. In our context, “something good” is understated, to say the least! May the enlightened eyes of our heart know the best thing that could possibly happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our glorious inheritance in the saints. What is this? In v3 Paul writes that the Lord “has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ”. Note the tense. Something has already happened! But what of the rest? The prophetic past tense is used throughout scripture where a future event is so certain it is written as if it had already occurred. The fulfillment of our future blessing in the heavenly realms is that certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His incomparably great power for us. This is the same power that raised Christ from the dead. It is not a small thing, and it is at work in us who believe! When we feel overwhelmed or empty, and so aware of our need for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and grace, perhaps his mighty strength which raised Christ from the dead will be enough. We must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the eyes of your heart be enlightened, Amy, in order that you may know, really know, these life changing things. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
