<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>hope on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/hope/</link>
        <description>Recent content in hope on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/hope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The elephant in the room</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-elephant-in-the-room/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-elephant-in-the-room/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-elephant-in-the-room/atwena-goodman-PB4dNSELi_E-unsplash-cropped.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The elephant in the room" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the elephant in the room of Isaiah 6?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s vision of the Lord seated on a throne, high and exalted, is a glimpse into heaven itself and convicts him deeply of his own sinfulness. We should be similarly convicted. But immediately after his guilt is taken away and his sin atoned for, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And I heard the voice of the Lord saying, “Whom shall I send, and who will go for us?” Then I said, “Here I am! Send me.” And he said, “Go, and say to this people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘Keep on hearing, but do not understand; keep on seeing, but do not perceive.’ Make the heart of this people dull, and their ears heavy, and blind their eyes; lest they see with their eyes, and hear with their ears, and understand with their hearts,
and turn and be healed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:8-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we to make of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said a similar thing to his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the disciples came and said to him, “Why do you speak to them in parables?” And he answered them, “To you it has been given to know the secrets of the kingdom of heaven, but to them it has not been given. For to the one who has, more will be given, and he will have an abundance, but from the one who has not, even what he has will be taken away. This is why I speak to them in parables, because seeing they do not see, and hearing they do not hear, nor do they understand. Indeed, in their case the prophecy of Isaiah is fulfilled &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:10-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must understand this in the context of the verbs that the Lord uses when commanding Isaiah: make the heart of this people dull, and their ears heavy, and blind their eyes. This is not a passive observation of failure to understand. It is the actual cause. To them it has not been given. The Lord himself confounds the understanding of the lost, lest they turn and be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we to make of it? And how is it remotely fair?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we must not brush this aside merely because it offends our sensibilities. May we never presume so to stand in judgment on the revealed word of God. He is sovereign, not us. So we must grapple, and we must grapple in the context of what we know to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then do we know to be true? Behold God&amp;rsquo;s own description of himself, his response to Moses&amp;rsquo; request, please show me now your ways, that I may know you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had no right to expect that the infinitely powerful creator God of the universe, glorious in splendour and terrifying in holiness, would be quite so good and kind. But we must not overlook that the Lord, whose name is Jealous, is a jealous God (Exodus 34:14). Nor must we overlook the judgment to the third and fourth generation, nor the steadfast love to the thousandth generation, nor the orders of magnitude difference between these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately our response will be the same as Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I said, “How long, O Lord?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord? We have grappled with this before. But here we must notice something else, even after the land has become a desolate waste, and after the burning again of the tenth that remains⸺terebinth or oak, whose stump remains when it is felled: &lt;em&gt;the holy seed is its stump&lt;/em&gt; (Isaiah 6:13)⸺hope remains! With God, all things are possible, and hope remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in the mystery of the confounding, Amy, know that all his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness, and that hope remains! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Jesus is alive!</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/jesus-is-alive/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/jesus-is-alive/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/jesus-is-alive/todd-kent-PsLrgT55DeM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Jesus is alive!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference does it make that Jesus is alive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into that, let&amp;rsquo;s firstly celebrate the joyous truth of it: Jesus is alive! He is risen indeed! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what difference does it make?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us. Since, therefore, we have now been justified by his blood, much more shall we be saved by him from the wrath of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are justified in the sight of God by Jesus&amp;rsquo; blood, accomplished by his death on the cross. This is amazing grace, freely given by the one who loves us beyond imagining. Praise him! By this our sins are counted against us no more. The slate is wiped clean. And wiped clean again. And again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, this is only half a gospel. Paul underlines it for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And if Christ has not been raised, your faith is futile and you are still in your sins. Then those also who have fallen asleep in Christ have perished. If in Christ we have hope in this life only, we are of all people most to be pitied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 15:17-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to notice some who live by justification alone⸺grateful for forgiveness of sins, muddling along in life, asking for forgiveness over and over for those same besetting sins⸺poor beggars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the power of the resurrection there would be no victory. We would still be in our sins, all of us, over and over. And after that, only death⸺a people most to be pitied. Poor beggars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is not so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were buried therefore with him by baptism into death, in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, we too might walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if we have been united with him in a death like his, we shall certainly be united with him in a resurrection like his. We know that our old self was crucified with him in order that the body of sin might be brought to nothing, so that we would no longer be enslaved to sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:4-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Jesus is alive, we walk in newness of life right now, by his resurrection power, no longer slaves to sin but rejoicing as slaves to righteousness, rejoicing in victory over sin. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also at the end of our earthly lives, we shall certainly be united with him in a resurrection like his. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is alive, Amy!! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The helmet of salvation</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/Cypraecassis_rufaGlobal.png" alt="Featured image of post The helmet of salvation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the helmet of salvation a misnomer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the helmet of salvation &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:13, 17a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What actually is this helmet of salvation that Paul tells us to put on? It can&amp;rsquo;t be salvation per se, as that is a gift of and from the Lord, received through faith. What is it then that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; should put on, and continue to put on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is found in a similar exhortation Paul writes to the Thessalonians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But since we belong to the day, let us be self-controlled, putting on faith and love as a breastplate, and the hope of salvation as a helmet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s all about &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt;⸺the hope of salvation. Recall what hope is. It&amp;rsquo;s not some finger-crossing wishful thinking. By no means! It is grounds for believing that something good will happen, with certainty. And in this case that is something overwhelmingly wonderfully bountifully joyously good, something worth truly waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the case of salvation, what is there still to hope for? Don&amp;rsquo;t we already have it? The simple truth is this: our salvation is already accomplished, but not yet complete. One day it will be so and the battle will be over. That is a certainty, and until then this hope is stored up for us in heaven (Colossians 1:5-6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, the process by which we receive this salvation is ongoing and joyous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Though you have not seen [Jesus], you love him; and even though you do not see him now, you believe in him and are filled with an inexpressible and glorious joy, for you are receiving the goal of your faith, the salvation of your souls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the present continuous tense here. We &lt;em&gt;are receiving&lt;/em&gt; the goal of our faith, which is our salvation. The process is ongoing and will last for all of our earthly lives, but it will eventually come to an end, as recounted in John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the end of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I heard a loud voice in heaven say: “Now have come the salvation and the power and the kingdom of our God, and the authority of his Christ. For the accuser of our brothers and sisters, who accuses them before our God day and night, has been hurled down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 12:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anticipate that day with great joy, Amy, and in the meantime, put on and continue to put on the hope of salvation as a helmet! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Two victories</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 09:11:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/jordan-wozniak-xP_AGmeEa6s-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two victories" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, why am I writing to you on a Tuesday rather than a Wednesday? As you know, I like to ask the big questions, so let&amp;rsquo;s start with that! In fact, Megan and I are in Glenorchy, just about to embark on the Rees-Dart track, so we&amp;rsquo;ll be out of coverage for the next four days, and that&amp;rsquo;s the reason. With that out of the way, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the next big question. 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the first Easter victory, and how did that lead to the second?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two victories?  Yes, really!  The first victory was won on the cross, as Jesus died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said, “It is finished.” With that, he bowed his head and gave up his spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished here means completed, fulfilled, accomplished. A triumphant, “I have done it!” This is the first victory, won at inconceivable cost, to the Son and the Father both. It is victory over sin, in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did this lead to the second? Paul explains exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your attitude should be the same as that of Christ Jesus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, being in very nature God, did not consider equality with God something to be grasped, but made himself nothing, taking the very nature of a servant, being made in human likeness. And being found in appearance as a man, he humbled himself and became obedient to death⸺even death on a cross! Therefore God exalted him to the highest place and gave him the name that is above every name, that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:5-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The how is in the therefore. Jesus made himself obedient even to death on a cross, and &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; God exalted him to the highest place and gave him the name that is above every name. This is the second victory, resurrection victory over death itself, in his life and ours both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how exalted is Jesus? &lt;em&gt;Every knee&lt;/em&gt; should bow, and &lt;em&gt;every tongue&lt;/em&gt; confess. Here&amp;rsquo;s John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the end of time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I heard every creature in heaven and on earth and under the earth and on the sea, and all that is in them, singing: “To him who sits on the throne and to the Lamb be praise and honour and glory and power, for ever and ever!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four living creatures said, “Amen”, and the elders fell down and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall down with them, Amy,  and worship the one who is worthy to receive praise and honour and glory and power, for ever and ever! 🙏🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Radiant disciples</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/autumn-goodman-vTL_qy03D1I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Radiant disciples" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t look at the sun, it&amp;rsquo;s far too bright. Any attempt even to look nearby overloads our retina, so all else fades into nothing. And so it is with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the source of the radiance. Ours is merely a reflection, unlikely to cause blindness, but bright and shining nonetheless, and enormously attractive to those who don&amp;rsquo;t have it. How does this work, then? We must consider how to be those who &lt;em&gt;look to him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with forgiveness⸺&lt;em&gt;their faces are never covered with shame&lt;/em&gt;. All is forgiven, all debt is cancelled and all shame is gone. This is the glorious truth that underpins everything we are as children of God. Rejoice in that forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues with hope. As we look to the Lord, we look with the hope that notwithstanding all that we have already received, his work in us is not yet complete. There&amp;rsquo;s more to come, and what is to come is so certain and so very good, and so much more than we could possibly ask or imagine. This is our source of joy, our source of radiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we love the Lord, with a grateful heart that magnifies that love, and irrepressible hope that fuels it with tremendous power. When someone is in love, absolutely captivated, they have a glow about them, evidenced in shining eyes and wonder. This is powerful and joyous, and others desire it. May we know this as we look to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him, Amy, bask in his glory which shines like the sun in all its brilliance, and be radiant! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The eyes of your heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:31:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/javardh-FC59Au36moM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The eyes of your heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the eyes of our heart for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still stuck on this desert island, reading Ephesians 1. It is not a bad place to be! Consider what Paul writes about the eyes of our heart. (The heart is the seat of life and strength, the centre of one&amp;rsquo;s will. That is mind, soul, spirit, one&amp;rsquo;s entire emotional nature and understanding.)  Paul writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I pray also that the eyes of your heart may be enlightened in order that you may know the hope to which he has called you, the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and his incomparably great power for us who believe. That power is like the working of his mighty strength, which he exerted in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a prayer. Paul asks for enlightening of the eyes of our heart. We must ask for this thing that otherwise we may miss. Notice that what the enlightened eyes of our heart do is to &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;. Merely seeing is curiosity. Knowing is life-changing. What is there to know? Three things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope. My dictionary defines hope as grounds for believing that something good may happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not wishful thinking, there are actual grounds for believing this. In our context, “something good” is understated, to say the least! May the enlightened eyes of our heart know the best thing that could possibly happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our glorious inheritance in the saints. What is this? In v3 Paul writes that the Lord “has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ”. Note the tense. Something has already happened! But what of the rest? The prophetic past tense is used throughout scripture where a future event is so certain it is written as if it had already occurred. The fulfillment of our future blessing in the heavenly realms is that certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His incomparably great power for us. This is the same power that raised Christ from the dead. It is not a small thing, and it is at work in us who believe! When we feel overwhelmed or empty, and so aware of our need for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and grace, perhaps his mighty strength which raised Christ from the dead will be enough. We must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the eyes of your heart be enlightened, Amy, in order that you may know, really know, these life changing things. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
