<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>revelation on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/revelation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in revelation on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 06:38:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/revelation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A mystery revealed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 06:38:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-mystery-revealed/david-clode-EDfZ0Sjmp_w-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A mystery revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know a mystery?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God’s grace that he lavished on us. With all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will according to his good pleasure, which he purposed in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an alternate reality, the Lord could have dealt with our sin as he did, and simply told us, it&amp;rsquo;s ok, we can be friends again, I&amp;rsquo;ve sorted it out. But in our reality, &lt;em&gt;with all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will&lt;/em&gt;. He desires us to know just what our rescue cost him, and what it cost his only son, as he lavished his grace on us. As he continues to lavish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have redemption &lt;em&gt;through his blood&lt;/em&gt;. The cost was enormous. The love that paid this price, unfathomable. The forgiveness of sins and restoration of relationship with our Heavenly Father, beyond all worth. And the revelation of this mystery, according to his good pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we understand what has been done for us, and why? The Lord desires that we do. If we really grasp this, won&amp;rsquo;t it magnify our love for him a hundredfold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know the mystery, Amy, and love the author of the mystery who has made it known! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Desert island</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 06:43:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/pablo-garcia-saldana-K1YRblz-rD0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Desert island" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could take only one chapter of the Bible with you to a desert island, which would you choose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, my pick would be Ephesians Chapter One. I cannot possibly do the whole chapter justice in this short letter, so for now let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one verse. (I may have to return to the wider chapter another time. Perhaps several times!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I keep asking that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the glorious Father, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and revelation, so that you &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you complete that prayer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; may be able to make good choices in your life? &amp;hellip; may be able to discern his will for you? &amp;hellip; may be able to better understand what is happening around you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, none of these! Paul asks this of the Lord so that you “&amp;hellip; may know him better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That you may know the Lord better! This is what the Spirit of wisdom and revelation is for. That I may know him better. To know and be known, this is the ultimate in relationship. But how can we possibly know the infinite, everlasting, majestic God, creator of the ends of the earth, of the universe? It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to know such a one, surely, with our finite minds, with our sinful hearts. And yet, the Spirit of wisdom and revelation makes the impossible, possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we marvel at this, let us notice that this is not a small thing Paul asks for. He &lt;em&gt;keeps asking&lt;/em&gt;, persisting in prayer for the stuff that really matters. Keep asking, Amy, for the stuff that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one he keeps asking is God, the glorious Father. He is glorious, and it is glorious that he is our father. He is the source of all that is good, and he is kind and generous beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the glorious Father, give you the Spirit of wisdom and revelation, Amy, so that you may know him better! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently when the future is uncertain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/arthur-ogleznev-rWDumHFt8E8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently when the future is uncertain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently when the future is uncertain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things we would like to know. What will I do with my life? Will it be worthwhile? How will I live? Will I be able to use the talents God has given me for his glory? Where will I go? Is my soul mate out there somewhere? Will I be alone? How can I know I will be ok? Why won&amp;rsquo;t God tell me these things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the Lord does not tell us such things ahead of time, and nor should we expect it. If he does reveal something, as he occasionally does, even an incredible and specific promise, it is unlikely to be how or when. What is my part then? What must I do? I must trust him, and I must live for him with my whole heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the first thing I wrote to you Amy, back in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By choosing to trust, to walk by faith, with all of our hope in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s unfailing love, we can delight him. I will say it again. We can delight him! Without uncertainty there can be no faith, so let us embrace it, and show the Lord that we really can walk by faith. What an opportunity to show him that! There is no risk, really. Read Psalm 145 again, and believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
