<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>promise on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/promise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in promise on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/promise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faith vs reason</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Does radical faith require us to switch off our intellect?
A dear friend of mine has been having what I would call a faith crisis. In the context of my ongoing waiting on an impossible promise from the Lord, he cannot relate to someone who he would say is living in the hope of something that contradicts the observed and obvious reality. He asks, how could I have abandoned reason and switched off the rational part of my brain in quite such a naive way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get what you want</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What if I told you there was a way to get exactly what you want? That the Spirit would work towards this end, and the Lord himself would make it so? Absolutely guaranteed. Are you interested in that?
 Delight yourself in the LORD and he will give you the desires of your heart.
― Psalm 37:4 What kind of promise is this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem too good to be true?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impossible</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we receive it when God speaks the impossible?
We have many examples of God speaking something impossible. Why does he do that?
Joshua was told to march the Israelite army around the walls of Jericho for seven days, and the walls would collapse, but even before he was so instructed, we find this.
 The LORD said to Joshua, “See, I have delivered Jericho into your hands, along with its king and its fighting men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we know for sure that all we are hoping for in eternity is real, and that it will be as promised?
I think I&amp;rsquo;m just about ready to leave this desert island, and I see a boat on the horizon (yay!), but first let&amp;rsquo;s look into Ephesians 1 for one last time.
 And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
