<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>promise on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/promise/</link>
        <description>Recent content in promise on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 07:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/promise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How long, O Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 07:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/zoltan-tasi-CLJeQCr2F_A-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How long, O Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most unanswered question in the Bible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever?&lt;br&gt;
How long will you hide your face from me?&lt;br&gt;
How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day?&lt;br&gt;
How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the Lord answer? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t he know how hard it is to wait on him? Why won&amp;rsquo;t he at least tell us how long? Imagine how much more straightforward it would be if he did. “Hang in there, Amy, for eighteen months. And for you, Simon, six years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does he not answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, this is not all that hard to understand. Paul points us at two reasons in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, because I have heard of your faith in the Lord Jesus and your love toward all the saints, I do not cease to give thanks for you, remembering you in my prayers, that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of him, having the eyes of your hearts enlightened, that you may know what is the hope to which he has called you, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4, 15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the eyes of our hearts enlightened that we may know what is the hope to which he has called us⸺the first reason is our faith, which requires us to use the eyes of our hearts rather than the eyes of our faces. Waiting is faith building, oh how it is that! Waiting confidently on the Lord, not doubting⸺it changes us. It grows our faith. Hear two questions from the Lord in the waiting time: “Do you trust me, Amy?” and the second, harder one: “How much do you trust me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is what David clings to in our psalm. And knowing how long would require less trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason is our holiness. We were chosen in Christ before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. Our sanctification, our steadily increasing holiness, is a work of the Holy Spirit, but it is also our own most earnest hard work. What better work is there to do in the waiting time, that at the time of fulfillment we may be found to be holy and blameless in his sight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habbakuk also cries out with the same question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O LORD, how long shall I cry for help, and you will not hear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his particular case, the Lord answers, and praise him for that answer in which we also can rejoice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days
that you would not believe if told.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for us. We would not believe if told the work the Lord is doing in our own waiting time. It is a work of faith, of holiness, and of fulfillment of promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise the Lord, wonder and be astounded, Amy, for he is doing a work in our lives which we would not believe if told! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faith vs reason</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/faith-vs-reason/dan-cristian-padure-h3kuhYUCE9A-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faith vs reason" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does radical faith require us to switch off our intellect?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dear friend of mine has been having what I would call a faith crisis. In the context of my ongoing waiting on an impossible promise from the Lord, he cannot relate to someone who he would say is living in the hope of something that contradicts the observed and obvious reality. He asks, how could I have abandoned reason and switched off the rational part of my brain in quite such a naive way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I argue that in fact the opposite is true, and that I have brought all my intellect and understanding to bear in my faith situation. How so? And what does the Bible have to say about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom, and knowledge of the Holy One is understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 9:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One aspect of wisdom is &lt;em&gt;applied intellect&lt;/em&gt;, that is intellect used to align a life with knowledge of the Holy One in a practical way, in order to live that life on the right path.  And wisdom begins with the fear of the Lord. Recall Tim Keller&amp;rsquo;s definition: “The fear of the Lord is a reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Lord of all creation loves me to the extent that he gave up his only Son to an excruciating death in order to rescue me, and has promised abundant life and ongoing rescue in him, the only rational response is to completely cast myself upon his love, trusting him, absolutely. Anything less betrays a lack of understanding of the eternal reality. (Sadly it seems to me that few indeed are able to rationalize to this extent.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this rational response look like then? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. Diving headfirst into the wellspring of life. Living confidently on the firm foundation of such a promise from the Lord.  Ruthless consistency is the key which unlocks the understanding to be able to live like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so radical faith in the one who is faithful and true is in fact the only way to live with intellectual integrity. Having tested it, we must lean into it as the foundation of our life. Nothing else makes any sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with radical faith, Amy, employing all of your intellect to live a life increasingly aligned with your growing knowledge of the Holy One! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to get what you want</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/jen-theodore-ualbj7tyJH0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to get what you want" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I told you there was a way to get exactly what you want? That the Spirit would work towards this end, and the Lord himself would make it so? Absolutely guaranteed. Are you interested in that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of promise is this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem too good to be true? Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to delight yourself in the Lord? It is no small thing. Let me paraphrase. &lt;em&gt;Make the Lord the desire of your heart, and he will give you &amp;hellip; the desire of your heart.&lt;/em&gt; Dwell in that for a while. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re not disappointed, because truth be told, it&amp;rsquo;s a phenomenal promise. Jeremiah says the same, just after that verse that everyone quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You will seek me and find me when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this look like? To seek the Lord with all your heart? To make him your heart&amp;rsquo;s desire? It is surely time-consuming. In fact, it is all-consuming. It is worth waking up early for. It is worth pursuing through the day, and resting in through the night. We cannot afford to be half-hearted in this. David said as much to his own son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you, my son Solomon, acknowledge the God of your father, and serve him with wholehearted devotion and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches every heart and understands every motive behind the thoughts. If you seek him, he will be found by you;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There can be no pretending here. He &lt;em&gt;understands every motive behind the thoughts&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s confronting! So we must be absolutely ruthless, rooting out and expelling every misplaced thought and motive. This takes real work, earnest heart-work. But it is Spirit work. It is what he does. It is the work he knows so well. In him, and only in him, we can do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the Lord, Amy, and he will give you the desires of your heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Impossible</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/isaac-quesada-dZYI4ga2eUA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Impossible" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we receive it when God speaks the impossible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have many examples of God speaking something impossible. Why does he do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua was told to march the Israelite army around the walls of Jericho for seven days, and the walls would collapse, but even before he was so instructed, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Joshua, “See, I have delivered Jericho into your hands, along with its king and its fighting men.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 6:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if it had already happened! Joshua had to act on the basis that something impossible would happen. (And it did.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably Abraham had it even harder. He had to wait on an impossible promise, for twenty-five years! Waiting is perhaps harder than doing. And waiting for twenty-five years?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other examples in the Bible of God speaking the impossible. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: &lt;em&gt;he is still doing it today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I the LORD do not change.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 13:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bible itself teaches that we are to understand it in terms of our own experience when it says that Paul, Barnabas and Elijah were human beings like us and that Jesus knows how we feel in our weaknesses because he himself “in every respect has been tested as we are” (Heb 4:15). It means that &lt;em&gt;their experience was substantially like our own&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must pray for the faith and for the experiences that would enable us to believe that &lt;em&gt;such things could happen to us&lt;/em&gt;. Only then will we be able to recognize, accept and dwell in them when they come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dallas Willard, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hearing God, Chapter 2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we receive it when God speaks the impossible? It is in fact a high honour, an invitation to demonstrate radical faith, and to grow in that faith. Perhaps God reserves such things for those for whom he has great plans, which will require great faith. (That&amp;rsquo;s a little scary, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?)  No-one starts with such faith, but the Lord in his wisdom knows what he is doing.  Again, consider Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I hold on to this verse, which has kept me going for some years, and was itself given to me in a miraculous way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God is not a man, that he should lie, nor a son of man, that he should change his mind. Does he speak and then not act? Does he promise and not fulfill?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 23:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This remains even if the promise is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the word of the LORD came to Jeremiah: “I am the LORD, the God of all mankind. Is anything too hard for me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 32:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait on the Lord in faith, Amy, knowing that he who promised is faithful (Heb 10:23), even if it seems impossible!  🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/ishan-seefromthesky-2d7n2sfYjHY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know for sure that all we are hoping for in eternity is real, and that it will be as promised?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m just about ready to leave this desert island, and I see a boat on the horizon (yay!), but first let&amp;rsquo;s look into Ephesians 1 for one last time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession⸺to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some really significant points to note here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we in or out? We have been &lt;em&gt;included&lt;/em&gt;. Most assuredly in! And not on our own merit, as if anyone could come along later and say, there&amp;rsquo;s been some mistake. No, we have been included &lt;em&gt;in Christ&lt;/em&gt;. The power and the glory are his, and we are included, in him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have been &lt;em&gt;marked in him with a seal&lt;/em&gt;. When a legal contract used to be signed, both parties would sign and apply a wax seal with the impression of a signet ring, as authentication. The Holy Spirit authenticates us as children of God, the genuine article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Holy Spirit is a &lt;em&gt;deposit&lt;/em&gt;, that is part of the greater whole which is to follow, paid immediately, as a foretaste. There is more to come!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The deposit is a &lt;em&gt;guarantee&lt;/em&gt; of what is to come. What is to come is a certainty, and cannot be revoked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is guaranteed is &lt;em&gt;our inheritance&lt;/em&gt;. If we are children, then we are heirs⸺heirs of God and co-heirs with Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are &lt;em&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s possession&lt;/em&gt;, bought with a price, and he will never give us up. I am his and he is mine, forever. You too, Amy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prize is our &lt;em&gt;redemption&lt;/em&gt;, which is already accomplished, but not yet complete. One day it will be so, and we will shed off all that tires us out and drags us down. How I long for that day!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Spirit living in us not only proves our adoption by the Lord, but gives us power to live victoriously, a foretaste of what is certain, of what is promised and true. A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance! Now we can truly say this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise be to the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise him, Amy, for such blessing as this! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
