<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>commitment on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/commitment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in commitment on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/commitment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Living confidently when the future is uncertain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/arthur-ogleznev-rWDumHFt8E8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently when the future is uncertain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently when the future is uncertain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things we would like to know. What will I do with my life? Will it be worthwhile? How will I live? Will I be able to use the talents God has given me for his glory? Where will I go? Is my soul mate out there somewhere? Will I be alone? How can I know I will be ok? Why won&amp;rsquo;t God tell me these things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the Lord does not tell us such things ahead of time, and nor should we expect it. If he does reveal something, as he occasionally does, even an incredible and specific promise, it is unlikely to be how or when. What is my part then? What must I do? I must trust him, and I must live for him with my whole heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the first thing I wrote to you Amy, back in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By choosing to trust, to walk by faith, with all of our hope in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s unfailing love, we can delight him. I will say it again. We can delight him! Without uncertainty there can be no faith, so let us embrace it, and show the Lord that we really can walk by faith. What an opportunity to show him that! There is no risk, really. Read Psalm 145 again, and believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
