<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>courage on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/courage/</link>
        <description>Recent content in courage on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/courage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Courage and kindness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/courage-and-kindness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/courage-and-kindness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/courage-and-kindness/pexels-pixabay-36785.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Courage and kindness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What other family values did Boaz have besides kindness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you noticed who his mother was? Matthew tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and Salmon the father of Boaz by Rahab, and Boaz the father of Obed by Ruth, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever noticed this before? Boaz&amp;rsquo; mother was none other than Rahab, the Canaanite prostitute of Jericho. His wife was Ruth, that Moabite outsider. And in this verse we see these two women, mother and daughter-in-law, neither of them children of the promise, but both having made choices which exceedingly honoured and pleased the Lord, and so both themselves unusually honoured by being named in Matthew&amp;rsquo;s genealogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was the primary value that Rahab demonstrated during the fall of Jericho? Here&amp;rsquo;s what: it was astonishing courage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also showed astonishing insight. No-one chooses where to be born, and she certainly hadn&amp;rsquo;t chosen to be born in the city of Jericho in the land of Canaan, that land consigned to destruction by the Lord for its horrifically evil practices and to make room for his chosen people. No-one chooses where to be born. But she alone among the people of Jericho had both the insight and the courage to choose for the Lord, a choice which honoured and pleased him, and a choice which was to deliver both her and her loved ones from that awful retribution on the city where she lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look what happened after she chose to shelter Joshua&amp;rsquo;s spies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the king of Jericho sent to Rahab, saying, “Bring out the men who have come to you, who entered your house, for they have come to search out all the land.” But the woman had taken the two men and hidden them. And she said, “True, the men came to me, but I did not know where they were from. And when the gate was about to be closed at dark, the men went out. I do not know where the men went. Pursue them quickly, for you will overtake them.” But she had brought them up to the roof and hid them with the stalks of flax that she had laid in order on the roof.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 2:3-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that she had her own house, and she was the master of it. A woman of some means, brave and resourceful, she was no-one&amp;rsquo;s victim. And what courage she had, to defy the king of Jericho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before the men lay down, she came up to them on the roof and said to the men, “I know that the LORD has given you the land, and that the fear of you has fallen upon us, and that all the inhabitants of the land melt away before you. For we have heard how the LORD dried up the water of the Red Sea before you when you came out of Egypt, and what you did to the two kings of the Amorites who were beyond the Jordan, to Sihon and Og, whom you devoted to destruction. And as soon as we heard it, our hearts melted, and there was no spirit left in any man because of you, for the LORD your God, he is God in the heavens above and on the earth beneath.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 2:8-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no spirit left in any man in Jericho, but there was clearly spirit left in this woman, this Canaanite prostitute⸺sufficient spirit to defy the king of Jericho and to choose for the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And furthermore, don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the courage that it would have taken to choose a life among the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own people. In Jericho she was a woman of means, master of her own house. Who knew what she would be now? Certainly she wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be continuing with her current profession!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did happen as a result of her courage and kindness? We can infer much from the honour shown to Rahab by her inclusion in Matthew&amp;rsquo;s genealogy of Jesus our Lord and Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Great is our Lord, and abundant in power; his understanding is beyond measure. The LORD lifts up the humble; he casts the wicked to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, Amy, that one such as Rahab can choose for the Lord and be lifted up and highly honoured by him. Great is the Lord! 🙌🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The spiritual battle</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-spiritual-battle/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-spiritual-battle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-spiritual-battle/cade-roberts-EpIUbeFrqwQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The spiritual battle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that our most holy and righteous prayers, those prayed for God&amp;rsquo;s glory and the advancement of the Kingdom, are not answered immediately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know we can pray in Jesus&amp;rsquo; name as he wonderfully lays upon our hearts those things which are on his own heart. There is much joy in such praying and there is intimacy in relationship with Jesus as our own most earnest desires become aligned with his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why then the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to know that there is a spiritual battle raging, for there is indeed a spiritual battle and we are right in the middle of it and never more so than when we pray such Kingdom prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exiled in Babylon, Daniel experienced this in his own time of crying out to the Lord and waiting on him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In those days I, Daniel, was mourning for three weeks. I ate no delicacies, no meat or wine entered my mouth, nor did I anoint myself at all, for the full three weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seventy long years had passed since Daniel had been taken into exile in his youth and he was now an old man. Throughout this time he had lived a life pleasing to the Lord. Consider for a moment: that earnest young man carried off into Babylon all those years previously, who with his three friends set their course with such boldness and determination to honour the Lord and live for him alone. Here he was now as an old man, no less dedicated and no less determined. Praise the Lord for Daniel and others like him, for the consistency of such lives lived for the Lord through so many years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so here he was, praying most earnestly about matters central to the Kingdom, matters on God&amp;rsquo;s own heart, and in the praying there was mourning and waiting. But surely even Daniel wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I lifted up my eyes and looked, and behold, a man clothed in linen, with a belt of fine gold from Uphaz around his waist. His body was like beryl, his face like the appearance of lightning, his eyes like flaming torches, his arms and legs like the gleam of burnished bronze, and the sound of his words like the sound of a multitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was no mere angelic messenger. Here stood an angelic warrior, come to strengthen Daniel and give him the courage he would need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he said to me, “Fear not, Daniel, for from the first day that you set your heart to understand and humbled yourself before your God, your words have been heard, and I have come because of your words. The prince of the kingdom of Persia withstood me twenty-one days, but Michael, one of the chief princes, came to help me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly notice the affirmation of a life lived before the Lord⸺Daniel&amp;rsquo;s whole-hearted devotion to the Lord through all these years had not gone unnoticed. His prayers had not gone unheeded, and the angelic warrior was standing before him precisely because of those prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spiritual battle had been raging and it was not over, but Daniel&amp;rsquo;s praying mattered so greatly to the commander of the army of the Lord that he had momentarily spared an angelic warrior from the battle to strengthen and encourage Daniel, his loyal and faithful prayer warrior, equally engaged in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said, “O man greatly loved, fear not, peace be with you; be strong and of good courage.” And as he spoke to me, I was strengthened and said, “Let my lord speak, for you have strengthened me.” Then he said, “Do you know why I have come to you? But now I will return to fight against the prince of Persia; and when I go out, behold, the prince of Greece will come. But I will tell you what is inscribed in the book of truth: there is none who contends by my side against these except Michael, your prince.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:19-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spiritual battle continued to rage and the angelic warrior could not stay. He had taken time out to come to Daniel to strengthen and encourage him for what lay ahead, and furthermore to remind him that he was a man greatly loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spiritual battle continues to rage today. We must engage faithfully in prayer, knowing full well that answering our own most earnest and Kingdom-centric prayers is no small or easy matter. May our own prayers be so aligned with the plans and purposes of the commander of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s army in this spiritual battle that we find ourselves fighting alongside these angelic warriors, fully engaged and fully committed for the Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray Kingdom prayers, Amy, and know that as the spiritual battle continues to rage you are so greatly loved, your own prayers are contributing to the glorious and God-honouring outcome, and so be strong and of good courage! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blinded by seeing </title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/blinded-by-seeing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/blinded-by-seeing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/blinded-by-seeing/matrix-digital-rain.png" alt="Featured image of post Blinded by seeing " /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a mighty prophet of God lose his faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re surely familiar with the glorious story of Elijah on Mount Carmel, where he defeated the prophets of Baal and so was revealed who is the true God (1 Kings 18).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But look what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Jezebel sent a messenger to Elijah, saying, “So may the gods do to me and more also, if I do not make your life as the life of one of them by this time tomorrow.” Then he was afraid, and he arose and ran for his life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notwithstanding Jezebel&amp;rsquo;s threat to kill him, how does “he was afraid” make any sense given what had just happened? In fact it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a fascinating paper about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pivotal term in our text is the Hebrew word &lt;em&gt;wayyarʼ&lt;/em&gt;, the first word in verse three. This common verbal form should be translated “then he saw” (from &lt;em&gt;rāʼâ&lt;/em&gt;). &amp;hellip; Virtually all of the more recent translations of the Bible have opted for another reading, the Hebrew &lt;em&gt;wayyîrāʼ&lt;/em&gt;, “and he was afraid” (from &lt;em&gt;yārēʼ&lt;/em&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against this &amp;hellip; most Hebrew manuscripts read “and he saw”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ronald Barclay Allen, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etsjets.org/files/JETS-PDFs/22/22-3/22-3-pp193-202_JETS.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Elijah the Broken Prophet, Journal of the Evangelical Theological Society 22/3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen goes on to argue how “he saw” is surely what was originally written, and is in fact the only translation which makes any sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then does it mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How had Elijah defeated the Baals? By exercising incredible faith in the infinite power and steadfast faithfulness of the invisible God. The invisible God who cannot be seen is the one who defines reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what did Elijah do next. He saw. He looked at the so-called real world, and the pseudo-reality that he saw defeated him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul writes about the reason for our courage and confidence in the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we walk by faith, not by sight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 5:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking by sight means looking at the visible world around us as all there is, or at least the most part of it. How this defeats us! It defeated Elijah, that mighty prophet of God, who ran for his life and hid in a cave, where he was rebuked by the Lord (albeit with great tenderness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There he came to a cave and lodged in it. And behold, the word of the LORD came to him, and he said to him, “What are you doing here, Elijah?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the love in that rebuke? Read the rest of 1 Kings 19 for further insight into the loving kindness and provision of our Heavenly Father. Elijah had gone off-script. He had momentarily lost his faith, precisely because he saw, and he thought that what he saw was the true reality. It was not, as the Lord showed him with such patience and love and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the infinite power and the steadfast love and faithfulness and the great kindness of the invisible God, Amy, and walk by faith not by sight! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Who am I?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/who-am-i/spencer-tamichi-bjH4uE6iuEo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Who am I?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a vital question that is for any of us. It could take some time to answer! In fact, I have had to revisit it myself in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valiant attempt I know of to grapple with this is by Dietrich Bonhoeffer, a German pastor who was imprisoned in Flossenbürg concentration camp by the Nazis during World War II. He was executed just one month before the end of the war. One month! He wrote the following while incarcerated. Notice that someone we might regard as a giant in the faith did not regard himself like that at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Am I?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They often tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I stepped from my cell&amp;rsquo;s confinement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Calmly, cheerfully, firmly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Like a squire from his country house.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They often tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I used to speak to my warders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Freely and friendly and clearly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As though it were mine to command.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They also tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I bore the days of misfortune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Equably, smilingly, proudly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;like one accustomed to win.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Am I then really that which other men tell of?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Or am I only what I myself know of myself?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Restless and longing and sick, like a bird in a cage,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Struggling for breath, as though hands were compressing my throat,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yearning for colours, for flowers, for the voices of birds,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Thirsting for words of kindness, for neighbourliness,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tossing in expectations of great events,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powerlessly trembling for friends at an infinite distance,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Weary and empty at praying, at thinking, at making,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Faint, and ready to say farewell to it all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? This or the other?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Am I one person today and tomorrow another?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Am I both at once? A hypocrite before others,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And before myself a contemptible woebegone weakling?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Or is something within me still like a beaten army&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fleeing in disorder from victory already achieved?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They mock me, these lonely questions of mine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Whoever I am, Thou knowest, O God, I am thine!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What courageously honest words, from someone facing the ultimate test of faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, while you continue to work out the rest 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
