<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>blessing on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/blessing/</link>
        <description>Recent content in blessing on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/blessing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Expectation in unsolicited blessing</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/expectation-in-unsolicited-blessing/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/expectation-in-unsolicited-blessing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/expectation-in-unsolicited-blessing/mieke-campbell-Q6DmZLEejkE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Expectation in unsolicited blessing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much expectation of blessing can we have in the absence of a specific promise or request?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sure, the Lord does from time to time give very specific promises to specific people for specific situations, and in these we must wait expectantly and with great assurance, resting in what he has promised. But what of the rest of our lives, or those not holding such promises, or those areas of our lives not so covered? What should we expect when nothing in particular has been promised and we haven&amp;rsquo;t even asked for anything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the first thing the Lord did on creating Adam and Eve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So God created man in his own image, in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And God blessed them. And God said to them, “Be fruitful and multiply and fill the earth and subdue it, and have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the heavens and over every living thing that moves on the earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:27-28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? As soon as he had created them and even before instructing them to be fruitful and multiply, the very first thing he did was to bless them. This reveals his very nature. What a good Father he is, so wonderfully generous and kind to his beloved sons and daughters! All his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course we don&amp;rsquo;t know specifically what Adam and Eve&amp;rsquo;s blessing comprised, just as we don&amp;rsquo;t know in our own lives, in the middle of things, when the Lord seems to be doing a work of grace and kindness. What is it that he is doing, exactly, and what should we expect for the continuation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we to think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the world say? Don&amp;rsquo;t count your chickens before they&amp;rsquo;re hatched. Wait until the final reveal before getting too excited. And expect to be disappointed because that&amp;rsquo;s just how life is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How utterly wretched! How utterly miserable! That&amp;rsquo;s not the life to which we are called. That&amp;rsquo;s not the expectation to which we are called. What did Jesus say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And David?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life, and I shall dwell in the house of the LORD forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 23:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in the absence of specific promises and when things are still unfolding around us we must be excited. Our Heavenly Father loves to bless his sons and daughters. We should therefore let our imaginations run wild with all the things the Lord may choose to do in our lives. His imagination is bigger and more wonderful than ours, and his power to bless is without limit. May our own expectation of that lead us into thanks and praise to the one who alone is worthy, the source of all that is good in our lives. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, Amy, whatever your state of expectation of blessing from the Lord, you will surely not be disappointed as you wait on him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The poor in spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-poor-in-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-poor-in-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-poor-in-spirit/jackson-david-2hJZF52UR9k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The poor in spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it that is so remarkable about the blessing for the poor in spirit, the first thing Jesus said in The Sermon on the Mount, almost the very first thing he was recorded as saying publicly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get to what is so remarkable here, let&amp;rsquo;s first unpack what it means to be poor in spirit, because poor in spirit doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound very blessed does it? Psalm 63 will help us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O God, you are my God; earnestly I seek you; my soul thirsts for you; my flesh faints for you, as in a dry and weary land where there is no water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction to the psalm tells us that David wrote this when he was in the wilderness of Judah. The physical thirst experienced in that arid land parallelled the spiritual thirst of his being poor in spirit, being so aware of his need of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t think for a moment that there is any lack of desire for God among the poor in spirit, or any lack of understanding of his goodness and mercy. The truth is the complete opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because your steadfast love is better than life, my lips will praise you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love is better than life itself. There is full understanding here, along with the most desperate longing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So I will bless you as long as I live; in your name I will lift up my hands. My soul will be satisfied as with fat and rich food, and my mouth will praise you with joyful lips, when I remember you upon my bed, and meditate on you in the watches of the night; for you have been my help, and in the shadow of your wings I will sing for joy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:4-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two things we must notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, his life is hard⸺so very hard. There is steadfast determination to praise, to trust, to honour the Lord, right alongside the sleeplessness. That&amp;rsquo;s right. In the watches of the night, in the time for sleeping, sleep does not come. So the psalmist meditates on the Lord, on his goodness and kindness and faithfulness, and so must we.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly, the blessing and satisfaction in the Lord which is so painfully longed for is in the future. It is not yet. My soul will be satisfied. I will sing for joy. There is both trust and determination here. But it is not yet. The joy is to come. And in the meantime?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to you; your right hand upholds me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 63:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are both in the present tense, right here, right now. My Heavenly Father upholds me with his right hand in the longing and the sleeplessness, and my soul clings to him. I am poor in spirit, so very aware of my need for him, and he honours that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we can understand what is so remarkable about the blessing for the poor in spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a present tense blessing, almost uniquely amidst the others (they shall be comforted; they shall inherit the earth; they shall be satisfied; they shall receive mercy; they shall see God; they shall be called sons and daughters of God — Matthew 5:4-9).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theirs is the kingdom of heaven, right now. There is nothing to wait for. There is nothing held back. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are the poor in spirit, Amy, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dwelling in the land</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/dwelling-in-the-land/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/dwelling-in-the-land/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/dwelling-in-the-land/leonard-cotte-c1Jp-fo53U8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dwelling in the land" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever marvel at how the Bible is quite so dense with blessing and encouragement, and that even the most familiar passages can suddenly reveal to us new insight and bestow upon us new grace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example, just half a verse, a mere seven words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dwell in the land and befriend faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the face of it this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be saying very much at all. What does “dwell in the land” even mean? Is it simply saying, live your life? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand this we must understand the Old Testament significance of the land from the very beginning, from the call of Abraham, even before God gave him his new name which means “father of a multitude”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the LORD said to Abram, “Go from your country and your kindred and your father&amp;rsquo;s house to the land that I will show you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To your offspring I will give this land.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 12:1, 7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Be mindful that this promise was spoken to a childless 75 year old man who was married to a barren woman.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More was revealed when God spoke to Moses out of the burning bush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, and I have come down to deliver them out of the hand of the Egyptians and to bring them up out of that land to a good and broad land, a land flowing with milk and honey, to the place of the Canaanites, the Hittites, the Amorites, the Perizzites, the Hivites, and the Jebusites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was “the land” and it was hugely symbolic of the covenant promise of the Lord to Abraham and to his chosen people, the Israelites. To dwell in the land then is to live in the promises of God⸺the promises of the most faithful God to his woefully unfaithful people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And “befriend faithfulness”? The Lord himself is faithfulness personified. We befriend faithfulness by honouring him with our own faithfulness, trusting not doubting his promises to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these promises? Some are common to us all⸺Scripture is full of them! One of the most astonishing is in the very next verse, and we already considered this extravagant promise, seemingly too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD, and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek the Lord with all of your heart, desiring him alone, and he will give himself to you in the richest of relationship. This extraordinary promise is that we can have as much of the Lord in our lives as we desire. Praise his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some promises are uniquely given. Promises that I have received are for me, and different from yours, Amy. We honour him alike by resting in these promises, living in them expectantly, believing not doubting, just as David goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is not uninvolved as we live in his promises. Trust in him and he will act, whatever has been promised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dwell in the land, Amy, and befriend faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
