<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>future on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/future/</link>
        <description>Recent content in future on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/future/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/ishan-seefromthesky-2d7n2sfYjHY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know for sure that all we are hoping for in eternity is real, and that it will be as promised?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m just about ready to leave this desert island, and I see a boat on the horizon (yay!), but first let&amp;rsquo;s look into Ephesians 1 for one last time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession — to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some really significant points to note here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we in or out? We have been &lt;em&gt;included&lt;/em&gt;. Most assuredly in! And not on our own merit, as if anyone could come along later and say, there&amp;rsquo;s been some mistake. No, we have been included &lt;em&gt;in Christ&lt;/em&gt;. The power and the glory are his, and we are included, in him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have been &lt;em&gt;marked in him with a seal&lt;/em&gt;. When a legal contract used to be signed, both parties would sign and apply a wax seal with the impression of a signet ring, as authentication. The Holy Spirit authenticates us as children of God, the genuine article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Holy Spirit is a &lt;em&gt;deposit&lt;/em&gt;, that is part of the greater whole which is to follow, paid immediately, as a foretaste. There is more to come!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The deposit is a &lt;em&gt;guarantee&lt;/em&gt; of what is to come. What is to come is a certainty, and cannot be revoked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is guaranteed is &lt;em&gt;our inheritance&lt;/em&gt;. If we are children, then we are heirs — heirs of God and co-heirs with Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are &lt;em&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s possession&lt;/em&gt;, bought with a price, and he will never give us up. I am his and he is mine, forever. You too, Amy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prize is our &lt;em&gt;redemption&lt;/em&gt;, which is already accomplished, but not yet complete. One day it will be so, and we will shed off all that tires us out and drags us down. How I long for that day!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Spirit living in us not only proves our adoption by the Lord, but gives us power to live victoriously, a foretaste of what is certain, of what is promised and true. A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance! Now we can truly say this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Praise be to the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praise him, Amy, for such blessing as this! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
