<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>protection on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/protection/</link>
        <description>Recent content in protection on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 06:23:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/protection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>He is with you</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/he-is-with-you/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/he-is-with-you/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/he-is-with-you/jed-owen-dKXVO9EOPT8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post He is with you" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What three or four words comprise the heart of Psalm 23?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having started reflecting on this psalm last week, I&amp;rsquo;m not quite ready to move on. So, where is its heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He restores my soul (v3)? Yes indeed, this is the wonderful truth we considered, but not I think the heart of the psalm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cup overflows (v5)? Oh to know the ongoing reality of that, as the Lord rains down his blessing upon us, unceasingly! That blessing is consequential though, not causal — the wonderful result of something, but not it&amp;rsquo;s source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is my shepherd (v1)? Oops that&amp;rsquo;s five words, but we are now homing in on the source of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s this: &lt;em&gt;You are with me&lt;/em&gt; (v4). That&amp;rsquo;s the heart of the psalm, the reason behind everything else. The rest of the psalm unpacks this truth, revealing who is the one who is with me, the Lord, my shepherd, and what he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider the rest of that verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil, for you are with me; your rod and your staff, they comfort me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 23:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in that valley. It was a lonely, desperate place to walk, for the longest time, and I hope never to return. But it was the place where I died to self, and that was only possible because the Lord was with me. Sometimes the Lord has things to teach us that can only be received in the darkest places. And my testimony is, he was with me then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His rod and his staff comfort me. There is both discipline and protection here, guiding me in paths of righteousness even when I am inclined to wander, and guarding me on those paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is. He is with you, Amy. Fear no evil, there is no need. Consider who is this one who is with you. He prepares a table before you in the presence of your enemies. They are nothing to him. He invites you to sit and eat in his presence, and as he pours out his blessing into your cup, it overflows, cascading everywhere, and still he pours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear no evil, Amy, the Lord of all creation is with you, and you will dwell in his house forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Integrity and uprightness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/integrity-and-uprightness/chris-brignola-X2CxUXFqKcM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Integrity and uprightness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can goodness protect us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; goodness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greek word is &lt;em&gt;agathōsunē&lt;/em&gt;, which can be translated &lt;em&gt;uprightness of heart and life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look briefly again into Psalm 25 (what a jewel of a psalm that is!), where David writes with such humility, so aware of his own shortcomings and his desire to live a life of integrity, honouring the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect me, because my hope is in you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see protection there, but how does that work? Before we get to that, read the whole psalm and notice that there is not a shred of smug self-satisfaction as David seeks with all his heart to honour the Lord and live a right life. Paul also writes of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must seek with our whole heart to live as slaves to righteousness, purging every wrong thought and deed, pouring ourselves out in humility and gratitude to the Lord. The Holy Spirit enables us to do this. It is a miracle of grace that sinners such as we are, even forgiven sinners, can live with such integrity and uprightness, evidence in our own lives of the victory Jesus won on the cross. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we live with humility as slaves to righteousness, continuing to be sanctified by the Holy Spirit, integrity and uprightness keep us on the narrow path that leads to life, and it is this that protects us. The process is ongoing, and so is the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect you, Amy, as you live as a slave to righteousness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
