<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>peace on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/peace/</link>
        <description>Recent content in peace on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/peace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The shoes of the gospel of peace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/ben-weber-8W-p8SS6NJE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shoes of the gospel of peace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come to what Paul says about feet, I have been contemplating, what is it that feet do? Well clearly they go, and they dance. Since you&amp;rsquo;re already acing both of these, I had to wonder whether I had anything at all for you this week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God &amp;hellip; with your feet fitted with the readiness that comes from the gospel of peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:13, 15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two thoughts, however, that I have had. May they encourage your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the armour of God is all about being prepared for battle. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t the gospel of peace seem to be somewhat at odds with that? I was prompted to reread Lieutenant Colonel Tim Collins&amp;rsquo; rousing eve-of-battle speech in the Iraq War. It is not long, but too much to include here in its entirety — I encourage you to look it up. I was struck by the juxtaposition of ferocity and compassion, of the warrior on a mission of mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We go to liberate, not to conquer. We will not fly our flags in their country. We are entering Iraq to free a people and the only flag which will be flown in that ancient land is their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Show respect for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you are ferocious in battle remember to be magnanimous in victory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lieutenant Colonel Tim Collins, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.royal-irish.com/stories/lieutenant-colonel-tim-collins-eve-of-battle-speech&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Fort Blair Mayne, Kuwait, 19 March 2003&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who seem to be our adversaries in this world are really not. We are bringers of the gospel of peace, and we go to liberate. May compassion define us in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, our feet must be fitted with &lt;em&gt;readiness&lt;/em&gt;. Who can say when the Lord will choose to act with power and mercy by his Spirit in the lives of those around us? Let us anticipate that he will, and be ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God, Amy, and fit your dancing, going feet with the readiness that comes from the gospel of peace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>He is with you</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/he-is-with-you/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 06:23:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/he-is-with-you/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/he-is-with-you/jed-owen-dKXVO9EOPT8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post He is with you" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What three or four words comprise the heart of Psalm 23?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having started reflecting on this psalm last week, I&amp;rsquo;m not quite ready to move on. So, where is its heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He restores my soul (v3)? Yes indeed, this is the wonderful truth we considered, but not I think the heart of the psalm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cup overflows (v5)? Oh to know the ongoing reality of that, as the Lord rains down his blessing upon us, unceasingly! That blessing is consequential though, not causal — the wonderful result of something, but not it&amp;rsquo;s source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is my shepherd (v1)? Oops that&amp;rsquo;s five words, but we are now homing in on the source of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s this: &lt;em&gt;You are with me&lt;/em&gt; (v4). That&amp;rsquo;s the heart of the psalm, the reason behind everything else. The rest of the psalm unpacks this truth, revealing who is the one who is with me, the Lord, my shepherd, and what he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider the rest of that verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil, for you are with me; your rod and your staff, they comfort me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 23:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in that valley. It was a lonely, desperate place to walk, for the longest time, and I hope never to return. But it was the place where I died to self, and that was only possible because the Lord was with me. Sometimes the Lord has things to teach us that can only be received in the darkest places. And my testimony is, he was with me then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His rod and his staff comfort me. There is both discipline and protection here, guiding me in paths of righteousness even when I am inclined to wander, and guarding me on those paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is. He is with you, Amy. Fear no evil, there is no need. Consider who is this one who is with you. He prepares a table before you in the presence of your enemies. They are nothing to him. He invites you to sit and eat in his presence, and as he pours out his blessing into your cup, it overflows, cascading everywhere, and still he pours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear no evil, Amy, the Lord of all creation is with you, and you will dwell in his house forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Tranquility in the soul</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/capturing-the-human-heart-i9uIhSlOWYc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Tranquility in the soul" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know real peace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; peace&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peace here is the Greek word &lt;em&gt;eirene&lt;/em&gt;, which corresponds to the Hebrew word shalom, and could be translated as &lt;em&gt;tranquility in the soul&lt;/em&gt;. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want such a thing? But how can we possibly know such a peace in the turbulent and warmongering world in which we live?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 46 provides insight, and is worth reading in its entirety. The world it describes doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem so very different from our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mountains fall into the heart of the sea,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nations are in uproar, kingdoms fall;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 46:2, 6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an apparently chaotic and tempestuous world this is.  And yet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He lifts his voice, the earth melts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a voice that is! Tranquility in the soul is rooted in the absolute surety that the Lord is sovereign, infinite in power, so very good, and that he loves us beyond imagining. Only so can we rest in him, completely and comprehensively, and have this peace that defies circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He breaks the bow and shatters the spear;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be still, and know that I am God; I will be exalted among the nations, I will be exalted in the earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v9, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem that the world is out of control, but this is illusory and temporary.  Ultimately, God will be exalted in all the earth. In such times as these, we must be still, and in the stillness we can know this, with certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be still, and know that he is God, Amy, and grow in tranquility in the soul! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Covid prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/covid-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/covid-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/covid-prayer/yannis-h-zpSXcUpmhNc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Covid prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear God, my God,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the Lord of all creation, majestic, sovereign, good, and wise beyond our understanding. Praise your holy name! I lift up to you the situation in Amy&amp;rsquo;s village, with Covid having arrived, and along with it, fear. Forgive us when we doubt your goodness or your sovereignty. I pray the people there would hear Jesus speaking, &amp;ldquo;Peace I leave with you; my peace I give you. I do not give to you as the world gives. Do not let your hearts be troubled and do not be afraid.&amp;rdquo; (John 14:27). Please keep Amy safe and well, and may she be a beacon of hope for those who may be losing theirs, pointing to Jesus and trusting him.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cc: Amy, with love&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Peace and provision</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/peace-and-provision/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:21:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/peace-and-provision/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/peace-and-provision/raimond-klavins-DDwOFA_9LiY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Peace and provision" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;May you know peace from the Lord, and his provision for you, Amy, as you wait on him, and especially when things don&amp;rsquo;t turn out as you expected or hoped. Know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans prevail, and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
