<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>compassion on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/compassion/</link>
        <description>Recent content in compassion on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/compassion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Act justly</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/act-justly/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/act-justly/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/act-justly/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Act justly" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s not to like about justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has told you, O man, what is good; and what does the LORD require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/micah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Micah 6:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But justice can be harsh, and justice as enforced by the privileged and powerful sometimes especially so. Perhaps the very worst aspect of justice is some entitled one insisting on asserting their own rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s heart in this justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The opening of the prison to those who are bound could also be translated &lt;em&gt;the opening of the eyes to those who are blind&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a justice which rescues and protects and defends and cares for the most vulnerable. It is a justice overflowing with compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how it continues. The outcast and the alien are welcomed and invited in and integrated. They receive blessing and protection from the Lord as ministered by his people. And his people in return are richly blessed as these vulnerable ones who are raised up and made whole become themselves the source of blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Strangers shall stand and tend your flocks; foreigners shall be your plowmen and vinedressers; but you shall be called the priests of the LORD; they shall speak of you as the ministers of our God; you shall eat the wealth of the nations, and in their glory you shall boast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s own people shall boast in the glory of these broken and vulnerable ones raised up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why does the Lord set his love upon these who were not his people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; that they may be called oaks of righteousness, the planting of the LORD, that he may be glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such justice born from compassion brings glory to the Lord, that he may display his beauty. May the name of the Lord be praised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I the LORD love justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the justice of which Micah speaks⸺justice as an outworking of compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is the source of the compassion that enables us to do such justice? It is found in the justice that the Lord has done for us⸺the justice that surprises and rescues and will not be thwarted by our own sin and wretchedness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have considered this before. Christ died for our sins, paying the debt in full. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s justice demands that we be forgiven. He will not take a second payment. We cannot keep such compassion to ourselves! It rises up and overflows and stokes the justice that we do⸺the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own justice. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the Lord&amp;rsquo;s justice with compassion, Amy, and bring glory to his name! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Be holy, for I am holy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/be-holy-for-i-am-holy/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/be-holy-for-i-am-holy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/be-holy-for-i-am-holy/linda-christiansen-cybTg_gYWkw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Be holy, for I am holy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the point of Leviticus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished compiling a Scripture index of everything I&amp;rsquo;ve written to you over the last two years or so. It was really quite interesting to me! I see that I have managed to make reference to 44 out of the 66 books of the Bible, which got me thinking about those I&amp;rsquo;ve so far omitted. Why do I think this matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Timothy 3:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “man of God” is a common Old Testament expression, which can refer to male or female, and indeed the NIV translates this as servant of God. It simply means us, you or me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, all Scripture? Including Leviticus? For us?! How could that possibly be relevant for Christians living in a post-resurrection world? Let&amp;rsquo;s see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am the LORD your God. Consecrate yourselves therefore, and be holy, for I am holy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/leviticus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 11:44&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostle Peter endorses its relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As obedient children, do not be conformed to the passions of your former ignorance, but as he who called you is holy, you also be holy in all your conduct, since it is written, “You shall be holy, for I am holy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:14-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My study Bible summarises it like this: the book of Leviticus is concerned with what it means to be the holy people of a holy God. And what could be more relevant for us than that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gain insight from Leviticus into things we might otherwise overlook. What can we learn from the myriad of seemingly picky little laws that we would instinctively brush aside and not think about? Such things were clearly of great importance to the Lord. Ought we not at least to ponder why that was? These are not unrelated to those matters upon which Jesus expounded in the Sermon on the Mount, and Paul also has long lists over which we must take great care. The Lord is apparently greatly concerned about things we may be inclined to brush aside as “details”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to understand the sacrificial system of the Old Testament we must study Leviticus, and by this we can start to understand Jesus&amp;rsquo; own sacrifice on the cross. Why did it have to be quite so bloody? And why did he have to die such a death? Leviticus teaches us such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the life of the flesh is in the blood, and I have given it for you on the altar to make atonement for your souls, for it is the blood that makes atonement by the life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/leviticus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 17:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also much we can learn of God&amp;rsquo;s own heart from reading Leviticus, such that as we grow in this knowledge we can more fully honour him. For example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“When you reap the harvest of your land, you shall not reap your field right up to its edge, neither shall you gather the gleanings after your harvest. And you shall not strip your vineyard bare, neither shall you gather the fallen grapes of your vineyard. You shall leave them for the poor and for the sojourner: I am the LORD your God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/leviticus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 19:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What compassion there is to be found here, what concern for the poor and for the alien. The God who gave this commandment is our God, who does not change. It turns out that the book of Leviticus is a veritable treasure trove!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look into it, unpacking these treasures, let us not forget the headline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be holy, Amy, because he is holy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Emptiness and exhaustion</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/emptiness-and-exhaustion/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/emptiness-and-exhaustion/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/emptiness-and-exhaustion/brut-carniollus-jGEsapFCLgw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Emptiness and exhaustion" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else can we learn from Elijah&amp;rsquo;s faith-wobble?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was running for his life, and after 120 miles or so he left his servant and continued alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But he himself went a day&amp;rsquo;s journey into the wilderness and came and sat down under a broom tree. And he asked that he might die, saying, “It is enough; now, O LORD, take away my life, for I am no better than my fathers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was a man empty and exhausted, utterly cast down, apparently at his end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he lay down and slept under a broom tree. And behold, an angel touched him and said to him, “Arise and eat.” And he looked, and behold, there was at his head a cake baked on hot stones and a jar of water. And he ate and drank and lay down again. And the angel of the LORD came again a second time and touched him and said, “Arise and eat, for the journey is too great for you.” And he arose and ate and drank, and went in the strength of that food forty days and forty nights to Horeb, the mount of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey to Horeb was at least another 250 miles. What a cake that must have been!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice what was the Lord&amp;rsquo;s first response⸺not that gentle rebuke which was to follow. The first response was practical and compassionate care and provision for his servant who was empty and utterly exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what? Elijah poured out his heart to the Lord, and you can be sure the tears were streaming down his face. Read for yourself the words of a broken man with nothing left to give, without hope and apparently all alone (1 Kings 19:10, 14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was the Lord&amp;rsquo;s response to that? He rescued him and restored him and gave him something to do (1 Kings 19:15-18). Let me paraphrase it like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It&amp;rsquo;s ok, Elijah, I&amp;rsquo;ve got this. And by the way, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. I have seven thousand others. And you are still useful to me. Come on, let&amp;rsquo;s go again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus the Lord restored Elijah, gave him hope, and continued to work out his plans and purposes through him and through Elisha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So he departed from there and found Elisha the son of Shaphat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then [Elisha] arose and went after Elijah and assisted him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:19, 21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same God who looks with such love on each one of us in our own brokenness and emptiness and exhaustion, and rescues and restores, and continues to use us for his Kingdom plans and purposes. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His grace is sufficient for you, Amy, for his power is made perfect in your weakness! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The God of all comfort</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-god-of-all-comfort/helena-lopes-ikOKjyLZRno-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The God of all comfort" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the nature of the comfort we can receive from God, and how can we receive it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life can be so hard. We need this comfort. So we need to understand just what it is, and how it works. Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise be to the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of compassion and the God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our troubles, so that we can comfort those in any trouble with the comfort we ourselves have received from God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gained some insight into this recently, quite indirectly and unexpectedly. Just as I was arriving back home from a run, I bumped into a friend, a professor of theology with whom I have had some interesting and uplifting conversations over the years. I remarked that I had been struck by the incredible grace and kindness of the Lord. He then asked an interesting question: “Did something particularly good just happen?” to which the answer was no, not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I reflected on this later, it made me a little sad. So often, the grace of God is understood as being received through our circumstances, equated with something good and pleasant happening to us. How impoverished can be our understanding of grace! The grace of God is a powerful, tangible thing, which can be received and experienced in its own right, independently of any change in circumstance. And invisible to others, save perhaps for some glow about us as we receive it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with comfort. If we read around those verses we see the context of the comfort is severe hardship, hardly pleasant circumstances. In particular, note this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For just as the sufferings of Christ flow over into our lives, so also through Christ our comfort overflows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering and comfort here are hand-in-hand. This comfort from God is not received through observable, physical happenings. It is received directly. It is wonderful, powerful, and oh so tangible, a gift from the Father of compassion himself. A heavenly hug, so to speak, from the one who loves us beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever is happening, Amy, receive comfort directly from the God of all comfort, the Father of compassion, the one who loves you beyond imagining! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An axe-head floats</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/hendrik-cornelissen-x59BNivBcQ8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post An axe-head floats" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can a floating axe-head provide insight into the Father-heart of God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Elisha and his servants and the company of the prophets] went to the Jordan and began to cut down trees [to build a place for them to live]. As one of them was cutting down a tree, the iron axe-head fell into the water. “Oh, my lord,” he cried out, “it was borrowed!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man of God asked, “Where did it fall?” When he showed him the place, Elisha cut a stick and threw it there, and made the iron float. “Lift it out,” he said. Then the man reached out his hand and took it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Kings 6:4-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a curious little account. How are we to understand it? Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s note just what a man of God Elisha was. When Elijah was handing down to him the mantle of being the Lord&amp;rsquo;s prophet, Elisha asked to inherit a double portion of his spirit. (How cheeky was that? — 2 Kings 2:1-15) He certainly received it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the axe-head then. Losing an axe-head would have been no small matter⸺there was certainly no Mitre 10 Mega to provide a replacement. And consider the shame of losing borrowed equipment, especially something so valuable. But still, surely a trivial thing in the light of eternity? Why would the Lord even care? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t he be more concerned with the learning and growth opportunity afforded by suffering such a loss? Isn&amp;rsquo;t this life supposed to be about learning to suffer and submit to such? How easily we could fail to understand the Father-heart of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we actually see revealed here then? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. A lavish, gratuitously kind and compassionate miraculous response to a material loss. Yes, the man had been careless, and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have let this happen. But it did, and the Lord stepped in with no rebuke, demonstrating through his servant Elisha such affection and concern for one he loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with us. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s kindness and compassion for us is rooted in the reality of our situation. How ready he is to step in and rescue! He understands us, he understands our need, and his response is love and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run to your Heavenly Father, Amy, with any and all of your needs, because he cares for you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
