<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>spiritual warfare on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/spiritual-warfare/</link>
        <description>Recent content in spiritual warfare on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/spiritual-warfare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The belt of truth</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/Roman_cingulum_1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The belt of truth" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for last week&amp;rsquo;s email — what a lot has been going on! I hope by now you&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying your well-deserved break, and that the Lord is doing a work of refreshing and refilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your email you referred to the armour of God, which has prompted me to spend some time reflecting on that. You know how I love to unpack these things! I&amp;rsquo;ll start with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand firm then, with the belt of truth buckled round your waist &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How vital is truth. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to some specifics, but firstly, have you wondered why Paul represents truth as a belt? Why a belt?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found when I looked into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cingulum was the traditional Roman soldier&amp;rsquo;s belt, which only soldiers were allowed to wear, and which they wore even when off duty. The leather straps (baltea) dangling from the front of the belt with their decorative studs (bullae) were the only insignia on their uniform. The belt was about &lt;em&gt;identity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the belt of truth. It is our fundamental identity in Christ, upon which everything else hangs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Christian&amp;rsquo;s identity is in truth — truth in who we are and truth in our status before God, sinners saved by grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no difference &amp;hellip; for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and all are justified freely by his grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22b-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spiritual battle, when Satan accuses and we are tempted to despair of who we are, we must hold onto this truth: our heavenly Father already knows the very worst about us, yet still he loves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God demonstrates his own love for us in this: While we were still sinners, Christ died for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our identity, and our identity is in Christ. Only by holding onto this are we able to stand firm in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he or she is a new creation; the old has gone, the new has come!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand firm in this truth, Amy, which is your identity in Christ! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unmasking the true villain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/adnan-khan-VS2C5_GI_MM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unmasking the true villain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this life like Scooby-Doo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Scooby-Doo episode I can remember ends in the same way. The mystery villain is finally unmasked by the gang and is seen to be a familiar character, who then says, “And I would have gotten away with it too, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for you meddling kids!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul tells a similar tale in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an important lesson there is here. How often life can seem so adversarial, with obstacles being put in our way by people who are frankly, just so annoying! Aargh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If instead we can step back and regain perspective, discerning who is the real enemy and recognising that we are in the middle of a spiritual battle in the heavenly realms, the Holy Spirit will be able to equip us with everything we need to face this. That is the only way to prevail in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of hostility, for example, may we respond with gentleness and kindness towards the one who is not our enemy. Hearts are healed like this, the Lord is glorified and the devil thwarted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this asking too much though? How could we possibly live like this? Paul tells us how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, be strong in the Lord and in his mighty power. Put on the full armour of God, so that you can take your stand against the devil&amp;rsquo;s schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s clearly a bit to be said about the armour of God. For now, though, be a meddling kid and unmask the true villain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your struggle is not against flesh and blood, Amy, so put on the full armour of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
