<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>spiritual warfare on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/spiritual-warfare/</link>
        <description>Recent content in spiritual warfare on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/spiritual-warfare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The spiritual battle</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-spiritual-battle/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-spiritual-battle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-spiritual-battle/cade-roberts-EpIUbeFrqwQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The spiritual battle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that our most holy and righteous prayers, those prayed for God&amp;rsquo;s glory and the advancement of the Kingdom, are not answered immediately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know we can pray in Jesus&amp;rsquo; name as he wonderfully lays upon our hearts those things which are on his own heart. There is much joy in such praying and there is intimacy in relationship with Jesus as our own most earnest desires become aligned with his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why then the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to know that there is a spiritual battle raging, for there is indeed a spiritual battle and we are right in the middle of it and never more so than when we pray such Kingdom prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exiled in Babylon, Daniel experienced this in his own time of crying out to the Lord and waiting on him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In those days I, Daniel, was mourning for three weeks. I ate no delicacies, no meat or wine entered my mouth, nor did I anoint myself at all, for the full three weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seventy long years had passed since Daniel had been taken into exile in his youth and he was now an old man. Throughout this time he had lived a life pleasing to the Lord. Consider for a moment: that earnest young man carried off into Babylon all those years previously, who with his three friends set their course with such boldness and determination to honour the Lord and live for him alone. Here he was now as an old man, no less dedicated and no less determined. Praise the Lord for Daniel and others like him, for the consistency of such lives lived for the Lord through so many years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so here he was, praying most earnestly about matters central to the Kingdom, matters on God&amp;rsquo;s own heart, and in the praying there was mourning and waiting. But surely even Daniel wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I lifted up my eyes and looked, and behold, a man clothed in linen, with a belt of fine gold from Uphaz around his waist. His body was like beryl, his face like the appearance of lightning, his eyes like flaming torches, his arms and legs like the gleam of burnished bronze, and the sound of his words like the sound of a multitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was no mere angelic messenger. Here stood an angelic warrior, come to strengthen Daniel and give him the courage he would need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he said to me, “Fear not, Daniel, for from the first day that you set your heart to understand and humbled yourself before your God, your words have been heard, and I have come because of your words. The prince of the kingdom of Persia withstood me twenty-one days, but Michael, one of the chief princes, came to help me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly notice the affirmation of a life lived before the Lord⸺Daniel&amp;rsquo;s whole-hearted devotion to the Lord through all these years had not gone unnoticed. His prayers had not gone unheeded, and the angelic warrior was standing before him precisely because of those prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spiritual battle had been raging and it was not over, but Daniel&amp;rsquo;s praying mattered so greatly to the commander of the army of the Lord that he had momentarily spared an angelic warrior from the battle to strengthen and encourage Daniel, his loyal and faithful prayer warrior, equally engaged in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said, “O man greatly loved, fear not, peace be with you; be strong and of good courage.” And as he spoke to me, I was strengthened and said, “Let my lord speak, for you have strengthened me.” Then he said, “Do you know why I have come to you? But now I will return to fight against the prince of Persia; and when I go out, behold, the prince of Greece will come. But I will tell you what is inscribed in the book of truth: there is none who contends by my side against these except Michael, your prince.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/daniel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Daniel 10:19-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spiritual battle continued to rage and the angelic warrior could not stay. He had taken time out to come to Daniel to strengthen and encourage him for what lay ahead, and furthermore to remind him that he was a man greatly loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spiritual battle continues to rage today. We must engage faithfully in prayer, knowing full well that answering our own most earnest and Kingdom-centric prayers is no small or easy matter. May our own prayers be so aligned with the plans and purposes of the commander of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s army in this spiritual battle that we find ourselves fighting alongside these angelic warriors, fully engaged and fully committed for the Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray Kingdom prayers, Amy, and know that as the spiritual battle continues to rage you are so greatly loved, your own prayers are contributing to the glorious and God-honouring outcome, and so be strong and of good courage! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Pray in the Spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/manuel-meurisse-EuCll-F5atI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Pray in the Spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the last piece of the armour of God that is so often overlooked, indeed not even thought of as armour by many?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the Bible is about reading in paragraphs, which are the basic units of expression, things that belong together. Not every Bible translation has the same paragraph breaks, but in both of my preferred translations⸺the NIV 1984 and the ESV⸺the armour of God is described in just one paragraph, which in the NIV ends with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And pray in the Spirit on all occasions with all kinds of prayers and requests. With this in mind, be alert and always keep on praying for all the saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How interesting that Paul would conclude his writing about the armour of God with this. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider how praying in the Spirit could be considered a vital piece of the armour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what does “in the Spirit” even mean? There seems to be much confusion today about what is the work of the Holy Spirit. Jim Packer wrote a whole book about it, &lt;em&gt;Keep in Step with the Spirit&lt;/em&gt;, in which he outlines some of the secondary aspects that seem to occupy most people&amp;rsquo;s attention, including power, revelation, and promptings, before arguing that &lt;em&gt;the primary work of the Holy Spirit is to mediate the presence of Jesus in our lives&lt;/em&gt;. And indeed, this matches with what Jesus says of the Spirit in John 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Paul writes in Romans is closely related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the same way, the Spirit helps us in our weakness. We do not know what we ought to pray for, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groans that words cannot express.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not overthink this. Praying in the Spirit is simply praying in relationship with Jesus. There is no formula, just as there is no formula in human relationship. Mutual commitment and time spent together are required for the relationship to flourish. Jesus is committed! How he is that!! Are we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must do this on all occasions, and with all kinds of prayers and requests. Let&amp;rsquo;s not get into a rut of formulaic praying. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with our wonderful Saviour and enjoy intimacy in relationship. In his presence we are protected in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice too that Paul&amp;rsquo;s instruction is to pray for all the saints, that is, all Christians. In the spiritual battle we must avoid at all cost turning in on ourselves, as if we are the ones who matter most. By no means! Our brothers and sisters in Christ are the ones we must love, and continue to lift up before the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray in the Spirit on all occasions with all kinds of prayers and requests, Amy, for all the saints! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The sword of the Spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-sword-of-the-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-sword-of-the-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-sword-of-the-spirit/totte-annerbrink-7PRi1chCnrs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The sword of the Spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the two complementary ways to become an expert swordswoman?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take &amp;hellip; the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first, Sunday school teachers have known since forever the value of memory verses for the spiritual battle. Jesus himself refuted Satan with such when tempted in the wilderness at the beginning of his ministry (Luke 4:1-13).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Man does not live on bread alone.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 8:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Worship the Lord your God and serve him only.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 6:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Do not put the Lord your God to the test.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is enormous power in such verses in the midst of the spiritual battle. Build up your arsenal, Amy, commit them to memory, and make them your own. Here&amp;rsquo;s just one of mine that I lean on when tempted to doubt and despair in the waiting time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You know with all your heart and soul that not one of all the good promises the LORD your God gave you has failed. Every promise has been fulfilled; not one has failed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But such verses are not enough. For the second then, we need understanding of the full breadth and depth of Scripture. We won&amp;rsquo;t get this from isolated verses. We get it from extensive reading and studying of the Bible. This is the only way to handle the word of God with integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest help I have found in this intimidating task is a book I bought while at university, shortly after becoming a Christian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because the Bible is God&amp;rsquo;s Word, it has &lt;em&gt;eternal relevance&lt;/em&gt;; it speaks to all mankind, in every age and in every culture. Because it is God&amp;rsquo;s Word, we must listen⸺and obey. But because God chose to speak His Word through &lt;em&gt;human words in history&lt;/em&gt;, every book in the Bible also has &lt;em&gt;historical particularity&lt;/em&gt;; each document is conditioned by the language, time, and culture in which it was originally written (and in some cases also by the oral history it had before it was written down). Interpretation of the Bible is demanded by the “tension” that exists between its &lt;em&gt;eternal relevance&lt;/em&gt; and its &lt;em&gt;historical particularity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A text cannot mean what it never meant&lt;/em&gt;. Or to put that in a positive way, the true meaning of the biblical text for us is what God originally intended it to mean when it was first spoken. This is the starting point. How we work it out from that point is what this book is basically all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gordon D. Fee &amp;amp; Douglas Stuart, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;How to Read the Bible for All Its Worth, Chapter 1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the Bible in its entirety is surely the journey of a lifetime, but may it never become a dry and dusty chore, nor one that leads to intellectual vanity. Let us engage in this task with all of our mind and a surrendered will, joyfully anticipating new depths of insight into the Father&amp;rsquo;s holiness, majesty, love and faithfulness, and into the magnitude of our rescue by our wonderful Saviour. A right response to our increasing knowledge and understanding will be holy reverence, awe and wonder, gratitude, and adoration and worship of our Lord and Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immerse yourself joyfully in the written word of God, Amy, and learn to wield the sword of the Spirit with integrity and understanding! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The helmet of salvation</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-helmet-of-salvation/Cypraecassis_rufaGlobal.png" alt="Featured image of post The helmet of salvation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the helmet of salvation a misnomer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the helmet of salvation &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:13, 17a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What actually is this helmet of salvation that Paul tells us to put on? It can&amp;rsquo;t be salvation per se, as that is a gift of and from the Lord, received through faith. What is it then that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; should put on, and continue to put on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is found in a similar exhortation Paul writes to the Thessalonians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But since we belong to the day, let us be self-controlled, putting on faith and love as a breastplate, and the hope of salvation as a helmet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s all about &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt;⸺the hope of salvation. Recall what hope is. It&amp;rsquo;s not some finger-crossing wishful thinking. By no means! It is grounds for believing that something good will happen, with certainty. And in this case that is something overwhelmingly wonderfully bountifully joyously good, something worth truly waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the case of salvation, what is there still to hope for? Don&amp;rsquo;t we already have it? The simple truth is this: our salvation is already accomplished, but not yet complete. One day it will be so and the battle will be over. That is a certainty, and until then this hope is stored up for us in heaven (Colossians 1:5-6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, the process by which we receive this salvation is ongoing and joyous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Though you have not seen [Jesus], you love him; and even though you do not see him now, you believe in him and are filled with an inexpressible and glorious joy, for you are receiving the goal of your faith, the salvation of your souls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the present continuous tense here. We &lt;em&gt;are receiving&lt;/em&gt; the goal of our faith, which is our salvation. The process is ongoing and will last for all of our earthly lives, but it will eventually come to an end, as recounted in John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the end of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I heard a loud voice in heaven say: “Now have come the salvation and the power and the kingdom of our God, and the authority of his Christ. For the accuser of our brothers and sisters, who accuses them before our God day and night, has been hurled down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 12:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anticipate that day with great joy, Amy, and in the meantime, put on and continue to put on the hope of salvation as a helmet! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The shield of faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shield-of-faith/Cap-s_Shield.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shield of faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have so many Christians thrown away the shield of faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In addition to all this, take up the shield of faith, with which you can extinguish all the flaming arrows of the evil one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, understand the nature of these flaming arrows. They are lies. Lies about us and lies about the Lord and what he has done. Jesus says of the devil,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“When he lies, he speaks his native language, for he is a liar and the father of lies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:44b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lies can be insidious. They must be stamped out before they take hold, like flames licking around. What do these lies do? They create doubt. And how do we combat doubt? By exercising and building faith! But how do we do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is faith anyway? Those who think it is an intellectual acceptance of some revealed truth are so far away from real understanding. Faith is a &lt;em&gt;life lived&lt;/em&gt; upon the foundation of this truth from the Lord, upon Christ himself, fully committed, trusting and even depending on him to keep his promises. (And he will.) So, how to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is again the key. I have to ask myself with brutal honesty, does my life reflect that I will one day stand before the Lord and give an account? Does my life reflect that I have understood Jesus teaching and am living by it in full obedience to him, joyously surrendered? Many seem not to understand this and then wonder why their faith is so small and why doubt is creeping in. Half-hearted belief is no belief at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider even this one thing that Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But many who are first will be last, and many who are last will be first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context of this is the rich young ruler, earnestly seeking but tragically unable to give up this life&amp;rsquo;s riches and pleasures for the Kingdom, just like so many today. Why is it that even within the church so many are trying to be first? Do we really not believe Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given to you as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may need some help with this. So let us ask our Heavenly Father, who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open my eyes that I may see wonderful things in your law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May this be our most earnest prayer as we learn to wield the shield of faith and extinguish those flaming arrows. And let us observe the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in our lives as we live this life of faith, recognising that his faithfulness is in fact the ultimate faith builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take up your shield of faith, Amy, and know that he who promised is faithful! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The shoes of the gospel of peace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/ben-weber-8W-p8SS6NJE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shoes of the gospel of peace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come to what Paul says about feet, I have been contemplating, what is it that feet do? Well clearly they go, and they dance. Since you&amp;rsquo;re already acing both of these, I had to wonder whether I had anything at all for you this week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God &amp;hellip; with your feet fitted with the readiness that comes from the gospel of peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:13, 15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two thoughts, however, that I have had. May they encourage your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the armour of God is all about being prepared for battle. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t the gospel of peace seem to be somewhat at odds with that? I was prompted to reread Lieutenant Colonel Tim Collins&amp;rsquo; rousing eve-of-battle speech in the Iraq War. It is not long, but too much to include here in its entirety⸺I encourage you to look it up. I was struck by the juxtaposition of ferocity and compassion, of the warrior on a mission of mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We go to liberate, not to conquer. We will not fly our flags in their country. We are entering Iraq to free a people and the only flag which will be flown in that ancient land is their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Show respect for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you are ferocious in battle remember to be magnanimous in victory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lieutenant Colonel Tim Collins, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.royal-irish.com/stories/lieutenant-colonel-tim-collins-eve-of-battle-speech&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Fort Blair Mayne, Kuwait, 19 March 2003&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who seem to be our adversaries in this world are really not. We are bringers of the gospel of peace, and we go to liberate. May compassion define us in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, our feet must be fitted with &lt;em&gt;readiness&lt;/em&gt;. Who can say when the Lord will choose to act with power and mercy by his Spirit in the lives of those around us? Let us anticipate that he will, and be ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God, Amy, and fit your dancing, going feet with the readiness that comes from the gospel of peace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The breastplate of righteousness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 07:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-breastplate-of-righteousness/Lorica_segmentata.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The breastplate of righteousness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the breastplate of righteousness, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand firm then &amp;hellip; with the breastplate of righteousness in place &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the function of the breastplate is to protect the torso, the heart and lungs, those vital organs without which we cannot live. But what is the nature of this righteousness without which we cannot live before the Lord? It is interesting to see how writers disagree about this, because there are two possible answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the gospel a righteousness from God is revealed, a righteousness that is by faith from first to last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first view is that the breastplate is Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to us, a free gift of grace received entirely through &lt;em&gt;faith&lt;/em&gt;. We can stand firm irrespective of our own wretchedness and sin and failure because of this righteousness from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is profound truth in this. But there is another view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But thanks be to God that, though you used to be slaves to sin, you wholeheartedly obeyed the form of teaching to which you were entrusted. You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:17-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Very truly I tell you, whoever keeps my word will never see death.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:51&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being slaves to righteousness and living in total surrender and complete obedience to God is about our sanctification, and ultimately our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;, as we are transformed into the likeness of Christ and live lives that reflect that. Faith or works? Are these contradictory? Jim Packer has a helpful explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final judgment, as we saw, will be according to our &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;⸺that is, our &lt;em&gt;doings&lt;/em&gt;, our whole course of life. The relevance of our &amp;lsquo;doings&amp;rsquo; is not that they ever merit an award from the court⸺they are too far short of perfection to do that⸺but that they provide an index of what is in the heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that one way of acting was meritorious while the other was not, but that from these actions one can tell whether there was love to Christ, the love that springs from faith, in the
heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J.I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Knowing God, Chapter 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James takes up this very idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Show me your faith without deeds, and I will show you my faith by my deeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 2:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we can see it clearly. The righteousness is Christ&amp;rsquo;s alone, freely given and received through faith by us who believe, and initiating in us an ongoing transformation into slaves to righteousness. Through this we live ever more radically changed lives, and through this we have assurance of salvation. The merit is all Christ&amp;rsquo;s and so is the glory. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand firm in the battle, Amy, wholly depending on Christ&amp;rsquo;s righteousness imputed to you, and have assurance of that by the evidence of your own transformed life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The belt of truth</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/Roman_cingulum_1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The belt of truth" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for last week&amp;rsquo;s email⸺what a lot has been going on! I hope by now you&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying your well-deserved break, and that the Lord is doing a work of refreshing and refilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your email you referred to the armour of God, which has prompted me to spend some time reflecting on that. You know how I love to unpack these things! I&amp;rsquo;ll start with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand firm then, with the belt of truth buckled round your waist &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How vital is truth. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to some specifics, but firstly, have you wondered why Paul represents truth as a belt? Why a belt?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found when I looked into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cingulum was the traditional Roman soldier&amp;rsquo;s belt, which only soldiers were allowed to wear, and which they wore even when off duty. The leather straps (baltea) dangling from the front of the belt with their decorative studs (bullae) were the only insignia on their uniform. The belt was about &lt;em&gt;identity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the belt of truth. It is our fundamental identity in Christ, upon which everything else hangs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Christian&amp;rsquo;s identity is in truth⸺truth in who we are and truth in our status before God, sinners saved by grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no difference &amp;hellip; for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and all are justified freely by his grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22b-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spiritual battle, when Satan accuses and we are tempted to despair of who we are, we must hold onto this truth: our Heavenly Father already knows the very worst about us, yet still he loves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God demonstrates his own love for us in this: While we were still sinners, Christ died for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our identity, and our identity is in Christ. Only by holding onto this are we able to stand firm in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he or she is a new creation; the old has gone, the new has come!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand firm in this truth, Amy, which is your identity in Christ! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unmasking the true villain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/adnan-khan-VS2C5_GI_MM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unmasking the true villain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this life like Scooby-Doo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Scooby-Doo episode I can remember ends in the same way. The mystery villain is finally unmasked by the gang and is seen to be a familiar character, who then says, “And I would have gotten away with it too, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for you meddling kids!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul tells a similar tale in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an important lesson there is here. How often life can seem so adversarial, with obstacles being put in our way by people who are frankly, just so annoying! Aargh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If instead we can step back and regain perspective, discerning who is the real enemy and recognising that we are in the middle of a spiritual battle in the heavenly realms, the Holy Spirit will be able to equip us with everything we need to face this. That is the only way to prevail in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of hostility, for example, may we respond with gentleness and kindness towards the one who is not our enemy. Hearts are healed like this, the Lord is glorified and the devil thwarted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this asking too much though? How could we possibly live like this? Paul tells us how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, be strong in the Lord and in his mighty power. Put on the full armour of God, so that you can take your stand against the devil&amp;rsquo;s schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s clearly a bit to be said about the armour of God. For now, though, be a meddling kid and unmask the true villain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your struggle is not against flesh and blood, Amy, so put on the full armour of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
