<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>spiritual warfare on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/spiritual-warfare/</link>
        <description>Recent content in spiritual warfare on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/spiritual-warfare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Pray in the Spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/pray-in-the-spirit/manuel-meurisse-EuCll-F5atI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Pray in the Spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the last piece of the armour of God that is so often overlooked, indeed not even thought of as armour by many?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the Bible is about reading in paragraphs, which are the basic units of expression, things that belong together. Not every Bible translation has the same paragraph breaks, but in both of my preferred translations⸺the NIV 1984 and the ESV⸺the armour of God is described in just one paragraph, which in the NIV ends with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And pray in the Spirit on all occasions with all kinds of prayers and requests. With this in mind, be alert and always keep on praying for all the saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How interesting that Paul would conclude his writing about the armour of God with this. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider how praying in the Spirit could be considered a vital piece of the armour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what does “in the Spirit” even mean? There seems to be much confusion today about what is the work of the Holy Spirit. Jim Packer wrote a whole book about it, &lt;em&gt;Keep in Step with the Spirit&lt;/em&gt;, in which he outlines some of the secondary aspects that seem to occupy most people&amp;rsquo;s attention, including power, revelation, and promptings, before arguing that &lt;em&gt;the primary work of the Holy Spirit is to mediate the presence of Jesus in our lives&lt;/em&gt;. And indeed, this matches with what Jesus says of the Spirit in John 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Paul writes in Romans is closely related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the same way, the Spirit helps us in our weakness. We do not know what we ought to pray for, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groans that words cannot express.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not overthink this. Praying in the Spirit is simply praying in relationship with Jesus. There is no formula, just as there is no formula in human relationship. Mutual commitment and time spent together are required for the relationship to flourish. Jesus is committed! How he is that!! Are we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must do this on all occasions, and with all kinds of prayers and requests. Let&amp;rsquo;s not get into a rut of formulaic praying. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with our wonderful Saviour and enjoy intimacy in relationship. In his presence we are protected in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice too that Paul&amp;rsquo;s instruction is to pray for all the saints, that is, all Christians. In the spiritual battle we must avoid at all cost turning in on ourselves, as if we are the ones who matter most. By no means! Our brothers and sisters in Christ are the ones we must love, and continue to lift up before the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray in the Spirit on all occasions with all kinds of prayers and requests, Amy, for all the saints! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The sword of the Spirit</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-sword-of-the-spirit/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-sword-of-the-spirit/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-sword-of-the-spirit/totte-annerbrink-7PRi1chCnrs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The sword of the Spirit" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the two complementary ways to become an expert swordswoman?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take &amp;hellip; the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first, Sunday school teachers have known since forever the value of memory verses for the spiritual battle. Jesus himself refuted Satan with such when tempted in the wilderness at the beginning of his ministry (Luke 4:1-13).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Man does not live on bread alone.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 8:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Worship the Lord your God and serve him only.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 6:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Do not put the Lord your God to the test.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is enormous power in such verses in the midst of the spiritual battle. Build up your arsenal, Amy, commit them to memory, and make them your own. Here&amp;rsquo;s just one of mine that I lean on when tempted to doubt and despair in the waiting time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You know with all your heart and soul that not one of all the good promises the LORD your God gave you has failed. Every promise has been fulfilled; not one has failed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But such verses are not enough. For the second then, we need understanding of the full breadth and depth of Scripture. We won&amp;rsquo;t get this from isolated verses. We get it from extensive reading and studying of the Bible. This is the only way to handle the word of God with integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest help I have found in this intimidating task is a book I bought while at university, shortly after becoming a Christian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because the Bible is God&amp;rsquo;s Word, it has &lt;em&gt;eternal relevance&lt;/em&gt;; it speaks to all mankind, in every age and in every culture. Because it is God&amp;rsquo;s Word, we must listen⸺and obey. But because God chose to speak His Word through &lt;em&gt;human words in history&lt;/em&gt;, every book in the Bible also has &lt;em&gt;historical particularity&lt;/em&gt;; each document is conditioned by the language, time, and culture in which it was originally written (and in some cases also by the oral history it had before it was written down). Interpretation of the Bible is demanded by the “tension” that exists between its &lt;em&gt;eternal relevance&lt;/em&gt; and its &lt;em&gt;historical particularity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A text cannot mean what it never meant&lt;/em&gt;. Or to put that in a positive way, the true meaning of the biblical text for us is what God originally intended it to mean when it was first spoken. This is the starting point. How we work it out from that point is what this book is basically all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gordon D. Fee &amp;amp; Douglas Stuart, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;How to Read the Bible for All Its Worth, Chapter 1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the Bible in its entirety is surely the journey of a lifetime, but may it never become a dry and dusty chore, nor one that leads to intellectual vanity. Let us engage in this task with all of our mind and a surrendered will, joyfully anticipating new depths of insight into the Father&amp;rsquo;s holiness, majesty, love and faithfulness, and into the magnitude of our rescue by our wonderful Saviour. A right response to our increasing knowledge and understanding will be holy reverence, awe and wonder, gratitude, and adoration and worship of our Lord and Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immerse yourself joyfully in the written word of God, Amy, and learn to wield the sword of the Spirit with integrity and understanding! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The shoes of the gospel of peace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 06:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-shoes-of-the-gospel-of-peace/ben-weber-8W-p8SS6NJE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The shoes of the gospel of peace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come to what Paul says about feet, I have been contemplating, what is it that feet do? Well clearly they go, and they dance. Since you&amp;rsquo;re already acing both of these, I had to wonder whether I had anything at all for you this week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God &amp;hellip; with your feet fitted with the readiness that comes from the gospel of peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:13, 15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two thoughts, however, that I have had. May they encourage your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the armour of God is all about being prepared for battle. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t the gospel of peace seem to be somewhat at odds with that? I was prompted to reread Lieutenant Colonel Tim Collins&amp;rsquo; rousing eve-of-battle speech in the Iraq War. It is not long, but too much to include here in its entirety⸺I encourage you to look it up. I was struck by the juxtaposition of ferocity and compassion, of the warrior on a mission of mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We go to liberate, not to conquer. We will not fly our flags in their country. We are entering Iraq to free a people and the only flag which will be flown in that ancient land is their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Show respect for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you are ferocious in battle remember to be magnanimous in victory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lieutenant Colonel Tim Collins, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.royal-irish.com/stories/lieutenant-colonel-tim-collins-eve-of-battle-speech&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Fort Blair Mayne, Kuwait, 19 March 2003&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who seem to be our adversaries in this world are really not. We are bringers of the gospel of peace, and we go to liberate. May compassion define us in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, our feet must be fitted with &lt;em&gt;readiness&lt;/em&gt;. Who can say when the Lord will choose to act with power and mercy by his Spirit in the lives of those around us? Let us anticipate that he will, and be ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put on the full armour of God, Amy, and fit your dancing, going feet with the readiness that comes from the gospel of peace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The belt of truth</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-belt-of-truth/Roman_cingulum_1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The belt of truth" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for last week&amp;rsquo;s email⸺what a lot has been going on! I hope by now you&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying your well-deserved break, and that the Lord is doing a work of refreshing and refilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your email you referred to the armour of God, which has prompted me to spend some time reflecting on that. You know how I love to unpack these things! I&amp;rsquo;ll start with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand firm then, with the belt of truth buckled round your waist &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How vital is truth. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to some specifics, but firstly, have you wondered why Paul represents truth as a belt? Why a belt?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found when I looked into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cingulum was the traditional Roman soldier&amp;rsquo;s belt, which only soldiers were allowed to wear, and which they wore even when off duty. The leather straps (baltea) dangling from the front of the belt with their decorative studs (bullae) were the only insignia on their uniform. The belt was about &lt;em&gt;identity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the belt of truth. It is our fundamental identity in Christ, upon which everything else hangs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Christian&amp;rsquo;s identity is in truth⸺truth in who we are and truth in our status before God, sinners saved by grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no difference &amp;hellip; for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and all are justified freely by his grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22b-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spiritual battle, when Satan accuses and we are tempted to despair of who we are, we must hold onto this truth: our Heavenly Father already knows the very worst about us, yet still he loves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God demonstrates his own love for us in this: While we were still sinners, Christ died for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our identity, and our identity is in Christ. Only by holding onto this are we able to stand firm in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he or she is a new creation; the old has gone, the new has come!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand firm in this truth, Amy, which is your identity in Christ! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unmasking the true villain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/adnan-khan-VS2C5_GI_MM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unmasking the true villain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this life like Scooby-Doo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Scooby-Doo episode I can remember ends in the same way. The mystery villain is finally unmasked by the gang and is seen to be a familiar character, who then says, “And I would have gotten away with it too, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for you meddling kids!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul tells a similar tale in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an important lesson there is here. How often life can seem so adversarial, with obstacles being put in our way by people who are frankly, just so annoying! Aargh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If instead we can step back and regain perspective, discerning who is the real enemy and recognising that we are in the middle of a spiritual battle in the heavenly realms, the Holy Spirit will be able to equip us with everything we need to face this. That is the only way to prevail in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of hostility, for example, may we respond with gentleness and kindness towards the one who is not our enemy. Hearts are healed like this, the Lord is glorified and the devil thwarted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this asking too much though? How could we possibly live like this? Paul tells us how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, be strong in the Lord and in his mighty power. Put on the full armour of God, so that you can take your stand against the devil&amp;rsquo;s schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s clearly a bit to be said about the armour of God. For now, though, be a meddling kid and unmask the true villain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your struggle is not against flesh and blood, Amy, so put on the full armour of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
