<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>law on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/law/</link>
        <description>Recent content in law on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The grace-filled life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/tom-morbey-r1SwcagHVG0-unsplash-cropped.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The grace-filled life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are not under law but under grace, does it even matter what we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It matters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What shall we say then? Are we to continue in sin that grace may abound? By no means! How can we who died to sin still live in it? Do you not know that all of us who have been baptized into Christ Jesus were baptized into his death? We were buried therefore with him by baptism into death, in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, we too might walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we learn to walk in newness of life, not under law but under grace? If all those long lists of commandments still apply, how are we not under law? And if not, how can we avoid living in sin? Certainly not by overlooking what Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Do not think that I have come to abolish the Law or the Prophets; I have not come to abolish them but to fulfill them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like us, the fledgling church in Galatia was under threat from those preaching works. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider what Paul wrote to them. Here&amp;rsquo;s the key:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, but that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big if! How can we know, and how can we be secure in that knowledge? Because there&amp;rsquo;s a grievous trap here which snares many, namely equating being led by the Spirit with living according to the convictions of one&amp;rsquo;s own heart. This is fraught with danger! Satan is the father of lies and the great deceiver, and by stroking our egos and flattering our vanity he can manipulate our feelings even and perhaps especially in this realm. How can we escape this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the desires of the flesh are against the Spirit, and the desires of the Spirit are against the flesh, for these are opposed to each other, to keep you from doing the things you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the works of the flesh are evident: sexual immorality, impurity, sensuality, idolatry, sorcery, enmity, strife, jealousy, fits of anger, rivalries, dissensions, divisions, envy, drunkenness, orgies, and things like these. I warn you, as I warned you before, that those who do such things will not inherit the kingdom of God. But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:17, 19-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first list is truly shocking, and we might be tempted to think is far from where we live our lives, but consider idolatry for one⸺in regard to career, reputation, and respectability, how evident is this in every church! Now, notice that eight out of these fifteen works of the flesh comprise dysfunctional relationship and unlove. There&amp;rsquo;s a clue here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could being led by the Spirit in fact be quite straightforward? The opposite of dysfunctional relationship and unlove is simply, love. There&amp;rsquo;s more than love in the second list, of course, but that&amp;rsquo;s surely the headline. And what does Paul say elsewhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here indeed is the answer. We can live not under law but under grace by loving the Lord with all our heart, soul, mind and strength, and loving one another, unconditionally and without exception, in joyful surrender. Love that starts small must grow and grow and continue to grow⸺this is the fruit of the Spirit. So simple, and yet learning to do this adequately will take each one of us the rest of our earthly lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live a life of love, Amy, led by the Spirit, as one not under law but under grace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Black and white?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/black-and-white/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/black-and-white/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/black-and-white/rafael-rex-felisilda-U_Kz2RnfFAk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Black and white?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean in practice to be a people not under law but under grace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For sin will have no dominion over you, since you are not under law but under grace. What then? Are we to sin because we are not under law but under grace? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Law and grace: are these in opposition? Jesus sets the highest standards in the Sermon on the Mount, then freely forgives and restores, refusing to let law limit grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a couple of contemporary issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I do not permit a woman to teach or to exercise authority over a man; rather, she is to remain quiet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 2:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely this was a cultural thing that no longer applies, and so surely these days women are free to pursue a preaching ministry? Surely? Except for the very next verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Adam was formed first, then Eve; and Adam was not deceived, but the woman was deceived and became a transgressor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 2:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh dear. Paul is making a creational argument here, which seems to be as clear as it is harsh. Not something that can be so easily brushed aside then!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose however to hold no opinion about this, and instead I choose to honour those women who have wrestled with this themselves and are honouring and serving the Lord through a preaching ministry. Wrestling is certainly required, but who am I to seek to impose my own view into someone else&amp;rsquo;s life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, I have my own issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said to them, “Because of your hardness of heart Moses allowed you to divorce your wives, but from the beginning it was not so. And I say to you: whoever divorces his wife, except for sexual immorality, and marries another, commits adultery.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this prevent the Lord from rescuing me from the shame of my own life after a failed marriage? Is grace trumped by law here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How tempted we are to be black and white about the lives of others, yet rather grey about our own. Show me the one who does not find themselves on the wrong side of particular verses in the Bible, and does not have to cast themselves upon God&amp;rsquo;s mercy even to live their life. Does such a one exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus himself faced a law versus grace issue in relation to the Fourth Commandment, and on one occasion when confronted by the Pharisees, he related the story of David apparently breaking the law by eating with his men consecrated bread from the temple, before concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I tell you, something greater than the temple is here. And if you had known what this means, &amp;lsquo;I desire mercy, and not sacrifice,&amp;rsquo; you would not have condemned the guiltless. For the Son of Man is lord of the Sabbath.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 12:6-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that under grace everything is in fact somewhat grey? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything rather is lit by a dazzling technicolour explosion of grace and redemption from the Lord, and that particular mercy which triumphs over judgment. This enables some women to pursue a preaching ministry for his glory, some divorced men to remarry by his grace, and others to live their lives in dependence on the riches of his mercy. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that this in no way removes or diminishes our call to live as slaves to righteousness, fully surrendered and walking in obedience with the Lord. (I will undoubtedly have to revisit this aspect of “not under law but under grace”.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live your life for his glory, Amy, as one not under law but under grace, and praise the Lord! 🙏🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
