<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>kindness on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/kindness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in kindness on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 06:24:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/kindness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Emptiness and exhaustion</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/emptiness-and-exhaustion/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/emptiness-and-exhaustion/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/emptiness-and-exhaustion/brut-carniollus-jGEsapFCLgw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Emptiness and exhaustion" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else can we learn from Elijah&amp;rsquo;s faith-wobble?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was running for his life, and after 120 miles or so he left his servant and continued alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But he himself went a day&amp;rsquo;s journey into the wilderness and came and sat down under a broom tree. And he asked that he might die, saying, “It is enough; now, O LORD, take away my life, for I am no better than my fathers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was a man empty and exhausted, utterly cast down, apparently at his end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he lay down and slept under a broom tree. And behold, an angel touched him and said to him, “Arise and eat.” And he looked, and behold, there was at his head a cake baked on hot stones and a jar of water. And he ate and drank and lay down again. And the angel of the LORD came again a second time and touched him and said, “Arise and eat, for the journey is too great for you.” And he arose and ate and drank, and went in the strength of that food forty days and forty nights to Horeb, the mount of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey to Horeb was at least another 250 miles. What a cake that must have been!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice what was the Lord&amp;rsquo;s first response⸺not that gentle rebuke which was to follow. The first response was practical and compassionate care and provision for his servant who was empty and utterly exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what? Elijah poured out his heart to the Lord, and you can be sure the tears were streaming down his face. Read for yourself the words of a broken man with nothing left to give, without hope and apparently all alone (1 Kings 19:10, 14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was the Lord&amp;rsquo;s response to that? He rescued him and restored him and gave him something to do (1 Kings 19:15-18). Let me paraphrase it like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It&amp;rsquo;s ok, Elijah, I&amp;rsquo;ve got this. And by the way, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. I have seven thousand others. And you are still useful to me. Come on, let&amp;rsquo;s go again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus the Lord restored Elijah, gave him hope, and continued to work out his plans and purposes through him and through Elisha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So he departed from there and found Elisha the son of Shaphat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then [Elisha] arose and went after Elijah and assisted him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 19:19, 21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same God who looks with such love on each one of us in our own brokenness and emptiness and exhaustion, and rescues and restores, and continues to use us for his Kingdom plans and purposes. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His grace is sufficient for you, Amy, for his power is made perfect in your weakness! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Thankfulness that glorifies</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/thankfulness-that-glorifies/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/thankfulness-that-glorifies/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/thankfulness-that-glorifies/joshua-clay-VNjNtdu0yCw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Thankfulness that glorifies" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can our thankfulness glorify the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will praise God’s name in song and glorify him with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 69:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an aspect to thankfulness that I want to explore this week, which is this: receiving kindness from those around us as from the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone treats me with particular kindness, who am I likely to thank? Too often we think in purely human terms, but there&amp;rsquo;s another dimension here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s one side of the coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For it is God who works in you to will and to act in order to fulfil his good purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we are God’s handiwork, created in Christ Jesus to do good works, which God prepared in advance for us to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has plans and purposes, and he works in and through each one of us to fulfil them. He works even in the lives of those who neither honour nor acknowledge him. We know this. Now consider the other side of that coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that the Lord delights in exercising kindness (Jeremiah 9:24)⸺this is one of his good purposes! So when we receive kindness from others, why would we not make that connection and ascribe it to him? To do so makes my soul sing in gratitude to my Saviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I experienced exactly this, twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one occasion I was in church, after the morning service. Church can be the loneliest place, and I was facing the bleak prospect of a Sunday afternoon by myself, at a time when I was particularly downcast. Just outside church and completely out of the blue, a friend invited me mountain biking that afternoon, in a way that seemed so random and so kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other was on my birthday, and I was at home in a melancholic mood. Suddenly there was a knock on my back door. It was my neighbour, with a slice of apple shortcake she had just made, and a little tub of cream to go with it. How lovely. She had no idea it was my birthday, nor did I tell her. How random again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have learned that these random acts of kindness are not remotely random. I ascribe them to my Heavenly Father, and thank him. And through these he makes known his own character, his overflowing kindness, and he is glorified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praise God’s name in song, Amy, and glorify him with thanksgiving! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unmasking the true villain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/unmasking-the-true-villain/adnan-khan-VS2C5_GI_MM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unmasking the true villain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this life like Scooby-Doo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Scooby-Doo episode I can remember ends in the same way. The mystery villain is finally unmasked by the gang and is seen to be a familiar character, who then says, “And I would have gotten away with it too, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for you meddling kids!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul tells a similar tale in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an important lesson there is here. How often life can seem so adversarial, with obstacles being put in our way by people who are frankly, just so annoying! Aargh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If instead we can step back and regain perspective, discerning who is the real enemy and recognising that we are in the middle of a spiritual battle in the heavenly realms, the Holy Spirit will be able to equip us with everything we need to face this. That is the only way to prevail in the spiritual battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of hostility, for example, may we respond with gentleness and kindness towards the one who is not our enemy. Hearts are healed like this, the Lord is glorified and the devil thwarted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this asking too much though? How could we possibly live like this? Paul tells us how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, be strong in the Lord and in his mighty power. Put on the full armour of God, so that you can take your stand against the devil&amp;rsquo;s schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s clearly a bit to be said about the armour of God. For now, though, be a meddling kid and unmask the true villain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your struggle is not against flesh and blood, Amy, so put on the full armour of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Kindness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/kindness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/kindness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/kindness/limor-zellermayer-cANocSiow7g-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Kindness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is one of the most important considerations when engaging with someone in a difficult conversation? When everything within you wants to make your point, to justify yourself with great vigour? When you have waited for so long and the time is now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; kindness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How easy this is to overlook. Could I be overstating its importance though? I think not. Consider this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am the LORD, who exercises kindness, justice and righteousness on earth, for in these I delight,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 9:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kindness is remarkably prominent don&amp;rsquo;t you think? And the Lord delights in it! And what of this, which characterizes Jesus as the embodiment of kindness and love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the kindness and love of God our Saviour appeared, he saved us &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Titus 3:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider those who hurt us, and don&amp;rsquo;t even know they have.  What better way is there to bless than with kindness? There&amp;rsquo;s real power in this, power to heal, and power to save. It is a work of the Holy Spirit that we can live like this, in giving rather than receiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As God’s chosen people, holy and dearly loved, clothe yourselves with &amp;hellip; kindness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be filled with kindness, Amy, breathing it out as a blessing from the Holy Spirit! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
