<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How to grow in reverent awe and wonder</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/atharva-tulsi-2jA_YoQuvaA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to grow in reverent awe and wonder" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do we grow in reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done? Because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just happen. It takes serious get-up-early-and-cry-out-to-God hard work, every single day. Work. But not without incredible joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 helps. I won&amp;rsquo;t quote it here, because, well, it&amp;rsquo;s quite long. I have been including the first 32 verses in my daily readings for several years now.  (From time to time I read the whole psalm; it is worth it.)  I find these qualities in the psalmist. Earnest. Longing. Disciplined. Realistic. Falling short. Being held. Fully surrendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These verses conclude, &amp;ldquo;I run in the path of your commands, for you have set my heart free.&amp;rdquo;  I pray that you may increasingly run in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commands like this.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know the will of the Lord? Let&amp;rsquo;s look again into the treasure trove which is Psalm 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, then, are those who fear the LORD? He will instruct them in the ways he chooses (v12).  The LORD confides in those who fear him; he makes his covenant known to them (v14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Keller defines the fear of the Lord as this, in a sermon from Proverbs on the fear of the Lord being the beginning of wisdom. &amp;ldquo;The fear of the Lord is a reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My prayer for you is that you learn to live this more each day.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>He guides the humble in what is right</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/claudio-carrozzo-fCtvc5eFcqk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post He guides the humble in what is right" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is Psalm 25:8-9 for you:  Good and upright is the LORD; therefore he instructs sinners in his ways. He guides the humble in what is right and teaches them his way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the therefore. Meditate on it. Revel in it. See how the Lord desires for us to be holy and blameless, and yet he does not wait for that to be so, to instruct us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path of humility is more than these two verses. It is the whole psalm. And now, I have given you one of my most precious jewels. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/jonny-james-TE0leJlNX8Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Filled with the knowledge of his will" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/joe-johannes-qVcs4k1H_4k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just wondering how you are coping with the heat over there, Amy. And that made me think of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But blessed is the one who trusts in the LORD, whose confidence is in him. They will be like a tree planted by the water that sends out its roots by the stream. It does not fear when heat comes; its leaves are always green. It has no worries in a year of drought and never fails to bear fruit.”  &amp;ndash; Jeremiah 17:7-8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s monsoon season there, so enjoy the irony. Praying for you 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Peace and Provision</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/raimond-klavins-DDwOFA_9LiY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Peace and Provision" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;May you know peace from the Lord, and his provision for you, Amy, as you wait on him, and especially when things don&amp;rsquo;t turn out as you expected or hoped. Know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans prevail, and &amp;hellip; he delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love. Psalm 147:11
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
