<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The truth will set you free</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/aaron-burden-TNlHf4m4gpI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The truth will set you free" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;If you hold to my teaching &amp;hellip; then you will know the truth &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (John 8:31-32). Truth is more important now than ever, given the post-truth world in which we live, where people are inclined to define their own truth. Christians are not immune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are never more vulnerable than when we say, &amp;ldquo;the Lord told me &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  What exactly do we mean by this? What interplay of conviction, imagination, emotion and coincidence are we leaning on? And what grounds do we have to trust any of that? We must take great care here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providentially, the Lord has told me a great deal, all of which is trustworthy and true. It was written down long ago, over 1200 pages. My best chance to grasp the truth is to read Scripture, diligently and comprehensively, with intellectual integrity and a surrendered heart, particularly when it becomes uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;If you hold to my teaching &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  It is not enough to read. We have to do it, to live and breathe his teaching, habitually and unceasingly. Only then can we really understand, and know the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot; &amp;hellip; and the truth will set you free.&amp;quot; (John 8:32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be free, Amy 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Perfect love drives out fear</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/josue-michel-xCU7nCMNfI8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Perfect love drives out fear" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another observation on plain old fear, also from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter. The punchline is &amp;ldquo;perfect love drives out fear&amp;rdquo; (1 Jn 4:18), but to understand what he is saying you have to read the whole passage — the golden rule, always!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll string some of it together. &amp;ldquo;If we love one another, God lives in us and his love is made complete in us&amp;rdquo; (v12).  &amp;ldquo;Love is made complete &amp;hellip; because in this world we are like him&amp;rdquo; (v17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What drives out fear, then? We must be Christ to one another, one relationship at a time. One conversation at a time. If we love as Christ loved us, we live in right relationship with God and with one another. Perspective is restored, and fear is dissipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pray you may know the power of this in your own life, Amy. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Plain old fear</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/simon-berger-rydQVdwcgUQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Plain old fear" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the fear of the Lord, and there&amp;rsquo;s plain old fear, and the two are mutually exclusive. Consider plain old fear. Fear that disempowers. Debilitates. Disembowels. Fear that blinds, and blindness that feeds fear, in a downward spiral. To see how to end it, understand how it begins. It begins with lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about me (1 Jn 4:9-10). God has no use for me (Jer 29:11). God won&amp;rsquo;t keep his promises (Josh 23:14). God can&amp;rsquo;t do it (Jer 32:27). It won&amp;rsquo;t end well (Rev 21:3-4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list is not exhaustive. But whatever the fear, when in its grip, expose the lie which birthed the fear. Here&amp;rsquo;s that joyous verse from Psalm 119 again: &amp;ldquo;I have chosen the way of truth &amp;hellip; I run in the path of your commands, for you have set my heart free&amp;rdquo; (v30, 32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May our Lord and Saviour continue to free your heart, Amy. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Covid Prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/yannis-h-zpSXcUpmhNc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Covid Prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear God, my God,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the Lord of all creation, majestic, sovereign, good, and wise beyond our understanding. Praise your holy name! I lift up to you the situation in Amy&amp;rsquo;s village, with Covid having arrived, and along with it, fear. Forgive us when we doubt your goodness or your sovereignty. I pray the people there would hear Jesus speaking, &amp;ldquo;Peace I leave with you; my peace I give you. I do not give to you as the world gives. Do not let your hearts be troubled and do not be afraid.&amp;rdquo; (John 14:27). Please keep Amy safe and well, and may she be a beacon of hope for those who may be losing theirs, pointing to Jesus and trusting him.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cc: Amy, with love&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiveness and purification</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/nega-YdyhHbWZ1V0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiveness and purification" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a well loved verse from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter, that we may be in danger of reading too quickly and missing the most important word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness. (1 Jn 1:9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some important words here. Confess. Sins. And some wonderful, lifting words. Faithful. Forgive. Purify. But what am I referring to? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. &lt;em&gt;Just&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem to be a little out of place, yet it is the crucial word. Consider why. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours, in full. If we confess our sins, and cry out to God for mercy, it is his &lt;em&gt;justice&lt;/em&gt; that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment. Rejoice, that he is faithful &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; just.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to grow in reverent awe and wonder</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/atharva-tulsi-2jA_YoQuvaA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to grow in reverent awe and wonder" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do we grow in reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done? Because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just happen. It takes serious get-up-early-and-cry-out-to-God hard work, every single day. Work. But not without incredible joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 helps. I won&amp;rsquo;t quote it here, because, well, it&amp;rsquo;s quite long. I have been including the first 32 verses in my daily readings for several years now.  (From time to time I read the whole psalm; it is worth it.)  I find these qualities in the psalmist. Earnest. Longing. Disciplined. Realistic. Falling short. Being held. Fully surrendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These verses conclude, &amp;ldquo;I run in the path of your commands, for you have set my heart free.&amp;rdquo;  I pray that you may increasingly run in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commands like this.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know the will of the Lord? Let&amp;rsquo;s look again into the treasure trove which is Psalm 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, then, are those who fear the LORD? He will instruct them in the ways he chooses (v12).  The LORD confides in those who fear him; he makes his covenant known to them (v14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Keller defines the fear of the Lord as this, in a sermon from Proverbs on the fear of the Lord being the beginning of wisdom. &amp;ldquo;The fear of the Lord is a reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My prayer for you is that you learn to live this more each day.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>He guides the humble in what is right</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/claudio-carrozzo-fCtvc5eFcqk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post He guides the humble in what is right" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is Psalm 25:8-9 for you:  Good and upright is the LORD; therefore he instructs sinners in his ways. He guides the humble in what is right and teaches them his way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the therefore. Meditate on it. Revel in it. See how the Lord desires for us to be holy and blameless, and yet he does not wait for that to be so, to instruct us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path of humility is more than these two verses. It is the whole psalm. And now, I have given you one of my most precious jewels. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/jonny-james-TE0leJlNX8Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Filled with the knowledge of his will" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/joe-johannes-qVcs4k1H_4k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just wondering how you are coping with the heat over there, Amy. And that made me think of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But blessed is the one who trusts in the LORD, whose confidence is in him. They will be like a tree planted by the water that sends out its roots by the stream. It does not fear when heat comes; its leaves are always green. It has no worries in a year of drought and never fails to bear fruit.”  &amp;ndash; Jeremiah 17:7-8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s monsoon season there, so enjoy the irony. Praying for you 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Peace and Provision</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/raimond-klavins-DDwOFA_9LiY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Peace and Provision" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;May you know peace from the Lord, and his provision for you, Amy, as you wait on him, and especially when things don&amp;rsquo;t turn out as you expected or hoped. Know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans prevail, and &amp;hellip; he delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love. Psalm 147:11
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
