<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 06:26:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Impossible</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/impossible/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/impossible/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/impossible/isaac-quesada-dZYI4ga2eUA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Impossible" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we receive it when God speaks the impossible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have many examples of God speaking something impossible. Why does he do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua was told to march the Israelite army around the walls of Jericho for seven days, and the walls would collapse, but even before he was so instructed, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Joshua, “See, I have delivered Jericho into your hands, along with its king and its fighting men.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 6:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if it had already happened! Joshua had to act on the basis that something impossible would happen. (And it did.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably Abraham had it even harder. He had to wait on an impossible promise, for twenty-five years! Waiting is perhaps harder than doing. And waiting for twenty-five years?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other examples in the Bible of God speaking the impossible. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: &lt;em&gt;he is still doing it today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I the LORD do not change.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 13:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bible itself teaches that we are to understand it in terms of our own experience when it says that Paul, Barnabas and Elijah were human beings like us and that Jesus knows how we feel in our weaknesses because he himself “in every respect has been tested as we are” (Heb 4:15). It means that &lt;em&gt;their experience was substantially like our own&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must pray for the faith and for the experiences that would enable us to believe that &lt;em&gt;such things could happen to us&lt;/em&gt;. Only then will we be able to recognize, accept and dwell in them when they come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dallas Willard, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hearing God, Chapter 2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How then can we receive it when God speaks the impossible? It is in fact a high honour, an invitation to demonstrate radical faith, and to grow in that faith. Perhaps God reserves such things for those for whom he has great plans, which will require great faith. (That&amp;rsquo;s a little scary, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hold on to this verse, which has kept me going for some years, and was itself given to me in a miraculous way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;God is not a man, that he should lie, nor a son of man, that he should change his mind. Does he speak and then not act? Does he promise and not fulfill?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 23:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This remains even if the promise is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Then the word of the LORD came to Jeremiah: “I am the LORD, the God of all mankind. Is anything too hard for me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 32:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait on the Lord in faith, Amy, knowing that he who promised is faithful (Heb 10:23), even if it seems impossible!  🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A great cloud of witnesses</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-great-cloud-of-witnesses/sandeep-damre-14IPTP-6mTc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A great cloud of witnesses" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently we are surrounded by a great cloud of witnesses, and this is a reason to run the race with perseverance. What&amp;rsquo;s all that about?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important that we understand this, because doesn&amp;rsquo;t it sound just a little bit creepy? Are all these witnesses sitting in heaven watching us, and so had we better not embarrass ourselves for that reason? By no means! (as Paul would say). That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what this is not saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these witnesses are listed in Chapter 11, with this introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now faith is being sure of what we hope for and certain of what we do not see. This is what the ancients were commended for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writer then goes on to list the incredible demonstrations of faith by these witnesses, and they are incredible. But what is it that they are witnessing? Is it us? No, it&amp;rsquo;s not us. Here&amp;rsquo;s what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By their faith they are &lt;em&gt;witnesses to the Lord&lt;/em&gt;, to his goodness and kindness and faithfulness. When we live lives of radical faith it points to the one who enables us to do that, to the one for whom we live. And they were commended for it and highly honoured because this is glorious, to live in such a way that our very lives bear testimony to the Lord. This is a powerful witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is why &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; run the race with perseverance. It is a powerful witness. The only ones watching are our contemporaries (oh, and the Lord, obviously — Ps 139, Rev 20:12). But if we run this race well, the Lord may choose to use &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; witness to save some of &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run with perseverance, Amy, and join the great cloud of witnesses in testifying to the goodness, kindness and faithfulness of the Lord! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Running with perseverance</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/running-with-perseverance/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/running-with-perseverance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/running-with-perseverance/cameron-venti-I1EWTM5mFEM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Running with perseverance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a long race to run. How will we not grow weary and lose heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews tells us exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by such a great cloud of witnesses, let us throw off everything that hinders and the sin that so easily entangles, and let us run with perseverance the race marked out for us. Let us fix our eyes on Jesus, the author and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy set before him endured the cross, scorning its shame, and sat down at the right hand of the throne of God. Consider him who endured such opposition from sinful men, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How? By fixing our eyes on Jesus and considering him. Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack that a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running is hard and I get tired, but by fixing my eyes on Jesus one thing is sure. I will be running towards him, always. He is the author of my story, the author of my faith, the reason that I live and the reason that I live in him. He is also the perfecter (that is completer) of my faith, sustaining me so that I can finish the race. I will not fall because &amp;hellip; Jesus. Because of all that he is and all that he has done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did he do all this? He endured such opposition from sinful men — those he had come to save no less! He endured the pain and humiliation of the cross, and the real agony of it all: separation from the Father. But why? Why did he do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are told why he did it and how he endured: &lt;em&gt;for the joy set before him&lt;/em&gt;. And what was that joy? That joy was the knowledge that he was saving you and me, Amy. That was what gave him the strength to endure the unendurable. That was his joy. His love for you and his love for me, and saving you and saving me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that! Consider him! How loved we are! How comprehensive Jesus&#39; victory! How wonderful his love!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider him, Amy, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Relational authenticity</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/relational-authenticity/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/relational-authenticity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/relational-authenticity/jingming-pan-iYsrkq5qq0Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Relational authenticity" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most important thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is love &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve left this one until last, precisely because it is the most important. Why do I say that? So many reasons, starting with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus replied: “&amp;lsquo;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.&amp;rsquo;  This is the first and greatest commandment. And the second is like it: &amp;lsquo;Love your neighbour as yourself.&amp;rsquo;  All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 22:36-40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A new command I give you: Love one another. As I have loved you, so you must love one another. By this everyone will know that you are my disciples, if you love one another.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not optional — there is absolutely no wriggle room here! And yet, why is it that we do not live like this? For tragically, we do not. We should be living and breathing this, all the time. Nothing matters more. But what exactly are we supposed to do as we go about our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phrase I came upon recently has really got its hooks into me: &lt;em&gt;relational authenticity&lt;/em&gt;. This is surely the starting point. Relational authenticity recognises that the one standing before me is a real person, whoever they may be. A real person with their hopes, dreams, disappointments and hurts, just like me. And the choice which is uniquely mine is whether and how to relate, to accept, to love. How do I regard them? As background noise? A diversion? A duty? Someone to look down upon? Someone to avoid? Or a whole person, with all their value and complexity and brokenness, loved by the Lord, as am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. Relational authenticity demands radical humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is no difference &amp;hellip; for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified freely by his grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How this challenges ego!  But could we live like this? The prize is glorious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In him the whole building is joined together and rises to become a holy temple in the Lord. And in him you too are being built together to become a dwelling in which God lives by his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we develop relational authenticity, this is what we will find: all of us, together, a holy temple in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us not overlook that this is the fruit of the Spirit. We grow in this as the Lord does his work of transforming grace in our lives. In my life. In yours. Softening our hearts, enabling us to love, and making us more like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursue relational authenticity, Amy, and learn to love like Jesus, the most important thing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Self-control</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/self-control/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/self-control/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/self-control/peter-herrmann-9_FK2Tp-kLA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Self-control" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we travel in time, and how could that help our self-control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; self-control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact it&amp;rsquo;s easy to travel in time, in our imagination. There are two vital destinations that can help us grow in self-control, especially in the face of temptation. But first, take note of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;God is faithful; he will not let you be tempted beyond what you can bear. But when you are tempted, he will also provide a way out so that you can stand up under it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should expect to be tempted. How else will we grow in self-control other than by exercising it? So we should expect also to have to work at this. It won&amp;rsquo;t be easy, obviously, since nothing worthwhile was ever gained like that. Just let us never overlook God&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness in enabling us to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first destination in time is just a few minutes into the future. Let us imagine looking back, observing our own behaviour through the lens of hindsight. Do we see someone behaving honourably? Someone displaying strength of character? Someone we are pleased to be? May the Lord&amp;rsquo;s sustaining grace enable us to be that! We must be mindful that our character is defined by the accumulation of every choice that we make, no matter how small or apparently insignificant. The new viewpoint helps enormously with this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second destination is a little further, at the end of our lives. Let us imagine being welcomed into heaven by our Lord. What is it that I want to hear on that day? I will live my life to hear him say this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Well done, good and faithful servant!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do some time-travelling in your mind, Amy, and live your life to hear him say, “Well done, my good and faithful servant!” 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faithfulness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faithfulness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faithfulness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faithfulness/sean-benesh-VnmbcgAfL3Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faithfulness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fuels faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; faithfulness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness is such an honourable character trait, perhaps the noblest of them all. To be loyal, steadfast, trustworthy and true — surely these words make our hearts soar. They speak to the very heart of noble character, of character that honours the Lord. So where does faithfulness come from? There are two answers to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness, evident throughout Scripture, from where he first introduces himself to Moses, right up to John&amp;rsquo;s vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, the rider on the white horse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And [the LORD] passed in front of Moses, proclaiming, “The LORD, the LORD, the compassionate and gracious God, slow to anger, abounding in love and faithfulness, maintaining love to thousands, and forgiving wickedness, rebellion and sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All the ways of the LORD are loving and faithful for those who keep the demands of his covenant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For the word of the LORD is right and true; he is faithful in all he does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 33:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your love, O LORD, reaches to the heavens, your faithfulness to the skies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 36:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yet this I call to mind and therefore I have hope: Because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great love we are not consumed, for his compassions never fail. They are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The one who calls you is faithful and he will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I saw heaven standing open and there before me was a white horse, whose rider is called Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness to us makes our hearts burn with fire, fuelling our own faithfulness, our noblest thoughts and deeds, through and for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, consider the word itself, &lt;em&gt;pistis&lt;/em&gt; in the original Greek. Mostly that word is not in fact translated as faithfulness, but rather faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pistis — persuasion that is credence; moral conviction (of religious truth or the truthfulness of God or a religious teacher) especially reliance upon Christ for salvation; abstractly constancy in such profession; by extension the system of religious (Gospel) truth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Strong&amp;#39;s Greek Lexicon&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faithfulness then is fueled by being full of faith. Genuine, all-in, life-changing faith in the one who is faithful to all he has said, and indeed all he is, gives us the power to live lives that are worthy of our calling, manifesting in the noblest of hearts, and lasting faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him Amy, whose name is Faithful and True, be full of faith, and let that fuel your own faithfulness, to him and for him, forever! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Joy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/joy/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 08:15:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/joy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/joy/mi-pham-FtZL0r4DZYk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Joy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we choose joy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; joy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t joy something that from time to time lands on us, thrills our heart, and lifts us into the Lord&amp;rsquo;s presence? How can we choose this for ourselves? In fact we can, and understanding this is the key to a deeper, richer, more joyous walk with the Lord, independent of the circumstances of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Paul&amp;rsquo;s command (a command, no less!) to the Philippians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says it again because it is of such great importance. We must understand this! But how can we rejoice when life is hard, and sorrow and pain feature so prominently in our world and in our lives? Paul tells us almost immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers and sisters, whatever is true, whatever is noble, whatever is right, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is admirable—if anything is excellent or praiseworthy—think about such things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are these things we must think about, exactly? I am grateful to Jim Packer for presenting this so clearly, thus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God loves me, infinitely and eternally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything comes to me from God, at least with his permission and always under his protection, to further my eternal good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My saving knowledge of the Lord Jesus, which will eternally increase, is something supremely worth having.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel message of salvation that I seek to pass on to others is something supremely worth giving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Laid-Back Religion? Chapter 6: Joy&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By meditating on these matters constantly and faithfully, springs of joy well up in our hearts, turning our Christian walk into “an experience of contentment and exaltation of which the world knows nothing” ― &lt;em&gt;J.I. Packer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose joy, Amy, and meditate on the uplifting and glorious truths of the Lord! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Integrity and uprightness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/integrity-and-uprightness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/integrity-and-uprightness/chris-brignola-X2CxUXFqKcM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Integrity and uprightness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can goodness protect us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; goodness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Greek word is &lt;em&gt;agathōsunē&lt;/em&gt;, which can be translated &lt;em&gt;uprightness of heart and life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look briefly again into Psalm 25 (what a jewel of a psalm that is!), where David writes with such humility, so aware of his own shortcomings and his desire to live a life of integrity, honouring the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect me, because my hope is in you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see protection there, but how does that work? Before we get to that, read the whole psalm and notice that there is not a shred of smug self-satisfaction as David seeks with all his heart to honour the Lord and live a right life. Paul also writes of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must seek with our whole heart to live as slaves to righteousness, purging every wrong thought and deed, pouring ourselves out in humility and gratitude to the Lord. The Holy Spirit enables us to do this. It is a miracle of grace that sinners such as we are, even forgiven sinners, can live with such integrity and uprightness, evidence in our own lives of the victory Jesus won on the cross. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we live with humility as slaves to righteousness, continuing to be sanctified by the Holy Spirit, integrity and uprightness keep us on the narrow path that leads to life, and it is this that protects us. The process is ongoing, and so is the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May integrity and uprightness protect you, Amy, as you live as a slave to righteousness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Kindness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/kindness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/kindness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/kindness/limor-zellermayer-cANocSiow7g-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Kindness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is one of the most important considerations when engaging with someone in a difficult conversation? When everything within you wants to make your point, to justify yourself with great vigour? When you have waited for so long and the time is now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; kindness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How easy this is to overlook. Could I be overstating its importance though? I think not. Consider this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I am the LORD, who exercises kindness, justice and righteousness on earth, for in these I delight,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 9:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kindness is remarkably prominent don&amp;rsquo;t you think? And the Lord delights in it! And what of this, which characterizes Jesus as the embodiment of kindness and love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the kindness and love of God our Saviour appeared, he saved us&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Titus 3:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider those who hurt us, and don&amp;rsquo;t even know they have.  What better way is there to bless than with kindness? There&amp;rsquo;s real power in this, power to heal, and power to save. It is a work of the Holy Spirit that we can live like this, in giving rather than receiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As God’s chosen people, holy and dearly loved, clothe yourselves with &amp;hellip; kindness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be filled with kindness, Amy, breathing it out as a blessing from the Holy Spirit! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Tranquility in the soul</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/tranquility-in-the-soul/capturing-the-human-heart-i9uIhSlOWYc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Tranquility in the soul" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know real peace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; peace&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace here is the Greek word &lt;em&gt;eirene&lt;/em&gt;, which corresponds to the Hebrew word shalom, and could be translated as &lt;em&gt;tranquility in the soul&lt;/em&gt;. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want such a thing? But how can we possibly know such a peace in the turbulent and warmongering world in which we live?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 46 provides insight, and is worth reading in its entirety. The world it describes doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem so very different from our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mountains fall into the heart of the sea,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nations are in uproar, kingdoms fall;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 46:2, 6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What an apparently chaotic and tempestuous world this is.  And yet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He lifts his voice, the earth melts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a voice that is! Tranquility in the soul is rooted in the absolute surety that the Lord is sovereign, infinite in power, so very good, and that he loves us beyond imagining. Only so can we rest in him, completely and comprehensively, and have this peace that defies circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He breaks the bow and shatters the spear;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be still, and know that I am God; I will be exalted among the nations, I will be exalted in the earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;v9, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem that the world is out of control, but this is illusory and temporary.  Ultimately, God will be exalted in all the earth. In such times as these, we must be still, and in the stillness we can know this, with certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be still, and know that he is God, Amy, and grow in tranquility in the soul! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Patience in affliction</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-affliction/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-affliction/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-affliction/zac-durant-_6HzPU9Hyfg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Patience in affliction" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any more to patience than waiting well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/&lt;br&gt;
▸ noun [mass noun]&lt;br&gt;
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Oxford Dictionary of English&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There most certainly is! What of patience in affliction then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job is an interesting book. Mostly we find mysteries are revealed at the end of a story, but with Job that is not so. There is no explanation when the Lord finally appears. We could summarise Job 38-42 like this: “I am the LORD Most High, Creator of Heaven and Earth. Who are you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explanation rather is where the story begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Satan, “Have you considered my servant Job? There is no one on earth like him; he is blameless and upright, a man who fears God and shuns evil.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Does Job fear God for nothing?” Satan replied.  “Have you not put a hedge around him and his household and everything he has? You have blessed the work of his hands, so that his flocks and herds are spread throughout the land. But stretch out your hand and strike everything he has, and he will surely curse you to your face.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 1:8-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apostle Peter takes this principle and expands upon it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For a little while you may have had to suffer grief in all kinds of trials. These have come so that your faith &amp;hellip; may be proved genuine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we truly grasp this, it empowers us to respond with patience in affliction. How else can I show the Lord that my love for him is real and not merely cupboard love, that my trust is absolute, and my faith genuine? I rejoice when I find that I can do these things! And I am mindful that this is a heart-work of the Holy Spirit. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; patience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be patient in affliction, Amy, and show the Lord that your faith is genuine! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Patience in waiting</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-waiting/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-waiting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/patience-in-waiting/pavlenko-8BNO4HUQYRw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Patience in waiting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we grow in patience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; patience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dictionary defines patience like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;patience /ˈpeɪʃ(ə)ns/&lt;br&gt;
▸ noun [mass noun]&lt;br&gt;
the capacity to accept or tolerate delay, problems, or suffering without becoming annoyed or anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Oxford Dictionary of English&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on delay for now. So, how can we grow in patience in the face of delay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m asking an easy question! We grow in this patience by having to wait, and by learning to wait well. But actually waiting well is anything but easy. It is the hardest thing. And it&amp;rsquo;s harder still when we can&amp;rsquo;t understand why. Why the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to consider those who waited before us. Like Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a miraculous escape from being drowned at birth, Moses had a privileged upbringing, growing up in the royal palace of Egypt, learning leadership and what it meant to rule.  As a gifted and highly capable forty year old, he thought he was ready to lead his people out of slavery. The Lord had other plans! Moses spent the next forty years tending sheep in the wilderness. We can wonder how long it took him to come to terms with that! I&amp;rsquo;m sure he spent quite some time raging against the apparent pointlessness of his life. But what was the result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now Moses was a very humble man, more humble than anyone else on the face of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Numbers 12:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During those forty years the Lord wrought some fundamental changes in Moses&#39; heart. Where else did that humility come from? In that waiting time, Moses had been completely transformed, and was finally ready to be used by the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting may feel like death, but in fact it can be a path to abundant life, to the mother lode of spiritual blessing and joy. It is a powerful agency of the Lord to change our heart and grow each one of us into someone who can be of some use in the Kingdom. If we can notice this happening in ourselves as it unfolds, that may help us to wait with patience, and to wait well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to wait well, Amy, and grow in patience! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Gentleness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/gentleness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/gentleness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/gentleness/david-clode-13PjNBaDMcg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Gentleness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most Christlike response we can give to an angry, frustrated, hostile, hurting world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is &amp;hellip; gentleness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to note about the fruit of the Spirit is that there is only one fruit (“the fruit of the Spirit &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip;”), and that fruit has nine characteristics. I may take nine weeks over this, let&amp;rsquo;s see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But gentleness? Why do I start here? Let&amp;rsquo;s notice what Paul wrote to Timothy, his final urging in his first letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But you, man of God, flee from all this [false teaching and the love of money], and pursue righteousness, godliness, faith, love, endurance and gentleness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 6:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy, still young, was just starting out in ministry, but was already held in high regard by Paul, who was particularly fond of him (1 Cor 4:17, 2 Tim 1:2, Phil 2:20-22). What would we write to such a one? If we&amp;rsquo;re honest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem a little surprising to see gentleness in that list of other more obvious qualities? It must be more important than we thought!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, in his final exhortations to the Philippians:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice! Let your gentleness be evident to all. The Lord is near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord is near, and what is the thing that really matters (besides rejoicing)? Our &lt;em&gt;gentleness&lt;/em&gt;. We see this in Jesus himself. How prominently is his gentleness described, both in prophecy, and by and of himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rejoice greatly, O Daughter of Zion! Shout, Daughter of Jerusalem! See, your king comes to you, righteous and having salvation, gentle and riding on a donkey, on a colt, the foal of a donkey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zechariah 9:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A bruised reed he will not break, and a smouldering wick he will not snuff out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 42:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Come to me, all you who are weary and burdened, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you and learn from me, for I am gentle and humble in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. For my yoke is easy and my burden is light.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 11:28-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In gentleness and humility, Jesus offers a haven for the weary and burdened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the pressure cooker of this life, Amy, live with the gentleness of Christ! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The rescued life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-rescued-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 06:28:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-rescued-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-rescued-life/kyle-cottrell-QGSD-bfJHIw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The rescued life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference does it make to have been rescued?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycling back from Karitane on Sunday afternoon, I saw my neighbours walking up the hill and stopped to say hello. They asked about the awful thing that happened to me in Rarotonga. Word evidently gets around! Instead I told them about the wonderful, impossible thing which happened, which resulted in me being alive and not dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found myself saying, “every day feels like a bonus now.” And so it is. But this principle applies equally to the original rescue, the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saved each one of us from our sin and brought us into relationship with our Heavenly Father in the first place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live as those rescued? We need to understand what has changed, and so experience each waking moment as a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are not your own; you were bought at a price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 6:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rescue changes everything! Recognizing that we now belong to the one who rescued us and our lives are no longer our own, may we surrender joyfully to the Holy Spirit, live as slaves to righteousness, and know the complete life-transformation that brings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness and self-control. Against such things there is no law. Those who belong to Christ Jesus have crucified the sinful nature with its passions and desires. Since we live by the Spirit, let us keep in step with the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This crucifying of the sinful nature sounds like a one-time thing, but is in fact a lifelong journey. May we travel it with grateful hearts, never forgetting the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in step with the Spirit, Amy, and continue to live as one rescued! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Radiant disciples</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/radiant-disciples/autumn-goodman-vTL_qy03D1I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Radiant disciples" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t look at the sun, it&amp;rsquo;s far too bright. Any attempt even to look nearby overloads our retina, so all else fades into nothing. And so it is with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the source of the radiance. Ours is merely a reflection, unlikely to cause blindness, but bright and shining nonetheless, and enormously attractive to those who don&amp;rsquo;t have it. How does this work, then? We must consider how to be those who &lt;em&gt;look to him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with forgiveness—&lt;em&gt;their faces are never covered with shame&lt;/em&gt;. All is forgiven, all debt is cancelled and all shame is gone. This is the glorious truth that underpins everything we are as children of God. Rejoice in that forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues with hope. As we look to the Lord, we look with the hope that notwithstanding all that we have already received, his work in us is not yet complete. There&amp;rsquo;s more to come, and what is to come is so certain and so very good, and so much more than we could possibly ask or imagine. This is our source of joy, our source of radiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we love the Lord, with a grateful heart that magnifies that love, and irrepressible hope that fuels it with tremendous power. When someone is in love, absolutely captivated, they have a glow about them, evidenced in shining eyes and wonder. This is powerful and joyous, and others desire it. May we know this as we look to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him, Amy, bask in his glory which shines like the sun in all its brilliance, and be radiant! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Rescue</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/rescue/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/rescue/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/rescue/axel-antas-bergkvist-zrSzqDnfkQ8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Rescue" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times will the Lord rescue? Isn&amp;rsquo;t once enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 91:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, my Bible actually says this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But gender is of no consequence here. What matters is this: the pronoun is singular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some think the only rescue is the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saves us from our sin and brings us into relationship with our Heavenly Father, but that&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning. Notice this: “Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”.  This is someone who is &lt;em&gt;already in relationship&lt;/em&gt;. The rescue is ongoing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fourth of July this year should have been the last day of my life. I was in Rarotonga, in a kayak, in a place I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been on that monster-surf day, caught in a rip in the Avaavaroa Passage. The waves were pounding on the exposed reef, and after ten minutes, two capsizes, and exhaustion, I knew I was going to die. I cried out to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge wave rolled in, picked me up, and carried me on the boiling white-water all the way to the inside, a hundred metres or so, to the calm water in the lagoon, with the only thought in my head being, “Why am I not capsizing? This is impossible!” And it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been a silly boy, but there was no judgement from the Lord. All I received was this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is, regardless of whether the crisis is quite so acute as was mine, quite so physical. Perhaps the one is in community, well regarded, serving the Lord. But nevertheless captive. Oppressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, Amy, the rescue is ongoing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Taste and see that the Lord is good</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/joyful-vT5xrj3z1OE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taste and see that the Lord is good" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we obey a command if we don&amp;rsquo;t know what it means?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously we can&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s a rhetorical question. What of this then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Taste and see that the LORD is good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is clearly an instruction to do something. It&amp;rsquo;s a command. Notice that David could have written, Behold! The Lord is good (because he is). That&amp;rsquo;s a true statement, but it&amp;rsquo;s not what he wrote. What he wrote, rather, is something we are commanded to do. Taste! And see! Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasting is an action. There is something to do. Physically, we put food in our mouths and chew on it. As an aside, how gracious of the Lord to make this a pleasurable experience. We are really just refueling our bodies. Who else would have decided to make that something to enjoy? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s character is revealed even in this, that he found yet another way to bless us, his beloved. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us some insight. We experience the goodness of God as a result of taking some action. What action is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that more than any other the word that appears alongside the goodness of God throughout scripture is &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt;, that those who would see his goodness must trust, in his unfailing love, in his mercy, in all he is and all he has done. Grab a concordance and see for yourself! This very verse continues “blessed is the one who takes refuge in him”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we would taste and see, we must then &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;depend&lt;/em&gt;. This makes sense. When we fully commit to depending on the Lord, such that we are not trying to control our own outcome, only then may we see the goodness of God, because only then have we left him space in which to show us that goodness. As we relinquish control over our own lives, may we learn to chew on and genuinely savour the goodness of God that he reveals to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust and depend, Amy, taste and see, and leave the Lord space to show you his goodness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unanswered prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/unanswered-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:31:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/unanswered-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/unanswered-prayer/sasha-freemind-nXo2ZsKHTHg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Unanswered prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we relate to our Heavenly Father when he leaves our most earnest and desperate prayers unanswered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[Jesus said] “Ask and it will be given to you &amp;hellip; how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7, 11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But unanswered prayer is a real thing. How can we deal with it? Many have grappled with this, and much has been written. Some have said, the Lord always answers prayer: sometimes yes; sometimes no; sometimes not yet. I find this glib and unhelpful. Because sometimes there is silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a husband and father, let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mark, a faithful servant of the Lord, suffering with severe health issues for so many years, for whom we have been faithfully, earnestly praying, confident that the Lord hears and is powerful to heal. Except he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, and this man dies, leaving his grieving wife, Grace, and their eight-year-old son, Callum. And from the Lord, only silence. What kind of answer to prayer is that? How is that a reasonable response to desperate prayers offered from a broken heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another way to see this. Unanswered prayer is an &lt;em&gt;invitation into relationship&lt;/em&gt;. An invitation into intimacy. How does this work? Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Why did Mark have to die? Don&amp;rsquo;t you care?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you have done something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “He loved you, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? Did you love him? You did love him, didn&amp;rsquo;t you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;silence, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Yes, Amy, I loved him. I love him still.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You:&lt;/strong&gt; “What about Grace and little Callum? This is breaking my heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;long pause, then,&lt;/em&gt; “Mine too, Amy. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit together for a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;intimate, healing silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father grieves over his broken world, and the suffering his people bear. Let&amp;rsquo;s sit with him, and grieve also, in the intimacy of his healing presence. And in the meantime,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us. For the creation waits in eager expectation for the children of God to be revealed. For the creation was subjected to frustration, not by its own choice, but by the will of the one who subjected it, in hope that the creation itself will be liberated from its bondage to decay and brought into the freedom and glory of the children of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:18-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sit with the Lord in the silence of the unanswered prayer, Amy, in the intimacy of his healing presence 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-deposit-guaranteeing-our-inheritance/ishan-seefromthesky-2d7n2sfYjHY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know for sure that all we are hoping for in eternity is real, and that it will be as promised?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m just about ready to leave this desert island, and I see a boat on the horizon (yay!), but first let&amp;rsquo;s look into Ephesians 1 for one last time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession — to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some really significant points to note here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we in or out? We have been &lt;em&gt;included&lt;/em&gt;. Most assuredly in! And not on our own merit, as if anyone could come along later and say, there&amp;rsquo;s been some mistake. No, we have been included &lt;em&gt;in Christ&lt;/em&gt;. The power and the glory are his, and we are included, in him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have been &lt;em&gt;marked in him with a seal&lt;/em&gt;. When a legal contract used to be signed, both parties would sign and apply a wax seal with the impression of a signet ring, as authentication. The Holy Spirit authenticates us as children of God, the genuine article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Holy Spirit is a &lt;em&gt;deposit&lt;/em&gt;, that is part of the greater whole which is to follow, paid immediately, as a foretaste. There is more to come!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The deposit is a &lt;em&gt;guarantee&lt;/em&gt; of what is to come. What is to come is a certainty, and cannot be revoked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is guaranteed is &lt;em&gt;our inheritance&lt;/em&gt;. If we are children, then we are heirs — heirs of God and co-heirs with Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are &lt;em&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s possession&lt;/em&gt;, bought with a price, and he will never give us up. I am his and he is mine, forever. You too, Amy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prize is our &lt;em&gt;redemption&lt;/em&gt;, which is already accomplished, but not yet complete. One day it will be so, and we will shed off all that tires us out and drags us down. How I long for that day!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Spirit living in us not only proves our adoption by the Lord, but gives us power to live victoriously, a foretaste of what is certain, of what is promised and true. A deposit guaranteeing our inheritance! Now we can truly say this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Praise be to the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praise him, Amy, for such blessing as this! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A mystery revealed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-mystery-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 06:38:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-mystery-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/a-mystery-revealed/david-clode-EDfZ0Sjmp_w-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A mystery revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know a mystery?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God’s grace that he lavished on us. With all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will according to his good pleasure, which he purposed in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an alternate reality, the Lord could have dealt with our sin as he did, and simply told us, it&amp;rsquo;s ok, we can be friends again, I&amp;rsquo;ve sorted it out. But in our reality, &lt;em&gt;with all wisdom and understanding, he made known to us the mystery of his will&lt;/em&gt;. He desires us to know just what our rescue cost him, and what it cost his only son, as he lavished his grace on us. As he continues to lavish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have redemption &lt;em&gt;through his blood&lt;/em&gt;. The cost was enormous. The love that paid this price, unfathomable. The forgiveness of sins and restoration of relationship with our Heavenly Father, beyond all worth. And the revelation of this mystery, according to his good pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we understand what has been done for us, and why? The Lord desires that we do. If we really grasp this, won&amp;rsquo;t it magnify our love for him a hundredfold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know the mystery, Amy, and love the author of the mystery who has made it known! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The eyes of your heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:31:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-eyes-of-your-heart/javardh-FC59Au36moM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The eyes of your heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the eyes of our heart for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still stuck on this desert island, reading Ephesians 1. It is not a bad place to be! Consider what Paul writes about the eyes of our heart. (The heart is the seat of life and strength, the centre of one&amp;rsquo;s will. That is mind, soul, spirit, one&amp;rsquo;s entire emotional nature and understanding.)  Paul writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I pray also that the eyes of your heart may be enlightened in order that you may know the hope to which he has called you, the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and his incomparably great power for us who believe. That power is like the working of his mighty strength, which he exerted in Christ when he raised him from the dead and seated him at his right hand in the heavenly realms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a prayer. Paul asks for enlightening of the eyes of our heart. We must ask for this thing that otherwise we may miss. Notice that what the enlightened eyes of our heart do is to &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;. Merely seeing is curiosity. Knowing is life-changing. What is there to know? Three things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope. My dictionary defines hope as grounds for believing that something good may happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not wishful thinking, there are actual grounds for believing this. In our context, “something good” is understated, to say the least! May the enlightened eyes of our heart know the best thing that could possibly happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our glorious inheritance in the saints. What is this? In v3 Paul writes that the Lord “has blessed us in the heavenly realms with every spiritual blessing in Christ”. Note the tense. Something has already happened! But what of the rest? The prophetic past tense is used throughout scripture where a future event is so certain it is written as if it had already occurred. The fulfillment of our future blessing in the heavenly realms is that certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His incomparably great power for us. This is the same power that raised Christ from the dead. It is not a small thing, and it is at work in us who believe! When we feel overwhelmed or empty, and so aware of our need for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and grace, perhaps his mighty strength which raised Christ from the dead will be enough. We must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the eyes of your heart be enlightened, Amy, in order that you may know, really know, these life changing things. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Predestination</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/predestination/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/predestination/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/predestination/saiph-muhammad-CSs8aiN_LkI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Predestination" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s all this about predestination? Don&amp;rsquo;t people have a right to choose for themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I swing in my hammock on that desert island, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do except read Ephesians 1. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He chose us in him before the creation of the world to be holy and blameless in his sight. In love he predestined us to be adopted as his children through Jesus Christ, in accordance with his pleasure and will (v4, 5) &amp;hellip; In him we were also chosen, having been predestined according to the plan of him who works out everything in conformity with the purpose of his will, in order that we, who were the first to hope in Christ, might be for the praise of his glory (v11, 12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no escaping that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s choice, rather than mine. And that is a wonderful thing. The Lord, the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, does not make mistakes. He chose me. He chose you, Amy, in accordance with his pleasure and will. As for me, I make mistakes, and my own choices are always subject to suspicion and doubt. Not so the Lord! His plans and purposes prevail, for the praise of his glory. I, you, we are both his, forever, and no mistake! And thus we have assurance of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. He chose us to be holy and blameless in his sight. Partly that is an instantaneous, Jesus-died-for-my sins-and-now-I-am-counted-righteous thing. And partly it is a rest-of-my-life thing, as the Holy Spirit continues both to convict me and to empower me to change, as I surrender my will on the pathway to holiness. Both are life-giving, lavish gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what of evangelism? If people are chosen, where is repentance and belief? See what comes next in the passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you also were included in Christ when you heard the message of truth, the gospel of your salvation. When you believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God’s possession — to the praise of his glory (v13, 14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those to whom Paul writes &lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; the message of truth (because someone told them), and &lt;em&gt;believed&lt;/em&gt;. Predestination does not diminish the gospel message in any way. There is undeniably mystery here, but the greatest evangelist of all time was surely &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Paul himself&lt;/em&gt;, who wrote these words. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, and he is yours, forever, because he chose you in him before the creation of the world. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Desert island</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/desert-island/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 06:43:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/desert-island/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/desert-island/pablo-garcia-saldana-K1YRblz-rD0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Desert island" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could take only one chapter of the Bible with you to a desert island, which would you choose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, my pick would be Ephesians Chapter One. I cannot possibly do the whole chapter justice in this short letter, so for now let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one verse. (I may have to return to the wider chapter another time. Perhaps several times!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I keep asking that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the glorious Father, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and revelation, so that you &amp;hellip; ” (v17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you complete that prayer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; may be able to make good choices in your life? &amp;hellip; may be able to discern his will for you? &amp;hellip; may be able to better understand what is happening around you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, none of these! Paul asks this of the Lord so that you “&amp;hellip; may know him better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That you may know the Lord better! This is what the Spirit of wisdom and revelation is for. That I may know him better. To know and be known, this is the ultimate in relationship. But how can we possibly know the infinite, everlasting, majestic God, creator of the ends of the earth, of the universe? It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to know such a one, surely, with our finite minds, with our sinful hearts. And yet, the Spirit of wisdom and revelation makes the impossible, possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we marvel at this, let us notice that this is not a small thing Paul asks for. He &lt;em&gt;keeps asking&lt;/em&gt;, persisting in prayer for the stuff that really matters. Keep asking, Amy, for the stuff that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one he keeps asking is God, the glorious Father. He is glorious, and it is glorious that he is our father. He is the source of all that is good, and he is kind and generous beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the glorious Father, give you the Spirit of wisdom and revelation, Amy, so that you may know him better! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Faith that changes the course of nations</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/faith-that-changes-the-course-of-nations/vladislav-klapin-YeO44yVTl20-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Faith that changes the course of nations" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does faith that changes the course of nations look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see something of it in the story of Naaman, in 2 Kings 5. The Lord had given victory to Syria through Naaman, the commander of the Syrian army (v1, how interesting), who suffered from leprosy. Previously, the Syrians had taken captives from Israel, and among them was a young girl, now a slave in the house of Naaman (v2). Not even named, and yet her faith makes her the hero of this story.  How would you expect a young girl, captive in a foreign land, to live? Not like this, surely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said to her mistress, “If only my master would see the prophet who is in Samaria! He would cure him of his leprosy” (v3).  Talk about not playing it safe and keeping your head down! What can we learn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She was simply and humbly living her life, a slave in Naaman&amp;rsquo;s house, with no resentment or discontent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She had a generous heart, wishing good and not harm upon her captors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She had such a conviction that through Elisha the Lord would heal Naaman the commander of the army of a hostile nation, that she was prepared to put herself on the line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did she speak out like this? What trouble would have come her way if there had not been a miraculous healing? Certainly the king of Israel himself expected the outcome to be conflict between nations (v7). Her faith is ridiculous. And so she is the reason that a pagan general&amp;rsquo;s life is turned around, he becomes a worshipper of the Lord, and takes his faith back to a pagan land, into the royal palace, no less (v18).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to conclude that the Lord placed this on her heart, as he does. These were his plans and purposes, and they rested on the faith of a humble slave girl, who otherwise might simply have been living in obscurity. And on her obedience, oh my! Risk-taking, reckless obedience, to the one who is faithful beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with a faith that changes the course of nations, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Greetings</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/greetings/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/greetings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/greetings/church-of-the-king-j9jZSqfH5YI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Greetings" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in a greeting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, who is loved by God and called to be one of the saints (Rom 1:7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, sanctified in Christ Jesus and called to be holy (1 Cor 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, one of the faithful in Christ Jesus (Eph 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, one of the saints in Christ Jesus (Phil 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, a faithful sister in Christ (Col 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy in God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ (1 Thes 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy my true daughter in the faith (1 Tim 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, my dear daughter (2 Tim 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy our dear friend and fellow worker (Philemon 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, a stranger in the world, one of God’s elect scattered throughout the provinces of Papua New Guinea, chosen according to the foreknowledge of God the Father, through the sanctifying work of the Spirit, for obedience to Jesus Christ and sprinkling by his blood (1 Peter 1:1-2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, who through the righteousness of our God and Saviour Jesus Christ has received a faith as precious as ours (2 Peter 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, who has been called, who is loved by God the Father and kept by Jesus Christ (Jude v1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a lot, it seems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive the truth and love in these greetings, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Receiving the kingdom of God like a little child</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/joice-kelly-38MGlMtsZyc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Receiving the kingdom of God like a little child" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to receive the kingdom of God like a little child?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a vital question!  Jesus himself said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, anyone who will not receive the kingdom of God like a little child will never enter it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must fathom this then!  Let&amp;rsquo;s consider three aspects of a little child&amp;rsquo;s relationship with their earthly parents, and infer how to receive from our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the little child trusts, absolutely. When the parent says it is so, or tells of something they will do, the child never doubts for a moment. The child wastes no energy at all worrying about it. They count on it, as if it were already so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the little child depends, completely. In fact their life makes no sense unless the parent provides, protects, cares, loves. They are wholly dependent. It is the very nature of the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, have you ever observed a little child anticipating something to come, something wonderful, like Christmas? They are so excited! The expectation can be almost too much to bear. And as the event approaches, the excitement grows, contagiously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us receive the kingdom of God like this. Our Heavenly Father is utterly reliable, and so very good. We can wholly lean on him, fully committed. He loves us deeply, has promised so much, and is able to do immeasurably more than all we ask or imagine. Could anything be more exciting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust, depend, and be excited, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The thorn in Paul&#39;s flesh</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-thorn-in-pauls-flesh/jacqueline-day-krUUaZ4GvHk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The thorn in Paul&#39;s flesh" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly was Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn anyway, and why does it matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been much speculation about the nature of Paul&amp;rsquo;s thorn in the flesh (2 Cor 12:7-9), and of course we do not know.  Personally, I doubt it was any disability, of speech or of stature, nor any severe pain to endure. Rather I suspect it was something utterly shameful and humiliating, perhaps something in his own character. Something internal and deeply personal. Why do I think this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every other respect, Paul was the elite. Highly educated. Highly disciplined. Highly capable. Zealous. Purging every sin and making every effort to live a right life (Acts 22:3, Phil 3:4-6). These are not attributes that lead to humility! They are more likely to lead to arrogance, to smug self-satisfaction, to a sense of moral superiority. How can such a one be depending completely on the Lord, and be of any use in the Kingdom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul rather was able to live with so much humility and dependence on the Lord &lt;em&gt;because of this&lt;/em&gt; (“in order to keep me from becoming conceited”, 2 Cor 12:7), being able to say, “Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners — of whom I am the worst” (1 Tim 1:15). And to live with boldness. Such boldness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the shame of my past comes back to haunt me, to crush me, I do not deny it. I must not. The Lord lifts me, welcomes me, saves me, accepts me. Oh how I need him! I am not condemned. But in the rescue and the redemption, all pride is gone. My grateful heart loves the Lord, and seeks to honour him. And so I can live with levels of humility, gentleness and compassion which eluded me previously. The Lord is glorified, and I am diminished. I can die to self, and live for him, holding nothing back. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the rescue, Amy, whatever form it takes! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Throwing a mountain into the sea</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:36:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/throwing-a-mountain-into-the-sea/sulthan-auliya-WLORfDtl7oM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Throwing a mountain into the sea" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we throw a mountain into the sea?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a ridiculous question! It&amp;rsquo;s clearly impossible. And yet, Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would Jesus say such a thing? Is he mocking us? Is he exaggerating? Is he lying, even?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone tells us something that is hard to accept, how we receive it depends critically on who they are, and what we know of them. Can we trust? And what reason do we have for that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many years, I have learnt that I can trust Jesus absolutely. I&amp;rsquo;m quite a slow learner, and have doubted in various ways for so much of my life, but no longer. I choose therefore to believe that Jesus was telling the truth when he said this impossible thing. What do I make of it then? I have to relate it to other things I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said a similar thing to his disciples at the Last Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You may ask me for anything in my name, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here we have the caveat, “in my name”. I can only ask for something in Jesus&#39; name if he would have asked for the same. That&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful guideline for praying in power, and it defines my own expectation in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I choose to believe Jesus. I can&amp;rsquo;t throw a mountain into the sea, only because I cannot escape my own doubt about that. I acknowledge that as the reason. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t doubt, it would be so. That is on me. Jesus is trustworthy and true, and he speaks truth. And there are so many other things I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; pray for, believing, not doubting. Impossible things, even. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray in power, Amy, believing and not doubting! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hard teaching</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/hard-teaching/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 06:39:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/hard-teaching/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/hard-teaching/maranda-vandergriff-9mqdPNk2Xwc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hard teaching" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain passages or verses in the Bible are really hard to understand. How should we approach them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intention this week was to write about telling a mountain to throw itself into the sea, not doubting. But when I looked into the context, I found that Jesus said it after cursing the fig tree on approaching Jerusalem for the last week of his life. How do we understand that? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about that first, and I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to the mountain another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The next day as they were leaving Bethany, Jesus was hungry. Seeing in the distance a fig tree in leaf, he went to find out if it had any fruit. When he reached it, he found nothing but leaves, because it was not the season for figs. Then he said to the tree, “May no one ever eat fruit from you again.” And his disciples heard him say it. &amp;hellip; In the morning, as they went along, they saw the fig tree withered from the roots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:12-14, 20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is this reasonable? It was not the season for figs! This seems so harsh. It is certainly hard to understand. What should we do with passages like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we ought not to anthropomorphize the tree. It was just a tree. It served a purpose, to illustrate a teaching point of Jesus. Nobody suffered in the making of this point. But still!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst comment I read about this explained that first fruits appear early, and Jesus would have expected there to be figs for that reason. But Mark would have known that, and would have said, there were no first fruits. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t the reason given! Let us not second guess the gospel writers. The Lord is responsible for his own reputation, and has no need of our defence, no need of our pitiful attempts to make him look good. Let us not brush aside these difficulties with bogus explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was about to suffer and die, for the sins of all humanity. This was God&amp;rsquo;s plan, and it required rejection and brutal treatment of the Son of God by those who should have been fruitful for the Kingdom, but were not. Was the fig tree a symbol of the Jews who rejected Jesus? It was not their season to be fruitful, and they were severely judged. Is this harsh? It is a hard teaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cannot claim perfect understanding of the mysteries of God. But as we grapple, let us do so with intellectual integrity, being faithful to Scripture, and honouring the Lord. And may we continue to love and trust him when the limits of our understanding are exceeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love and trust, Amy, and don&amp;rsquo;t stop grappling! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Expectant and not disappointed</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/expectant-and-not-disappointed/patrick-fore-T2S4CatGdfQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Expectant and not disappointed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we be expectant and not disappointed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living with high expectations of oneself and others is surely right, but can lead to ongoing disappointment, as we and those around us fall short of what we aspired to do and to be. How can the same not be true of the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should we expect of the Lord anyway?  “I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full” (Jn 10:10).   “I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living” (Ps 27:13).  “Truly I tell you, if anyone says to this mountain, ‘Go, throw yourself into the sea,’ and does not doubt in their heart but believes that what they say will happen, it will be done for them” (Mk 11:23).  “Is anyone among you sick? &amp;hellip; the prayer offered in faith will make the sick person well; the Lord will raise them up” (Jam 5:14-15).  “Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him” (Ps 91:14).  “You know with all your heart and soul that not one of all the good promises the LORD your God gave you has failed. Every promise has been fulfilled; not one has failed” (Josh 23:14).  “I am the LORD, the God of all mankind. Is anything too hard for me?” (Jer 32:27).  How are we not just setting ourselves up for disappointment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However we deal with this, we must never lower our expectation of the Lord. He is the Creator, Almighty, Sovereign Lord, infinite in power and wisdom. He loves us his children absolutely, and he blesses us richly and without bounds. May we never doubt that!  And may we never limit our praying to what seems reasonable. If someone is sick, shame on me if I pray merely for their comfort rather than for miraculous healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To live with such expectation makes me so vulnerable, though. Vulnerable to disappointment. Vulnerable to the scorn of the sceptics. Vulnerable and defenceless. How can my faith survive this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that Abraham was strengthened in his faith (Rom 4:20). It is a work of the Lord. I commit completely, in faith, trusting. The Lord defends me.  It is miraculous grace.  The heartache may remain as I wait, in that amalgam of joy and pain which characterises the Christian life as we engage with the Lord&amp;rsquo;s work in this broken world. But disappointment does not crush me, does not crush my faith. How does this work? It is a mystery, a wondrous gift of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my, I seem to have written another tome. Good job I do this only once a week, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lean on him, trust him for his impossible promises, and praise him for his miraculous grace, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-in-the-lords-love/melissa-askew-8n00CqwnqO8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently in the Lord&#39;s love" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 27 pretty much has it all. Here are the highlights.  “The LORD is my light and my salvation &amp;hellip; the stronghold of my life (v1). One thing I ask from the LORD &amp;hellip; that I may dwell in the house of the LORD all the days of my life (v4). He will keep me safe in his dwelling &amp;hellip; and set me high upon a rock (v5). Your face, LORD, I will seek (v8).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantly reminding ourselves of these things, and living them every day, every moment, is part of it. But then out of the blue comes v9, which suddenly expresses doubt and fear of rejection.  “Do not hide your face from me, do not turn your servant away in anger; you have been my helper. Do not reject me or forsake me, God my Saviour.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such sentiments occur throughout the Psalms, and this by the grace of God. Let&amp;rsquo;s try to understand why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s wisdom is beyond understanding, let&amp;rsquo;s first acknowledge that. He has plans and purposes, and they are good. He desires us to walk by faith, to trust him absolutely, and he loves us, ruthlessly. That&amp;rsquo;s an uncomfortable word! The walk of faith is not comfortable, nor should we expect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while it can feel, at times overwhelmingly, like he has turned his face away and rejected us, he has not. He alone knows what he is doing, and he is deeply invested in us. That rejection is what Jesus received on the cross, so we never have to. And that is why we can assert with the Psalmist, “I remain confident of this: I will see the goodness of the LORD in the land of the living.” (v13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we live confidently? “Wait for the LORD; be strong and take heart and wait for the LORD.” (v14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be strong and take heart and wait for the Lord, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What does the Lord want us to do?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 06:51:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/robert-nyman--ysyCHixMHU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What does the Lord want us to do?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the Lord want us to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely there must be some special work that he&amp;rsquo;s calling us to. Something that we have to carefully and prayerfully uncover, so we can live the life he has planned, and do the work he has for us. Surely?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was once asked exactly this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What must we do to do the works God requires?”  Jesus answered, “The work of God is this: to believe in the one he has sent.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 6:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a little enigmatic, don&amp;rsquo;t you think? Or is it? Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s actually really straightforward! What would that look like? To believe in the one the Lord has sent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus, the very Son of God, came to rescue us. From sin, and shame, and failure, and all that drags us down. From the sin that separated us from the Father. He loves us so much, that he did this completely and comprehensively, and at what cost!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to really believe in him.  I am loved. I am rescued. I am free. No doubt. No fear. No shame. Only love. By our Father, and for our Father.  All that remains is to live in that love. In him, and through him, and for him, forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like you&amp;rsquo;re loved, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The heavens declare the glory of God</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 06:26:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-heavens-declare-the-glory-of-god/martin-jernberg-UdURxHDhrgY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The heavens declare the glory of God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 19 starts like this. The heavens declare the glory of God; the skies proclaim the work of his hands. Day after day they pour forth speech; night after night they display knowledge. There is no speech or language where their voice is not heard. Their voice goes out into all the earth, their words to the ends of the world. (And it continues with real soul food.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole of creation bears witness to the glory and majesty of the Lord!  Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is indeed awe and wonder to be found in the night sky. As a Northerner, however, from where I live now it is quite unsettling to see Orion doing a hand stand. I wonder how he behaves on the equator. 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems appropriate therefore to turn these verses upside down. So my prayer is that you experience the Lord revealing himself to you in the small things too. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Experiencing grace</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/experiencing-grace/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 06:32:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/experiencing-grace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/experiencing-grace/denise-jans-IJy2ZUex0-Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Experiencing grace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we better perceive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s grace in all we experience, and what would that mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is full of frustrations and disappointments. Even for the Christian seeking the Lord with all of our heart, living a surrendered life, putting him first in everything, things may not turn out as we would have wished. And that&amp;rsquo;s not just small things. The whole course of one&amp;rsquo;s life could turn out to be so different from what was desired. Where is our loving Heavenly Father in this? Does he not want to bless his children? Absolutely he does! So what is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote to the Romans this oft-quoted verse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And we know that in all things God works for the good of those who love him, who have been called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider that in the context of Solomon&amp;rsquo;s wisdom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In his heart a man plans his course, but the LORD determines his steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 16:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has hopes and desires for their own life. Some may be sufficiently well organised to have a plan! But the Lord determines their steps. It is his plans and purposes that prevail. Let us not delude ourselves that we can control our own destiny, and somehow plan our way there. That is for the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to dispel a misconception. Paul is not saying that everything that happens is good and is caused by God. That is observably false — terrible things do happen. Rather he is saying that whatever happens, God works in it and through it “for the good of those who love him”. Let us be those!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us learn to see the world through the lens of Romans 8:28 as it actually is then. May we consciously receive God&amp;rsquo;s grace in all that happens. “In all things” let us submit to his superior wisdom, knowing that there is no better eternal outcome than the one he has for us. When apparent disappointments come, let us receive them with a grateful heart. The Lord has seen things that we have not. His love is unfailing. He may very well be rescuing us from something we thought was better, but is in fact not.  He is the one who determines our steps, and it is very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive his grace with a grateful heart in all things, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Walking by faith</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 06:52:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/walking-by-faith/jimmy-larry-7uvixXrQkfw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Walking by faith" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when we walk by faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest example we have is Abraham. He didn&amp;rsquo;t always get it right, nor did he manage always to trust, as shown by his shabby little misdeed with Hagar. Evidently not super-human then! But the Lord called him again out of that particular failure thirteen years later, out of the absolute mess he had made (“walk before me and be blameless” - Gen 17:1), after he had been waiting for the fulfillment of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promise to him for 25 years. Twenty-five years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul&amp;rsquo;s account in Romans 4 manages to overlook Abraham&amp;rsquo;s shameful failure (oh the grace of God!), and we find this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yet Abraham did not waver through unbelief regarding the promise of God, but was strengthened in his faith and gave glory to God, being fully persuaded that God had power to do what he had promised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 4:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He believed again, and walked by faith. What then happened? He was strengthened in his faith. Notice what happened here. He believed. He exercised faith. Just enough. Perhaps barely enough, but enough all the same. And the Lord strengthened him in that faith. And it was God who was thus glorified, not Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most striking consequence is found just before this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Against all hope, Abraham in hope believed and so became the father of many nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 4:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that little word, so. What was the reason Abraham became the father of many nations? Because he believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we walk by faith, God fulfills his plans and purposes in us and through us. There is a causal link. What more motivation could we have than this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on walking by faith, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living confidently when the future is uncertain</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/living-confidently-when-the-future-is-uncertain/arthur-ogleznev-rWDumHFt8E8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Living confidently when the future is uncertain" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we live confidently when the future is uncertain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things we would like to know. What will I do with my life? Will it be worthwhile? How will I live? Will I be able to use the talents God has given me for his glory? Where will I go? Is my soul mate out there somewhere? Will I be alone? How can I know I will be ok? Why won&amp;rsquo;t God tell me these things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the Lord does not tell us such things ahead of time, and nor should we expect it. If he does reveal something, as he occasionally does, even an incredible and specific promise, it is unlikely to be how or when. What is my part then? What must I do? I must trust him, and I must live for him with my whole heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the first thing I wrote to you Amy, back in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By choosing to trust, to walk by faith, with all of our hope in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s unfailing love, we can delight him. I will say it again. We can delight him! Without uncertainty there can be no faith, so let us embrace it, and show the Lord that we really can walk by faith. What an opportunity to show him that! There is no risk, really. Read Psalm 145 again, and believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delight him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>On being vulnerable</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/on-being-vulnerable/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/on-being-vulnerable/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/on-being-vulnerable/vitaliy-zalishchyker-3Ank_q_qVtE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post On being vulnerable" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it so important to be vulnerable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our every instinct is to protect and defend, to justify ourselves, and yet we must not do it!  Why is this?  Paul wrote to the Corinthians about his vision and the thorn in his flesh, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Lord said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly about my weaknesses, so that Christ’s power may rest on me &amp;hellip; I delight in weaknesses &amp;hellip; for when I am weak, then I am strong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 12:9, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am judged, even when the judgement is as ignorant as it is harsh, I choose not to defend myself. How easy is it to do this? It is the hardest thing! It is dying to self. (But, my integrity is not defined by what others think of me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reputation is the idol of our age, both within and without the church, maybe the greatest barrier to the gospel, to the transforming power of the Holy Spirit, and to us honouring the Lord with our whole lives. Here are the four most oppressive words, that empty us of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and make us utterly useless for him: &lt;em&gt;what will they think?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will they think of me? I choose not to care! And here is the reason to be vulnerable, to not care about this. Suddenly I can share the gospel with great power, and absolute confidence. I am invincible, because what defines me is unassailable! (2 Cor 5:17, Col 3:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Let me reach down from my pedestal of perfection and set you on the right path, O hapless misguided sinner.” No! No! No! A hundred times no! That is the way of the Pharisee, and the Lord is not in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather, “Let me tell you of the one who rescued me”, risking the contemptuous, sneering reply, “What? Did you need to be rescued?” Yes, I did. I was rescued, am being rescued, will be rescued. It is ongoing, and I am unashamed. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be vulnerable and unashamed, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Pharisaical heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-pharisaical-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 06:46:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-pharisaical-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-pharisaical-heart/tamara-gore-P4mxBJtINCw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Pharisaical heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What breaks our Father&amp;rsquo;s heart? That would be a long list to be sure. I&amp;rsquo;ll pick one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I got to see Les Misérables at the Regent. What a tremendous story of redemption, the power of love flowing through a redeemed life, and the triumph of love over adversity. But also so very sad — I was grateful for the darkness in the theatre, so no-one could see my tears. The saddest song? Some would say I Dreamed a Dream, and that is indeed crushing (“now life has killed the dream I dreamed”), or On My Own, Éponine&amp;rsquo;s song of unrequited love for Marius (“the trees are bare and everywhere the streets are full of strangers”). But there is another: Javert&amp;rsquo;s soliloquy, Stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Javert is the policeman who pursues the protagonist Jean Valjean through the decades, after he breaks parole from a 19 year sentence of slavery for stealing a loaf of bread to feed his starving family. Valjean receives unexpected grace and repents (“I feel my shame inside me like a knife. He told me that I have a soul. How does he know? What spirit comes to move my life? Is there another way to go?”). Thus he begins a sacrificial life of love, but Javert cannot accept this. Stars is his vow to pursue Valjean and never rest until he is again behind bars. He sings, “mine is the way of the Lord” (he is so wrong), and “those who falter and those who fall must pay the price” (wrong again, Javert — Rom 8:1-4, 31-39).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An isolated sad event cannot be a tragedy, no matter how heart-rending, as explained by Educating Rita&amp;rsquo;s teacher. Rather, a tragedy is the long and apparently inescapable trajectory of a life, set in motion by a particular course of events or an attitude of the heart, leading inexorably to one&amp;rsquo;s own destruction. It is the prolonged inevitability which makes it so. Javert eventually takes his own life, the only possible consequence given his Pharisaical heart, hardened over so many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many today live Javert&amp;rsquo;s life, bereft of grace. Each one is a tragedy, and each one breaks our Father&amp;rsquo;s heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love with the Father&amp;rsquo;s love, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Who am I?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/who-am-i/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/who-am-i/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/who-am-i/spencer-tamichi-bjH4uE6iuEo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Who am I?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a vital question that is for any of us. It could take some time to answer! In fact, I have had to revisit it myself in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valiant attempt I know of to grapple with this is by Dietrich Bonhoeffer, a German pastor who was imprisoned in Flossenbürg concentration camp by the Nazis during World War II. He was executed just one month before the end of the war. One month! He wrote the following while incarcerated. Notice that someone we might regard as a giant in the faith did not regard himself like that at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Am I?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They often tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I stepped from my cell&amp;rsquo;s confinement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Calmly, cheerfully, firmly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Like a squire from his country house.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They often tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I used to speak to my warders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Freely and friendly and clearly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As though it were mine to command.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They also tell me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I bore the days of misfortune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Equably, smilingly, proudly,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;like one accustomed to win.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Am I then really that which other men tell of?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Or am I only what I myself know of myself?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Restless and longing and sick, like a bird in a cage,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Struggling for breath, as though hands were compressing my throat,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yearning for colours, for flowers, for the voices of birds,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Thirsting for words of kindness, for neighbourliness,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tossing in expectations of great events,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Powerlessly trembling for friends at an infinite distance,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Weary and empty at praying, at thinking, at making,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Faint, and ready to say farewell to it all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? This or the other?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Am I one person today and tomorrow another?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Am I both at once? A hypocrite before others,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And before myself a contemptible woebegone weakling?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Or is something within me still like a beaten army&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fleeing in disorder from victory already achieved?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who am I? They mock me, these lonely questions of mine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Whoever I am, Thou knowest, O God, I am thine!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What courageously honest words, from someone facing the ultimate test of faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are his, Amy, while you continue to work out the rest 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why is life so hard?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/why-is-life-so-hard/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/why-is-life-so-hard/hugo-jehanne-LOHVrTsdvzY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Why is life so hard?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is life so hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider: the young person, to whom life seems so bleak they turn to self harm to try to anchor to reality; the older person who lives alone, who may go days without speaking with another, having long forgotten what it&amp;rsquo;s like to give and receive a hug; the faithful believer waiting on the Lord for the fulfillment of a promise, praising him in the heart-breaking years of waiting, or the one crying out for healing and enduring debilitating pain in the waiting and the praising; the grief in the death of a child. Why is life quite so very hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this may be a consequence of trying to live apart from the Lord, or simply failing to love one another, but some is not. What of that, then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul writes about this in Romans 8:18-27, in a passage sandwiched between two rather better known and loved celebrations of victory. If you possibly can, read it in The Message. Here&amp;rsquo;s an extract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The difficult times of pain throughout the world are simply birth pangs. But it’s not only around us; it’s within us. &amp;hellip; These sterile and barren bodies of ours are yearning for full deliverance. That is why waiting does not diminish us, any more than waiting diminishes a pregnant mother. We are enlarged in the waiting. &amp;hellip; the longer we wait, the larger we become, and the more joyful our expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s much in this world that is anaesthetic. Beware! It may dull the pain, but it will also dull the joyful expectancy. Perhaps only when we bear some pain ourselves can we be of any real use in the Kingdom. It need not be our own, but then it&amp;rsquo;s not too hard to find someone else&amp;rsquo;s, and wait with them in that. These are the places where God&amp;rsquo;s grace is most evident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait with joyful expectancy, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How can we love the Lord this much?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/nikola-jovanovic-OBok3F8buKY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How can we love the Lord this much?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we love the Lord this much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Revelation 4:8, where the four living creatures, day and night, never stop saying: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.”  And in Revelation 5:9, where together with the twenty-four elders, they sing to Jesus, “&amp;hellip; you were slain, and by your blood you ransomed people for God from every tribe and language and people and nation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When two people are in love, truly, madly, deeply, they think about each other a lot. Like, all the time! Detachment from reality may be observed. They think about each other&amp;rsquo;s attributes, the very best, and it fuels their love. David does this of the Lord in Psalm 145.  “Every day I will praise you” (v2) because “great is the LORD and most worthy of praise” (v3) “&amp;hellip; and I will meditate on your wonderful works” (v5). He goes on to remind himself and us of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s attributes (v8-9, 13-14, 17-20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read these verses. Meditate on them. Dwell in them. Express your love for the Lord through them. Put him at the centre, and lift him high. Adore him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must do this day and night, never ceasing, all the time!  “My mouth will speak in praise of the Lord &amp;hellip; for ever and ever” (v21).  Let us detach from the pseudo-reality that deceives us, and embrace the eternal reality. Let us feed and water our love for the Lord with endless praise, so it grows and grows, for his glory, and by his power and transforming grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him more, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How much can we love the Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/aldebaran-s-uXchDIKs4qI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How much can we love the Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much can we love the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently in church we were invited to speak out our praise to God. Woefully, every single prayer was me and us. What self-obsession! Is there any deliverance from this? Wonderfully there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s to be found in Revelation, chapters 4 and 5. Lose yourself in that for a while. Hear a hundred million angels and every creature singing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength and honour and glory and praise!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are any thinking about themselves, even for a moment? Not remotely! They are wholly captivated by the presence of the risen Lord Jesus, his glory and his power, and his irresistible love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us be so, and love the Lord with such a love that we forget ourselves. With a love for him that is magnified as he enlarges our hearts with his own overflowing love. Let us adore the one who is “worthy &amp;hellip; to receive glory and honour and power” (Rev 4:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The truth will set you free</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 06:42:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/the-truth-will-set-you-free/aaron-burden-TNlHf4m4gpI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The truth will set you free" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jesus said, “If you hold to my teaching &amp;hellip; then you will know the truth &amp;hellip;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:31-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth is more important now than ever, given the post-truth world in which we live, where people are inclined to define their own truth. Christians are not immune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are never more vulnerable than when we say, “the Lord told me &amp;hellip;”  What exactly do we mean by this? What interplay of conviction, imagination, emotion and coincidence are we leaning on? And what grounds do we have to trust any of that? We must take great care here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providentially, the Lord has told me a great deal, all of which is trustworthy and true. It was written down long ago, over 1200 pages. My best chance to grasp the truth is to read Scripture, diligently and comprehensively, with intellectual integrity and a surrendered heart, particularly when it becomes uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that Jesus said, “If you hold to my teaching &amp;hellip;”  It is not enough to read. We have to do it, to live and breathe his teaching, habitually and unceasingly. Only then can we really understand, and know the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“ &amp;hellip; and the truth will set you free.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be free, Amy 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Perfect love drives out fear</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/josue-michel-xCU7nCMNfI8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Perfect love drives out fear" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another observation on plain old fear, also from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter. The punchline is &amp;ldquo;perfect love drives out fear&amp;rdquo; (1 Jn 4:18), but to understand what he is saying you have to read the whole passage — the golden rule, always!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll string some of it together. &amp;ldquo;If we love one another, God lives in us and his love is made complete in us&amp;rdquo; (v12).  &amp;ldquo;Love is made complete &amp;hellip; because in this world we are like him&amp;rdquo; (v17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What drives out fear, then? We must be Christ to one another, one relationship at a time. One conversation at a time. If we love as Christ loved us, we live in right relationship with God and with one another. Perspective is restored, and fear is dissipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pray you may know the power of this in your own life, Amy. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Plain old fear</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/plain-old-fear/simon-berger-rydQVdwcgUQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Plain old fear" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s the fear of the Lord, and there&amp;rsquo;s plain old fear, and the two are mutually exclusive. Consider plain old fear. Fear that disempowers. Debilitates. Disembowels. Fear that blinds, and blindness that feeds fear, in a downward spiral. To see how to end it, understand how it begins. It begins with lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about me (1 Jn 4:9-10). God has no use for me (Jer 29:11). God won&amp;rsquo;t keep his promises (Josh 23:14). God can&amp;rsquo;t do it (Jer 32:27). It won&amp;rsquo;t end well (Rev 21:3-4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list is not exhaustive. But whatever the fear, when in its grip, expose the lie which birthed the fear. Here&amp;rsquo;s that joyous verse from Psalm 119 again: &amp;ldquo;I have chosen the way of truth &amp;hellip; I run in the path of your commands, for you have set my heart free&amp;rdquo; (v30, 32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May our Lord and Saviour continue to free your heart, Amy. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Covid prayer</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/covid-prayer/yannis-h-zpSXcUpmhNc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Covid prayer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear God, my God,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the Lord of all creation, majestic, sovereign, good, and wise beyond our understanding. Praise your holy name! I lift up to you the situation in Amy&amp;rsquo;s village, with Covid having arrived, and along with it, fear. Forgive us when we doubt your goodness or your sovereignty. I pray the people there would hear Jesus speaking, &amp;ldquo;Peace I leave with you; my peace I give you. I do not give to you as the world gives. Do not let your hearts be troubled and do not be afraid.&amp;rdquo; (John 14:27). Please keep Amy safe and well, and may she be a beacon of hope for those who may be losing theirs, pointing to Jesus and trusting him.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cc: Amy, with love&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiveness and purification</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 06:44:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/forgiveness-and-purification/nega-YdyhHbWZ1V0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiveness and purification" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a well loved verse from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter, that we may be in danger of reading too quickly and missing the most important word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some important words here. Confess. Sins. And some wonderful, lifting words. Faithful. Forgive. Purify. But what am I referring to? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. &lt;em&gt;Just&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem to be a little out of place, yet it is the crucial word. Consider why. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours, in full. If we confess our sins, and cry out to God for mercy, it is his &lt;em&gt;justice&lt;/em&gt; that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment. Rejoice, that he is faithful &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; just.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to grow in reverent awe and wonder</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/atharva-tulsi-2jA_YoQuvaA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to grow in reverent awe and wonder" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do we grow in reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done? Because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just happen. It takes serious get-up-early-and-cry-out-to-God hard work, every single day. Work. But not without incredible joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 helps. I won&amp;rsquo;t quote it here, because, well, it&amp;rsquo;s quite long. I have been including the first 32 verses in my daily readings for several years now.  (From time to time I read the whole psalm; it is worth it.)  I find these qualities in the psalmist. Earnest. Longing. Disciplined. Realistic. Falling short. Being held. Fully surrendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These verses conclude, &amp;ldquo;I run in the path of your commands, for you have set my heart free.&amp;rdquo;  I pray that you may increasingly run in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commands like this.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 06:43:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/fear-of-the-lord-is-the-beginning-of-wisdom/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know the will of the Lord? Let&amp;rsquo;s look again into the treasure trove which is Psalm 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, then, are those who fear the LORD? He will instruct them in the ways he chooses (v12).  The LORD confides in those who fear him; he makes his covenant known to them (v14).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Keller defines the fear of the Lord as this, in a sermon from Proverbs on the fear of the Lord being the beginning of wisdom. &amp;ldquo;The fear of the Lord is a reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My prayer for you is that you learn to live this more each day.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>He guides the humble in what is right</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 06:49:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/he-guides-the-humble-in-what-is-right/claudio-carrozzo-fCtvc5eFcqk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post He guides the humble in what is right" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of verses from Psalm 25 for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good and upright is the LORD; therefore he instructs sinners in his ways. He guides the humble in what is right and teaches them his way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the therefore. Meditate on it. Revel in it. See how the Lord desires for us to be holy and blameless, and yet he does not wait for that to be so, to instruct us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path of humility is more than these two verses. It is the whole psalm. And now, I have given you one of my most precious jewels. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Filled with the knowledge of his will</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:47:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/filled-with-the-knowledge-of-his-will/jonny-james-TE0leJlNX8Y-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Filled with the knowledge of his will" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask God to fill you with the knowledge of his will through all the wisdom and understanding that the Spirit gives, so that you may live a life worthy of the Lord and please him in every way: bearing fruit in every good work, growing in the knowledge of God, being strengthened with all power according to his glorious might so that you may have great endurance and patience as you begin your teaching ministry there, and so that you increasingly rely on the Lord, who provides all these things [adapted from Colossians 1:9-11].
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 06:54:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/blessed-is-the-one-who-trusts-in-the-lord/joe-johannes-qVcs4k1H_4k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blessed is the one who trusts in the Lord" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just wondering how you are coping with the heat over there, Amy. And that made me think of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But blessed is the one who trusts in the LORD, whose confidence is in him. They will be like a tree planted by the water that sends out its roots by the stream. It does not fear when heat comes; its leaves are always green. It has no worries in a year of drought and never fails to bear fruit.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 17:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s monsoon season there, so enjoy the irony. Praying for you 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Peace and provision</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:21:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.tesujimath.org/peace-and-provision/raimond-klavins-DDwOFA_9LiY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Peace and provision" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;May you know peace from the Lord, and his provision for you, Amy, as you wait on him, and especially when things don&amp;rsquo;t turn out as you expected or hoped. Know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s plans prevail, and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The LORD delights in those who fear him, who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
