<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>relationship on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/relationship/</link>
        <description>Recent content in relationship on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/relationship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Discouragement</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/discouragement/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/discouragement/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/discouragement/from-marwool-X-Z9gHq6iow-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Discouragement" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does discouragement come from and what can we do about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, discouragement can sneak in at any time and begin its insidious work of erosion of faith and joy. Perhaps all we notice is being a little flat, a little down. Why does this happen, and why does it sometimes happen so suddenly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many and varied reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the reasons are obvious: prolonged waiting, for healing, for deliverance, for the fulfillment of a promise; or fatigue, especially post-mission fatigue, when a work has been completed⸺perhaps when a young and enthusiastic team leaves after a significant and high energy visit and all the energy seems to leave with them. And sometimes the reasons are less obvious and there is simply an absence of waypoints upon which to pin hope, or merely a nagging sense that we have dropped off other people&amp;rsquo;s radar and there is no-one to notice whether we are flourishing or fading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, what to do? Paul knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I want you to know how great a struggle I have for you and for those at Laodicea and for all who have not seen me face to face, that their hearts may be encouraged, being knit together in love, to reach all the riches of full assurance of understanding and the knowledge of God&amp;rsquo;s mystery, which is Christ, in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, we all need encouragement from our brothers and sisters in Christ. The journey of faith is not a solitary one. Our hearts are encouraged as we are knit together in love, one with another, but more than this. What could be more encouraging than to be reminded of the treasures of wisdom and knowledge which are in Jesus and which are Jesus? To hear “cheer up” is of such limited comfort. But to hear “Jesus is interceding for you at the right hand of the Father, even now” lifts me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you look ahead to your last few months in the village, Amy, know that the work you have been doing and the work that you will complete before you leave is of eternal significance. Not only is Jesus himself interceding for you, but together with the Father he is so pleased to see you completing your faithful service, persevering even when it is hard and there is no-one to say well done. So pleased with you. And so I say it now: well done, Amy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one last insight for you, for sometimes when we need to hear such words of encouragement there is no-one speaking them to us. What then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider how Paul regarded the Thessalonians, who were so dear to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For what is our hope or joy or crown of boasting before our Lord Jesus at his coming? Is it not you? For you are our glory and joy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 2:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we long for a word of encouragement, and it does not come. So then we must speak it to another, affirm and encourage them in the Lord, and find in that, as Paul did, glory and joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With much love and encouragement to you, Amy, as you continue on in your faithful work for the Lord! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Reciprocity</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/reciprocity/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/reciprocity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/reciprocity/duy-pham-Cecb0_8Hx-o-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Reciprocity" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the principle of reciprocity in relationship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I long to see you, that I may impart to you some spiritual gift to strengthen you⸺that is, that we may be mutually encouraged by each other&amp;rsquo;s faith, both yours and mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 1:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote these words to the Christians in Rome before he ever met them. Marvel at the warmth in his longing to see them, his desire to bless, and that they might share &lt;em&gt;mutual encouragement&lt;/em&gt;, each to the other, even on meeting for the first time. Such is the love a Christian has for their brothers and sisters in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now those on the DCBC youth mission trip will be with you, and some of these you may be meeting for the first time: Abigail, Alexia, Blake, Emma, Hannah, Jack, Zac, Taylor, and Aria (although I notice that one of these you have known for her whole life!). We have been praying for safety and travelling mercies and the richest of blessings, lifting you and them both up before our loving Heavenly Father. Now be encouraged, each to the other, by each other&amp;rsquo;s faith and every spiritual blessing in Christ. And have some fun together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reciprocity is about giving and receiving simultaneously, imparting blessing and being blessed, symmetrically and joyously together. Every relationship is deepened by this: husband and wife, parent and child, teacher and student, boss and employee, and most especially brother and sister in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul knew this, and even as he desired to bring blessing and teaching to those new Christians in Rome, he was anticipating receiving blessing and encouragement in return. The huge difference in maturity and degree of experience simply did not matter. How joyous is genuine Christian fellowship!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever Christians come together, however, there is a potential barrier to such reciprocity in relationship, namely one taking the superior position, looking down on the other as somehow poorer or otherwise less than, to be solely the recipient rather than also the source of blessing. Let&amp;rsquo;s remind ourselves how Paul regarded Timothy to see how to avoid this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timothy was indeed young to be in Christian leadership, perhaps in his late 20s or early 30s, and there was a huge gulf between their levels of experience and capability. Paul was much older, was so much more highly educated, and ended up writing more than half of the New Testament, but see how highly he regarded Timothy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I have no one like him, who will be genuinely concerned for your welfare. For they all seek their own interests, not those of Jesus Christ. But you know Timothy&amp;rsquo;s proven worth, how as a son with a father he has served with me in the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:20-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And his charge to Timothy himself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let no one despise you for your youth, but set the believers an example in speech, in conduct, in love, in faith, in purity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 4:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish, I cannot help myself from giving you the mathematical definition of a reciprocal: of a quantity or function, related to another so that their product is unity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be one, Amy, with your younger brothers and sisters in Christ, and may you bring blessing and encouragement each to the other! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The grace-filled life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/tom-morbey-r1SwcagHVG0-unsplash-cropped.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The grace-filled life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are not under law but under grace, does it even matter what we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It matters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What shall we say then? Are we to continue in sin that grace may abound? By no means! How can we who died to sin still live in it? Do you not know that all of us who have been baptized into Christ Jesus were baptized into his death? We were buried therefore with him by baptism into death, in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, we too might walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we learn to walk in newness of life, not under law but under grace? If all those long lists of commandments still apply, how are we not under law? And if not, how can we avoid living in sin? Certainly not by overlooking what Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Do not think that I have come to abolish the Law or the Prophets; I have not come to abolish them but to fulfil them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like us, the fledgling church in Galatia was under threat from those preaching works. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider what Paul wrote to them. Here&amp;rsquo;s the key:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, but that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big if! How can we know, and how can we be secure in that knowledge? Because there&amp;rsquo;s a grievous trap here which snares many, namely equating being led by the Spirit with living according to the convictions of one&amp;rsquo;s own heart. This is fraught with danger! Satan is the father of lies and the great deceiver, and by stroking our egos and flattering our vanity he can manipulate our feelings even and perhaps especially in this realm. How can we escape this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the desires of the flesh are against the Spirit, and the desires of the Spirit are against the flesh, for these are opposed to each other, to keep you from doing the things you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the works of the flesh are evident: sexual immorality, impurity, sensuality, idolatry, sorcery, enmity, strife, jealousy, fits of anger, rivalries, dissensions, divisions, envy, drunkenness, orgies, and things like these. I warn you, as I warned you before, that those who do such things will not inherit the kingdom of God. But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:17, 19-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first list is truly shocking, and we might be tempted to think is far from where we live our lives, but consider idolatry for one⸺in regard to career, reputation, and respectability, how evident is this in every church! Now, notice that eight out of these fifteen works of the flesh comprise dysfunctional relationship and unlove. There&amp;rsquo;s a clue here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could being led by the Spirit in fact be quite straightforward? The opposite of dysfunctional relationship and unlove is simply, love. There&amp;rsquo;s more than love in the second list, of course, but that&amp;rsquo;s surely the headline. And what does Paul say elsewhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here indeed is the answer. We can live not under law but under grace by loving the Lord with all our heart, soul, mind and strength, and loving one another, unconditionally and without exception, in joyful surrender. Love that starts small must grow and grow and continue to grow⸺this is the fruit of the Spirit. So simple, and yet learning to do this adequately will take each one of us the rest of our earthly lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live a life of love, Amy, led by the Spirit, as one not under law but under grace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Forgiving others</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/forgiving-others/madhu-shesharam-KQZZCVyEWVk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Forgiving others" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we forgive those whose sin against us is breathtakingly heinous?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the how, let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge that we must. This is not optional, it is commanded by Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If your brother or sister sins, rebuke them; and if they repent, forgive them. Even if they sin against you seven times in a day and seven times come back to you saying &amp;lsquo;I repent&amp;rsquo;, you must forgive them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am facing a situation in which this is a real challenge. The response I received to my articulated desire for reconciliation and relationship and mutual forgiveness and healing was a crushing and callous brush-off. What now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first attempt to forgive was a false start. I tried to diminish the magnitude of the offence, to find a way to receive it as a simple misunderstanding, to excuse the other&amp;rsquo;s behaviour. This failed because there was no truth in it. The behaviour was in fact wretched and reprehensible. I cannot deny it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then had to grapple with “if they repent”. In my situation, there is no repentance. There is stubborn and Pharisaical judgment and rejection, and refusal to engage in authentic relationship. It is crushing. Heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some writers have tried to argue that the requirement to forgive is conditional on repentance, and in this passage it indeed appears so. Is that the whole story though? I think not. But let&amp;rsquo;s not resort to a human argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this from the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer, and what Jesus said next in the Sermon on the Mount:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you forgive others when they sin against you, your heavenly Father will also forgive you. But if you do not forgive others their sins, your Father will not forgive your sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:12, 14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here our forgiveness of others is linked to God&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness of us no less. How vital then is it to forgive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When they came to the place called the Skull, there they crucified him, along with the criminals⸺one on his right, the other on his left. Jesus said, “Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they are doing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 23:33-34a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was there repentance here? Of course not! How are we called to live? Like Christ! And how can we find the power to do this? Only in him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I must die to self, again. But as I do, I find I am being transformed into Christ&amp;rsquo;s likeness. There is no greater joy, even in the midst of all this pain. The joy in that transformation is empowering indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lengthy process, an ongoing journey, and I am not yet done. May the Lord have mercy on that individual as I forgive, and continue to forgive, dying to self and becoming like Christ. And if they come to the point of repentance, may we be restored in authentic relationship again, by Christ&amp;rsquo;s power and for his glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like Christ, Amy, in him and by his power and for his glory, fuelled by the joy in your own transformation! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Relational authenticity</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/jingming-pan-iYsrkq5qq0Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Relational authenticity" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most important thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is love &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve left this one until last, precisely because it is the most important. Why do I say that? So many reasons, starting with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus replied: “&amp;lsquo;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.&amp;rsquo;  This is the first and greatest commandment. And the second is like it: &amp;lsquo;Love your neighbour as yourself.&amp;rsquo;  All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 22:36-40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“A new command I give you: Love one another. As I have loved you, so you must love one another. By this everyone will know that you are my disciples, if you love one another.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not optional⸺there is absolutely no wriggle room here! And yet, why is it that we do not live like this? For tragically, we do not. We should be living and breathing this, all the time. Nothing matters more. But what exactly are we supposed to do as we go about our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phrase I came upon recently has really got its hooks into me: &lt;em&gt;relational authenticity&lt;/em&gt;. This is surely the starting point. Relational authenticity recognises that the one standing before me is a real person, whoever they may be. A real person with their hopes, dreams, disappointments and hurts, just like me. And the choice which is uniquely mine is whether and how to relate, to accept, to love. How do I regard them? As background noise? A diversion? A duty? Someone to look down upon? Someone to avoid? Or a whole person, with all their value and complexity and brokenness, loved by the Lord, as am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. Relational authenticity demands radical humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no difference &amp;hellip; for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified freely by his grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How this challenges ego!  But could we live like this? The prize is glorious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him the whole building is joined together and rises to become a holy temple in the Lord. And in him you too are being built together to become a dwelling in which God lives by his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we develop relational authenticity, this is what we will find: all of us, together, a holy temple in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us not overlook that this is the fruit of the Spirit. We grow in this as the Lord does his work of transforming grace in our lives. In my life. In yours. Softening our hearts, enabling us to love, and making us more like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursue relational authenticity, Amy, and learn to love like Jesus, the most important thing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Perfect love drives out fear</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/josue-michel-xCU7nCMNfI8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Perfect love drives out fear" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another observation on plain old fear, also from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter. The punchline is &amp;ldquo;perfect love drives out fear&amp;rdquo; (1 Jn 4:18), but to understand what he is saying you have to read the whole passage⸺the golden rule, always!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll string some of it together. &amp;ldquo;If we love one another, God lives in us and his love is made complete in us&amp;rdquo; (v12).  &amp;ldquo;Love is made complete &amp;hellip; because in this world we are like him&amp;rdquo; (v17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What drives out fear, then? We must be Christ to one another, one relationship at a time. One conversation at a time. If we love as Christ loved us, we live in right relationship with God and with one another. Perspective is restored, and fear is dissipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pray you may know the power of this in your own life, Amy. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
