<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>discipline on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/discipline/</link>
        <description>Recent content in discipline on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/discipline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>With your God</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/with-your-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/with-your-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/with-your-god/aron-visuals-LSFuPFE9vKE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post With your God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the fourth thing that Micah says the Lord requires from each one of us which is arguably the first in importance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has told you, O man, what is good; and what does the LORD require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/micah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Micah 6:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve already considered act justly, love mercy, and walk humbly. Do you see what&amp;rsquo;s left? &lt;em&gt;With your God.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your God⸺there&amp;rsquo;s not even a verb here! But in my view to assimilate “with your God” into “walk humbly” misses something vital and life-changing. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what is the most important thing. The. Most. Important. Thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And one of the scribes came up and heard them disputing with one another, and seeing that he answered them well, asked him, “Which commandment is the most important of all?” Jesus answered, “The most important is, ‘Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. And you shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength.’ The second is this: ‘You shall love your neighbour as yourself.’ There is no other commandment greater than these.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 12:28-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first and most important commandment is enough for us to understand “with your God”. &lt;em&gt;You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength.&lt;/em&gt; Nothing comes ahead of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does that look like? Jesus shows us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now even more the report about [Jesus] went abroad, and great crowds gathered to hear him and to be healed of their infirmities. But he would withdraw to desolate places and pray.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 5:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was so much work to be done. As people heard what Jesus was doing they flooded in. We know that Jesus ministered to them with grace and kindness, but he never neglected to spend time with his Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spending real quality time with someone is where love starts⸺making that a priority and ensuring that it happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As the Father has loved me, so have I loved you. Abide in my love. If you keep my commandments, you will abide in my love, just as I have kept my Father&amp;rsquo;s commandments and abide in his love. These things I have spoken to you, that my joy may be in you, and that your joy may be full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 15:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abide is rather an old fashioned term for stay and stay longer. We&amp;rsquo;ve considered before that the Apostle John wrote more about love than the other three gospel writers put together. Interestingly three-quarters of the occurrences of the word abide that appear in the Bible are written by John. That&amp;rsquo;s something to notice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must therefore make it an absolute priority to abide with our Heavenly Father and remain with him throughout the day, from when we wake until we sleep again. Every moment that we breathe we must spend in his presence, basking in his wonderful love and growing in our own love for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can we ensure to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deciding to get up earlier in the morning to spend unhurried and quality time with the Lord was for me the life-changing turning point when I left the shallows of faith and relatively meagre love for the Lord and started into deeper waters. For sure, other things were happening in my life to cause me to completely cast myself upon the Lord, but I think it was this which opened the way for him to begin his profound work of grace and healing. Abiding in his love throughout the day became possible because of the good start. And just as his mercies are new every morning, so every morning I had to begin again, with determination and great joy⸺exactly the joy that Jesus talked about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would we be coy about this? Is sleep more important than loving the Lord? For me it was an incremental journey, a progression in getting up earlier and then earlier again, and earlier still, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough until I had created a whole hour at the beginning of each day to immerse myself in the presence of my Heavenly Father, the one who loves me with an unfathomable love, who holds all mysteries and all power, the one that I live for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I can say now as I look back on that journey is that it was so profoundly worth it! Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abide with the one who loves you, Amy, each morning and throughout the day! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>In pursuit of wisdom</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/in-pursuit-of-wisdom/jonathan-chng-3R4vPrSB1c4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post In pursuit of wisdom" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this wisdom in the secret heart is so precious in the sight of the Lord then surely it is worth pursuing with zeal and determination. How exactly can we do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man [or woman] keep his [or her] way pure? By guarding it according to your word.&lt;br&gt;
With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments!&lt;br&gt;
I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed are you, O LORD; teach me your statutes!&lt;br&gt;
With my lips I declare all the rules of your mouth.&lt;br&gt;
In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches.&lt;br&gt;
I will meditate on your precepts and fix my eyes on your ways.&lt;br&gt;
I will delight in your statutes; I will not forget your word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 takes us into the depths, the depths of longing for the Lord, of desiring to be right with him, for an alignment of our secret heart with his will, and for his plans and purposes to be unfolded in our lives. Truly it challenges Ephesians Chapter One in my heart for which I would take to that desert island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see how to pursue wisdom in the secret heart. These are the headlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With my whole heart&lt;/em&gt; — no compromise! Ruthless consistency is required. Nothing can remain that is displeasing to the Lord, and in this we should expect to be tested. Will we take the Lord seriously or not? He is not deceived and nor should we be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have stored up your word in my heart &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — more than just knowing, this is loving⸺loving to spend time with the Lord in his word. His word in our hearts must be that which fuels our very lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; that I might not sin against you&lt;/em&gt; — our ongoing sanctification, our growing in holiness, is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessed are you, O Lord&lt;/em&gt; — we must meditate on the goodness of God, over and over, dwelling in it, reminding ourselves of his mercy. All his ways are steadfast love and faithfulness! To displace those idols which compete for our affection we must grow such a love for our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches&lt;/em&gt; — our Heavenly Father reveals himself to us through his written word. May we delight to read it, and to read it more, and to surrender our will to it, joyfully, ever growing in relationship with the one who loves us beyond imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will meditate on your precepts &amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; — with a surrendered heart, taking all the time required for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s holy word to permeate our hearts and lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip; and fix my eyes on your ways&lt;/em&gt; — every cyclist knows that you end up in the place where you fix your eyes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruthless consistency is required in pursuit of these things and we are not left alone in this. It is the heart-work of the Holy Spirit, his utmost desire for us, but we must not overlook how much discipline is required on our part, as Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that in a race all the runners run, but only one receives the prize? So run that you may obtain it. Every athlete exercises self-control in all things. They do it to receive a perishable wreath, but we an imperishable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 9:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lest we forget what is at stake,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all vigilance, Amy, pursue wisdom in the secret heart, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to grow in reverent awe and wonder</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-grow-in-reverent-awe-and-wonder/atharva-tulsi-2jA_YoQuvaA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to grow in reverent awe and wonder" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do we grow in reverent awe and wonder before the greatness of who God is and what he has done? Because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just happen. It takes serious get-up-early-and-cry-out-to-God hard work, every single day. Work. But not without incredible joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 helps. I won&amp;rsquo;t quote it here, because, well, it&amp;rsquo;s quite long. I have been including the first 32 verses in my daily readings for several years now.  (From time to time I read the whole psalm; it is worth it.)  I find these qualities in the psalmist. Earnest. Longing. Disciplined. Realistic. Falling short. Being held. Fully surrendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These verses conclude, I run in the path of your commands, for you have set my heart free (v32).  I pray that you may increasingly run in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commands like this.
🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
