<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>victory on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/victory/</link>
        <description>Recent content in victory on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 06:15:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/victory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Jesus is alive!</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/jesus-is-alive/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 06:15:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/jesus-is-alive/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/jesus-is-alive/todd-kent-PsLrgT55DeM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Jesus is alive!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference does it make that Jesus is alive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into that, let&amp;rsquo;s firstly celebrate the joyous truth of it: Jesus is alive! He is risen indeed! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what difference does it make?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us. Since, therefore, we have now been justified by his blood, much more shall we be saved by him from the wrath of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are justified in the sight of God by Jesus&amp;rsquo; blood, accomplished by his death on the cross. This is amazing grace, freely given by the one who loves us beyond imagining. Praise him! By this our sins are counted against us no more. The slate is wiped clean. And wiped clean again. And again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, this is only half a gospel. Paul underlines it for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And if Christ has not been raised, your faith is futile and you are still in your sins. Then those also who have fallen asleep in Christ have perished. If in Christ we have hope in this life only, we are of all people most to be pitied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 15:17-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to notice some who live by justification alone⸺grateful for forgiveness of sins, muddling along in life, asking for forgiveness over and over for those same besetting sins⸺poor beggars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the power of the resurrection there would be no victory. We would still be in our sins, all of us, over and over. And after that, only death⸺a people most to be pitied. Poor beggars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is not so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were buried therefore with him by baptism into death, in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, we too might walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if we have been united with him in a death like his, we shall certainly be united with him in a resurrection like his. We know that our old self was crucified with him in order that the body of sin might be brought to nothing, so that we would no longer be enslaved to sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:4-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Jesus is alive, we walk in newness of life right now, by his resurrection power, no longer slaves to sin but rejoicing as slaves to righteousness, rejoicing in victory over sin. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also at the end of our earthly lives, we shall certainly be united with him in a resurrection like his. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is alive, Amy!! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Personal holiness</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/personal-holiness/jeffery-erhunse-4XK2oKKvzVU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Personal holiness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you think of another aspect of worship which has nothing to do with singing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, I urge you, brothers and sisters, in view of God’s mercy, to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God⸺this is your spiritual act of worship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the act of worship which is personal holiness, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the most important word here: &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; links what follows to the entirety of the previous eleven chapters, which is Paul&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the wretched state of humankind without Christ, and of the magnitude and sufficiency of our rescue in Christ, God&amp;rsquo;s free and costly gift of grace to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now a righteousness from God, apart from law, has been made known, to which the Law and the Prophets testify. This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where, then, is boasting? It is excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:21-22, 27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My response then to this gift of grace and righteousness must be to live a life of personal holiness. As I live my life, each day facing temptation, and each day surrendering my will to the sanctifying work of the Spirit, I articulate each small victory as an act of worship to my Heavenly Father who loves me and has rescued me from such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; offer yourselves to God, as those who have been brought from death to life; and offer the parts of your body to him as instruments of righteousness. For sin shall not be your master, because you are not under law, but under grace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should note that God&amp;rsquo;s call to personal holiness is not to the righteous but to sinners, and we would do well to remember his call to Abraham out of the absolute mess and shame that he found himself in thirteen long years after his shabby act with Hagar. Hear the grace and love in this, right alongside the uncompromising call to holiness. Our Heavenly Father has so much love and such a high expectation for his sons and daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old, the LORD appeared to him and said, “I am God Almighty; walk before me and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only in Christ can we live like this, but in him, we can! Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer your body as a living sacrifice, Amy, holy and pleasing to God, and worship him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Two victories</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 09:11:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/two-victories/jordan-wozniak-xP_AGmeEa6s-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two victories" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, why am I writing to you on a Tuesday rather than a Wednesday? As you know, I like to ask the big questions, so let&amp;rsquo;s start with that! In fact, Megan and I are in Glenorchy, just about to embark on the Rees-Dart track, so we&amp;rsquo;ll be out of coverage for the next four days, and that&amp;rsquo;s the reason. With that out of the way, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the next big question. 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the first Easter victory, and how did that lead to the second?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two victories?  Yes, really!  The first victory was won on the cross, as Jesus died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said, “It is finished.” With that, he bowed his head and gave up his spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 19:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished here means completed, fulfilled, accomplished. A triumphant, “I have done it!” This is the first victory, won at inconceivable cost, to the Son and the Father both. It is victory over sin, in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did this lead to the second? Paul explains exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your attitude should be the same as that of Christ Jesus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, being in very nature God, did not consider equality with God something to be grasped, but made himself nothing, taking the very nature of a servant, being made in human likeness. And being found in appearance as a man, he humbled himself and became obedient to death⸺even death on a cross! Therefore God exalted him to the highest place and gave him the name that is above every name, that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:5-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The how is in the therefore. Jesus made himself obedient even to death on a cross, and &lt;em&gt;therefore&lt;/em&gt; God exalted him to the highest place and gave him the name that is above every name. This is the second victory, resurrection victory over death itself, in his life and ours both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how exalted is Jesus? &lt;em&gt;Every knee&lt;/em&gt; should bow, and &lt;em&gt;every tongue&lt;/em&gt; confess. Here&amp;rsquo;s John&amp;rsquo;s vision of the end of time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I heard every creature in heaven and on earth and under the earth and on the sea, and all that is in them, singing: “To him who sits on the throne and to the Lamb be praise and honour and glory and power, for ever and ever!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four living creatures said, “Amen”, and the elders fell down and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall down with them, Amy,  and worship the one who is worthy to receive praise and honour and glory and power, for ever and ever! 🙏🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
