<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dependence on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/dependence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dependence on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/dependence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An axe-head floats</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 06:24:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/an-axe-head-floats/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can a floating axe-head provide insight into the Father-heart of God?
 [Elisha and his servants and the company of the prophets] went to the Jordan and began to cut down trees [to build a place for them to live]. As one of them was cutting down a tree, the iron axe-head fell into the water. “Oh, my lord,” he cried out, “it was borrowed!”
The man of God asked, “Where did it fall?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect timing</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 06:26:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-timing/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What does perfect timing look like?
Some think it looks like that scene at Helm&amp;rsquo;s Deep, where Aragorn, Legolas and Gimli with some of the Rohirrim defend against an overwhelming army of orcs. They are expecting Gandalf to show up with the Riders of Rohan, but for so long he doesn&amp;rsquo;t come. After the longest time, when it looks like all may be lost, finally he arrives, riding Shadowfax and wielding his staff with great power against the evil hordes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taste and see that the Lord is good</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 06:33:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/taste-and-see-that-the-lord-is-good/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we obey a command if we don&amp;rsquo;t know what it means?
Obviously we can&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s a rhetorical question. What of this then?
 Taste and see that the LORD is good.
― Psalm 34:8 This is clearly an instruction to do something. It&amp;rsquo;s a command. Notice that David could have written, Behold! The Lord is good (because he is). That&amp;rsquo;s a true statement, but it&amp;rsquo;s not what he wrote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Receiving the kingdom of God like a little child</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What does it mean to receive the kingdom of God like a little child?
What a vital question! Jesus himself said:
 “Truly I tell you, anyone who will not receive the kingdom of God like a little child will never enter it.”
― Luke 18:17 We must fathom this then! Let&amp;rsquo;s consider three aspects of a little child&amp;rsquo;s relationship with their earthly parents, and infer how to receive from our Heavenly Father.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
