<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>love on Letters to Amy</title>
    <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/love/</link>
    <description>Recent content in love on Letters to Amy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Relational authenticity</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is the most important thing?
 The fruit of the Spirit is love &amp;hellip;
― Galatians 5:22 I&amp;rsquo;ve left this one until last, precisely because it is the most important. Why do I say that? So many reasons, starting with this.
 “Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?”
Jesus replied: “&amp;lsquo;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiant disciples</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?
 Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.
― Psalm 34:5 When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:
 His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescue</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/rescue/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How many times will the Lord rescue? Isn&amp;rsquo;t once enough?
 “Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”
― Psalm 91:14 To be honest, my Bible actually says this:
 “Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”
 But gender is of no consequence here. What matters is this: the pronoun is singular.
Some think the only rescue is the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saves us from our sin and brings us into relationship with our Heavenly Father, but that&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greetings</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/greetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/greetings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What&amp;rsquo;s in a greeting?
To Amy, who is loved by God and called to be one of the saints (Rom 1:7).
To Amy, sanctified in Christ Jesus and called to be holy (1 Cor 1:2).
To Amy, one of the faithful in Christ Jesus (Eph 1:1).
To Amy, one of the saints in Christ Jesus (Phil 1:1).
To Amy, a faithful sister in Christ (Col 1:2).
To Amy in God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ (1 Thes 1:1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the Lord want us to do?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 06:51:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
What does the Lord want us to do?
Surely there must be some special work that he&amp;rsquo;s calling us to. Something that we have to carefully and prayerfully uncover, so we can live the life he has planned, and do the work he has for us. Surely?
Jesus was once asked exactly this.
 “What must we do to do the works God requires?” Jesus answered, “The work of God is this: to believe in the one he has sent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we love the Lord this much?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How can we love the Lord this much?
There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Revelation 4:8, where the four living creatures, day and night, never stop saying: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.” And in Revelation 5:9, where together with the twenty-four elders, they sing to Jesus, “&amp;hellip; you were slain, and by your blood you ransomed people for God from every tribe and language and people and nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much can we love the Lord?</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
How much can we love the Lord?
Recently in church we were invited to speak out our praise to God. Woefully, every single prayer was me and us. What self-obsession! Is there any deliverance from this? Wonderfully there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s to be found in Revelation, chapters 4 and 5. Lose yourself in that for a while. Hear a hundred million angels and every creature singing:
 “Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength and honour and glory and praise!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect love drives out fear</title>
      <link>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</guid>
      <description>Dear Amy,
Here&amp;rsquo;s another observation on plain old fear, also from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter. The punchline is &amp;ldquo;perfect love drives out fear&amp;rdquo; (1 Jn 4:18), but to understand what he is saying you have to read the whole passage — the golden rule, always!
I&amp;rsquo;ll string some of it together. &amp;ldquo;If we love one another, God lives in us and his love is made complete in us&amp;rdquo; (v12). &amp;ldquo;Love is made complete &amp;hellip; because in this world we are like him&amp;rdquo; (v17).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
