<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>love on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/love/</link>
        <description>Recent content in love on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Fully known</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/miguel-bruna-ex1CRGFAftA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fully known" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else does God know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather a lot in fact⸺this is the omniscient Creator God of the universe we are talking about! But in particular, to understand what it means for each one of us to be known by God, let&amp;rsquo;s meditate on Psalm 139.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;O LORD, you have searched me and known me! You know when I sit down and when I rise up; you discern my thoughts from afar. You search out my path and my lying down and are acquainted with all my ways. Even before a word is on my tongue, behold, O LORD, you know it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you formed my inward parts; you knitted me together in my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb. I praise you, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My frame was not hidden from you, when I was being made in secret, intricately woven in the depths of the earth. Your eyes saw my unformed substance; in your book were written, every one of them, the days that were formed for me, when as yet there was none of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 139:1-4, 13-14a, 15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That I am known by my loving Heavenly Father quite so comprehensively and quite so intimately is truly wonderful. For one thing it completely dispels fear. All is fully known. The Lord is acquainted with all my ways. There is nothing hidden that could suddenly be revealed and remove his love for me, or for you. God already knows it all. He knows the very worst and he loves. He already knew and still he chose to love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one thing left to say. Consider the most well known passage on love in the Bible, the passage that is read at weddings and which makes our souls sing: 1 Corinthians 13. Have you noticed Paul&amp;rsquo;s penultimate point there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I have been fully known.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 13:12b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing and loving go together and they grow together. The extent to which we know another limits our love for them. Now I know the Lord only in part, which limits my love for him. Then I shall know fully and so will I love. But right here right now I am fully known by the Lord and fully loved by him. Fully loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, Amy: you are fully known by the Lord, and fully loved! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The grace-filled life</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-grace-filled-life/tom-morbey-r1SwcagHVG0-unsplash-cropped.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The grace-filled life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are not under law but under grace, does it even matter what we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It matters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What shall we say then? Are we to continue in sin that grace may abound? By no means! How can we who died to sin still live in it? Do you not know that all of us who have been baptized into Christ Jesus were baptized into his death? We were buried therefore with him by baptism into death, in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, we too might walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How then can we learn to walk in newness of life, not under law but under grace? If all those long lists of commandments still apply, how are we not under law? And if not, how can we avoid living in sin? Certainly not by overlooking what Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Do not think that I have come to abolish the Law or the Prophets; I have not come to abolish them but to fulfill them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like us, the fledgling church in Galatia was under threat from those preaching works. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider what Paul wrote to them. Here&amp;rsquo;s the key:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, but that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big if! How can we know, and how can we be secure in that knowledge? Because there&amp;rsquo;s a grievous trap here which snares many, namely equating being led by the Spirit with living according to the convictions of one&amp;rsquo;s own heart. This is fraught with danger! Satan is the father of lies and the great deceiver, and by stroking our egos and flattering our vanity he can manipulate our feelings even and perhaps especially in this realm. How can we escape this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the desires of the flesh are against the Spirit, and the desires of the Spirit are against the flesh, for these are opposed to each other, to keep you from doing the things you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the works of the flesh are evident: sexual immorality, impurity, sensuality, idolatry, sorcery, enmity, strife, jealousy, fits of anger, rivalries, dissensions, divisions, envy, drunkenness, orgies, and things like these. I warn you, as I warned you before, that those who do such things will not inherit the kingdom of God. But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:17, 19-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first list is truly shocking, and we might be tempted to think is far from where we live our lives, but consider idolatry for one⸺in regard to career, reputation, and respectability, how evident is this in every church! Now, notice that eight out of these fifteen works of the flesh comprise dysfunctional relationship and unlove. There&amp;rsquo;s a clue here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could being led by the Spirit in fact be quite straightforward? The opposite of dysfunctional relationship and unlove is simply, love. There&amp;rsquo;s more than love in the second list, of course, but that&amp;rsquo;s surely the headline. And what does Paul say elsewhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here indeed is the answer. We can live not under law but under grace by loving the Lord with all our heart, soul, mind and strength, and loving one another, unconditionally and without exception, in joyful surrender. Love that starts small must grow and grow and continue to grow⸺this is the fruit of the Spirit. So simple, and yet learning to do this adequately will take each one of us the rest of our earthly lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live a life of love, Amy, led by the Spirit, as one not under law but under grace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A melody made with the heart</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/a-melody-made-with-the-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/a-melody-made-with-the-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/a-melody-made-with-the-heart/nadin-mario-pO4ZI2krY_k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A melody made with the heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can our hearts make melody to the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; be filled with the Spirit, addressing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 5:18b-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greek word here translated &lt;em&gt;melody&lt;/em&gt; appears in only three other places in the New Testament. Here&amp;rsquo;s one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As it is written, “Therefore I will praise you among the Gentiles, and &lt;em&gt;sing&lt;/em&gt; to your name.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 15:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This relates to one of David&amp;rsquo;s psalms of deliverance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD lives, and blessed be my rock, and exalted be the God of my salvation⸺the God who &amp;hellip;  rescued me from my enemies &amp;hellip; .  For this I will praise you, O LORD, among the nations, and sing to your name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 18:46-49&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After more than 30 years of reading the NIV 1984, I have recently switched to the ESV, a more literal translation, and I am loving both the precision and the freshness. And so I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed something here. David will sing to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt;. What does that mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s name is his character, his reputation, the essence of who he is and what he is like. And what is that? Moses once asked exactly this, and behold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love for thousands, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.” And Moses quickly bowed his head toward the earth and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses&amp;rsquo; response is the only one possible⸺a heart-response of worship and adoration, a song to the Creator God of the universe, to the one who loves us, who is our rescuer, our rock and our redeemer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is an instrument of love, and this is the melody I can make to the name of the one who loves you and me both with boundless, unfathomable love, to all that he is and all that he has done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sing and make melody to the Lord with your heart, Amy, to the one who has rescued us and loves us beyond imagining! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The love of God</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/the-love-of-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 06:27:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/the-love-of-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/the-love-of-god/theo-eilertsen-photography-mwlhFUCir_8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The love of God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever come to realise something about the Lord which completely blew your mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We love because he first loved us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 4:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one aspect of the nature of God&amp;rsquo;s love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life group is working its way through Jim Packer&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;Knowing God&lt;/em&gt;. Last week we came upon just such a realisation. I can&amp;rsquo;t do better than to share the extract which had this effect on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If a father continues cheerful and carefree while his son is getting into trouble, or if a husband remains unmoved when his wife is in distress, we wonder at once how much love there can be in their relationship, for we know that those who truly love are only happy when those whom they love are truly happy also. So it is with God in his love for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Knowing God, Chapter 12, The Love of God&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already this is giving us an inkling that there could be something truly profound about the nature of God&amp;rsquo;s love that we may have overlooked. Packer continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Through setting his love on human beings God has voluntarily bound up his own final happiness with theirs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my! Could he really have done this? I am mind-blown already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has set his love upon particular sinners, and this means that, by his own free voluntary choice, he will not know perfect and unmixed happiness again till he has brought every one of them to heaven. He has in effect resolved that henceforth for all eternity his happiness shall be conditional upon ours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is almost beyond comprehension that the Lord would do this. How much pain, searing, lasting pain, has he taken upon himself in this decision? How much of his joy is now tied up in ours? What kind of love is this? What kind of God is this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus God saves, not only for his glory, but also for his gladness. This goes far to explain why it is that there is joy (God&amp;rsquo;s own joy) in the presence of the angels when a sinner repents (Luke 15:10), and why there will be exceeding joy when God sets us faultless at the last day in his own holy presence (Jude 24). The thought passes understanding and almost beggars belief, but there is no doubt that according to Scripture, such is the love of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;J. I. Packer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider what it means that the Lord has set his love on you, Amy, and may it blow your mind! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Relational authenticity</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/relational-authenticity/jingming-pan-iYsrkq5qq0Q-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Relational authenticity" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most important thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fruit of the Spirit is love &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve left this one until last, precisely because it is the most important. Why do I say that? So many reasons, starting with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus replied: “&amp;lsquo;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.&amp;rsquo;  This is the first and greatest commandment. And the second is like it: &amp;lsquo;Love your neighbour as yourself.&amp;rsquo;  All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 22:36-40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“A new command I give you: Love one another. As I have loved you, so you must love one another. By this everyone will know that you are my disciples, if you love one another.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not optional — there is absolutely no wriggle room here! And yet, why is it that we do not live like this? For tragically, we do not. We should be living and breathing this, all the time. Nothing matters more. But what exactly are we supposed to do as we go about our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phrase I came upon recently has really got its hooks into me: &lt;em&gt;relational authenticity&lt;/em&gt;. This is surely the starting point. Relational authenticity recognises that the one standing before me is a real person, whoever they may be. A real person with their hopes, dreams, disappointments and hurts, just like me. And the choice which is uniquely mine is whether and how to relate, to accept, to love. How do I regard them? As background noise? A diversion? A duty? Someone to look down upon? Someone to avoid? Or a whole person, with all their value and complexity and brokenness, loved by the Lord, as am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. Relational authenticity demands radical humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is no difference &amp;hellip; for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified freely by his grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How this challenges ego!  But could we live like this? The prize is glorious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him the whole building is joined together and rises to become a holy temple in the Lord. And in him you too are being built together to become a dwelling in which God lives by his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we develop relational authenticity, this is what we will find: all of us, together, a holy temple in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us not overlook that this is the fruit of the Spirit. We grow in this as the Lord does his work of transforming grace in our lives. In my life. In yours. Softening our hearts, enabling us to love, and making us more like Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursue relational authenticity, Amy, and learn to love like Jesus, the most important thing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Radiant disciples</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 06:29:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/radiant-disciples/autumn-goodman-vTL_qy03D1I-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Radiant disciples" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it about those who love the Lord with all of their heart, soul, mind and strength which is so profoundly attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When John had a vision on the island of Patmos of the risen Lord Jesus, he tried to describe the indescribable for us, concluding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;His face was like the sun shining in all its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t look at the sun, it&amp;rsquo;s far too bright. Any attempt even to look nearby overloads our retina, so all else fades into nothing. And so it is with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the source of the radiance. Ours is merely a reflection, unlikely to cause blindness, but bright and shining nonetheless, and enormously attractive to those who don&amp;rsquo;t have it. How does this work, then? We must consider how to be those who &lt;em&gt;look to him&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with forgiveness — &lt;em&gt;their faces are never covered with shame&lt;/em&gt;. All is forgiven, all debt is cancelled and all shame is gone. This is the glorious truth that underpins everything we are as children of God. Rejoice in that forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues with hope. As we look to the Lord, we look with the hope that notwithstanding all that we have already received, his work in us is not yet complete. There&amp;rsquo;s more to come, and what is to come is so certain and so very good, and so much more than we could possibly ask or imagine. This is our source of joy, our source of radiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we love the Lord, with a grateful heart that magnifies that love, and irrepressible hope that fuels it with tremendous power. When someone is in love, absolutely captivated, they have a glow about them, evidenced in shining eyes and wonder. This is powerful and joyous, and others desire it. May we know this as we look to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look to him, Amy, bask in his glory which shines like the sun in all its brilliance, and be radiant! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Rescue</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/rescue/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 06:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/rescue/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/rescue/axel-antas-bergkvist-zrSzqDnfkQ8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Rescue" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times will the Lord rescue? Isn&amp;rsquo;t once enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 91:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, my Bible actually says this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But gender is of no consequence here. What matters is this: the pronoun is singular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some think the only rescue is the body-and-blood-of-Christ one that saves us from our sin and brings us into relationship with our Heavenly Father, but that&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning. Notice this: “Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”.  This is someone who is &lt;em&gt;already in relationship&lt;/em&gt;. The rescue is ongoing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fourth of July this year should have been the last day of my life. I was in Rarotonga, in a kayak, in a place I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been on that monster-surf day, caught in a rip in the Avaavaroa Passage. The waves were pounding on the exposed reef, and after ten minutes, two capsizes, and exhaustion, I knew I was going to die. I cried out to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge wave rolled in, picked me up, and carried me on the boiling white-water all the way to the inside, a hundred metres or so, to the calm water in the lagoon, with the only thought in my head being, “Why am I not capsizing? This is impossible!” And it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been a silly boy, but there was no judgment from the Lord. All I received was this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because he loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue him”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is, regardless of whether the crisis is quite so acute as was mine, quite so physical. Perhaps the one is in community, well regarded, serving the Lord. But nevertheless captive. Oppressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because she loves me,” says the LORD, “I will rescue her”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, Amy, the rescue is ongoing! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Greetings</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/greetings/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/greetings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/greetings/church-of-the-king-j9jZSqfH5YI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Greetings" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in a greeting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, who is loved by God and called to be one of the saints (Rom 1:7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, sanctified in Christ Jesus and called to be holy (1 Cor 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, one of the faithful in Christ Jesus (Eph 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, one of the saints in Christ Jesus (Phil 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, a faithful sister in Christ (Col 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy in God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ (1 Thes 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy my true daughter in the faith (1 Tim 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, my dear daughter (2 Tim 1:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy our dear friend and fellow worker (Philemon 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, a stranger in the world, one of God’s elect scattered throughout the provinces of Papua New Guinea, chosen according to the foreknowledge of God the Father, through the sanctifying work of the Spirit, for obedience to Jesus Christ and sprinkling by his blood (1 Peter 1:1-2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, who through the righteousness of our God and Saviour Jesus Christ has received a faith as precious as ours (2 Peter 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Amy, who has been called, who is loved by God the Father and kept by Jesus Christ (Jude v1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a lot, it seems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive the truth and love in these greetings, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What does the Lord want us to do?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 06:51:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/what-does-the-lord-want-us-to-do/robert-nyman--ysyCHixMHU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What does the Lord want us to do?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the Lord want us to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely there must be some special work that he&amp;rsquo;s calling us to. Something that we have to carefully and prayerfully uncover, so we can live the life he has planned, and do the work he has for us. Surely?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was once asked exactly this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“What must we do to do the works God requires?”  Jesus answered, “The work of God is this: to believe in the one he has sent.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 6:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a little enigmatic, don&amp;rsquo;t you think? Or is it? Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s actually really straightforward! What would that look like? To believe in the one the Lord has sent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus, the very Son of God, came to rescue us. From sin, and shame, and failure, and all that drags us down. From the sin that separated us from the Father. He loves us so much, that he did this completely and comprehensively, and at what cost!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to really believe in him.  I am loved. I am rescued. I am free. No doubt. No fear. No shame. Only love. By our Father, and for our Father.  All that remains is to live in that love. In him, and through him, and for him, forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live like you&amp;rsquo;re loved, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How can we love the Lord this much?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-can-we-love-the-lord-this-much/nikola-jovanovic-OBok3F8buKY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How can we love the Lord this much?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we love the Lord this much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Revelation 4:8, where the four living creatures, day and night, never stop saying: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.”  And in Revelation 5:9, where together with the twenty-four elders, they sing to Jesus, “&amp;hellip; you were slain, and by your blood you ransomed people for God from every tribe and language and people and nation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When two people are in love, truly, madly, deeply, they think about each other a lot. Like, all the time! Detachment from reality may be observed. They think about each other&amp;rsquo;s attributes, the very best, and it fuels their love. David does this of the Lord in Psalm 145.  “Every day I will praise you” (v2) because “great is the LORD and most worthy of praise” (v3) “&amp;hellip; and I will meditate on your wonderful works” (v5). He goes on to remind himself and us of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s attributes (v8-9, 13-14, 17-20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read these verses. Meditate on them. Dwell in them. Express your love for the Lord through them. Put him at the centre, and lift him high. Adore him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must do this day and night, never ceasing, all the time!  “My mouth will speak in praise of the Lord &amp;hellip; for ever and ever” (v21).  Let us detach from the pseudo-reality that deceives us, and embrace the eternal reality. Let us feed and water our love for the Lord with endless praise, so it grows and grows, for his glory, and by his power and transforming grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him more, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How much can we love the Lord?</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/how-much-can-we-love-the-lord/aldebaran-s-uXchDIKs4qI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How much can we love the Lord?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much can we love the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently in church we were invited to speak out our praise to God. Woefully, every single prayer was me and us. What self-obsession! Is there any deliverance from this? Wonderfully there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s to be found in Revelation, chapters 4 and 5. Lose yourself in that for a while. Hear a hundred million angels and every creature singing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength and honour and glory and praise!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are any thinking about themselves, even for a moment? Not remotely! They are wholly captivated by the presence of the risen Lord Jesus, his glory and his power, and his irresistible love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us be so, and love the Lord with such a love that we forget ourselves. With a love for him that is magnified as he enlarges our hearts with his own overflowing love. Let us adore the one who is “worthy &amp;hellip; to receive glory and honour and power” (Rev 4:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love him, Amy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Perfect love drives out fear</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 06:48:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/perfect-love-drives-out-fear/josue-michel-xCU7nCMNfI8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Perfect love drives out fear" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another observation on plain old fear, also from John&amp;rsquo;s first letter. The punchline is &amp;ldquo;perfect love drives out fear&amp;rdquo; (1 Jn 4:18), but to understand what he is saying you have to read the whole passage — the golden rule, always!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll string some of it together. &amp;ldquo;If we love one another, God lives in us and his love is made complete in us&amp;rdquo; (v12).  &amp;ldquo;Love is made complete &amp;hellip; because in this world we are like him&amp;rdquo; (v17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What drives out fear, then? We must be Christ to one another, one relationship at a time. One conversation at a time. If we love as Christ loved us, we live in right relationship with God and with one another. Perspective is restored, and fear is dissipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pray you may know the power of this in your own life, Amy. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
