<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>omniscience on Letters to Amy</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/tags/omniscience/</link>
        <description>Recent content in omniscience on Letters to Amy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://letterstoamy.org/tags/omniscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Fully known</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 06:25:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/fully-known/miguel-bruna-ex1CRGFAftA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fully known" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else does God know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather a lot in fact⸺this is the omniscient Creator God of the universe we are talking about! But in particular, to understand what it means for each one of us to be known by God, let&amp;rsquo;s meditate on Psalm 139.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;O LORD, you have searched me and known me! You know when I sit down and when I rise up; you discern my thoughts from afar. You search out my path and my lying down and are acquainted with all my ways. Even before a word is on my tongue, behold, O LORD, you know it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you formed my inward parts; you knitted me together in my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb. I praise you, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My frame was not hidden from you, when I was being made in secret, intricately woven in the depths of the earth. Your eyes saw my unformed substance; in your book were written, every one of them, the days that were formed for me, when as yet there was none of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 139:1-4, 13-14a, 15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That I am known by my loving Heavenly Father quite so comprehensively and quite so intimately is truly wonderful. For one thing it completely dispels fear. All is fully known. The Lord is acquainted with all my ways. There is nothing hidden that could suddenly be revealed and remove his love for me, or for you. God already knows it all. He knows the very worst and he loves. He already knew and still he chose to love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one thing left to say. Consider the most well known passage on love in the Bible, the passage that is read at weddings and which makes our souls sing: 1 Corinthians 13. Have you noticed Paul&amp;rsquo;s penultimate point there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I have been fully known.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 13:12b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing and loving go together and they grow together. The extent to which we know another limits our love for them. Now I know the Lord only in part, which limits my love for him. Then I shall know fully and so will I love. But right here right now I am fully known by the Lord and fully loved by him. Fully loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, Amy: you are fully known by the Lord, and fully loved! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What to pray for</title>
        <link>https://letterstoamy.org/what-to-pray-for/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 06:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://letterstoamy.org/what-to-pray-for/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://letterstoamy.org/what-to-pray-for/marcel-smits-Wt6JoSxrsvU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What to pray for" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Amy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we know what we should pray for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s quite a responsibility here, don&amp;rsquo;t you think? After all, Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Whatever you ask in my name, this I will do, that the Father may be glorified in the Son. If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been in a prayer meeting where someone was sharing a prayer request, and they seemed to take aeons to lay out every painstaking detail about their situation? Well, we can&amp;rsquo;t risk praying for the wrong thing, can we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But could there be another way to see this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re surely familiar with the story of Joseph. After being sold into slavery by his brothers and thrown into prison in Egypt for a crime he didn&amp;rsquo;t commit, God raised him up to be second only to Pharaoh himself in all the land, and used him to deliver the Israelites from famine. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus Israel settled in the land of Egypt, in the land of Goshen. And they gained possessions in it, and were fruitful and multiplied greatly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 47:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some years later, however, things apparently weren&amp;rsquo;t going quite so well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During those many days the king of Egypt died, and the people of Israel groaned because of their slavery and cried out for help. Their cry for rescue from slavery came up to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 2:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this really what God had intended? Had it somehow all gone horribly wrong? Not really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God heard their groaning, and God remembered his covenant with Abraham, with Isaac, and with Jacob. God saw the people of Israel⸺and God knew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 2:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God knew. He didn&amp;rsquo;t need to be told. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t as if he hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed what was happening to his people, his chosen ones, his beloved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then what happened? What happened is that God met with Moses in the burning bush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, and I have come down to deliver them out of the hand of the Egyptians and to bring them up out of that land to a good and broad land, a land flowing with milk and honey.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God already knew what he was going to do and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t merely to alleviate the suffering of the Israelites. He was going to bless them far beyond that, far beyond imagining, gifting to them a land flowing with milk and honey⸺a land that would demonstrate his sovereign choice, his faithfulness to his covenant promise, his grace and kindness to his people, and ultimately his rescue for all of humankind. No-one was asking for this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 3:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply cry out to God, Amy, Lord have mercy! He already knows what to do. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
